<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0.599" dur="6.76">A friendly desert community where the sun  is hot, the moon is beautiful, and mysterious</text><text start="7.359" dur="4.68">lights pass overhead while we all pretend  to sleep.</text><text start="12.039" dur="2.48">Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="37.98" dur="6">Hello listeners. To start things off I&amp;#39;ve  been asked to read this brief notice:</text><text start="43.98" dur="5.199">the city council announces the opening of a new  dog park at the corner of Earl and Summerset</text><text start="49.179" dur="5.29">near the Ralph&amp;#39;s. They would like to remind  everyone that dogs are not allowed in the</text><text start="54.469" dur="8.85">dog park. People are not allowed in the dog  park. It is possible you will see hooded figures</text><text start="63.319" dur="10.56">in the dog park. Do not approach them. Do  not approach the dog park. The fence is electrified</text><text start="73.89" dur="6.74">and highly dangerous. Try not to look at the  dog park, and especially do not look for any</text><text start="80.63" dur="6.97">period of time at the hooded figures. The  dog park will not harm you.</text><text start="87.6" dur="4.839">And now the news.  Old Woman Josie out near the car lot says</text><text start="92.439" dur="6.631">the angels revealed themselves to her; said  they were ten feet tall, radiant, and one</text><text start="99.07" dur="6.02">of them was black; said they helped her with  various household chores. One of them changed</text><text start="105.09" dur="5.37">a light bulb for her, the porch light. She&amp;#39;s  offering to sell the old lightbulb, which</text><text start="110.46" dur="6.88">has been touched by an angel. It was the black  angel, if that sweetens the pot for anyone.</text><text start="117.34" dur="4.84">If you&amp;#39;re interested, contact Old Woman Josie.  She&amp;#39;s out near the car lot.</text><text start="123.969" dur="7.36">A new man came into town today. Who is he?  What does he want from us? Why his perfect</text><text start="131.33" dur="7.25">and beautiful haircut? Why his perfect and  beautiful coat? He says he is a scientist.</text><text start="138.58" dur="6.94">Well, we have all been scientists and one  point or another in our lives. But why now?</text><text start="145.53" dur="6.66">Why here? And just what does he plan to do  with all those breakers and humming electrical</text><text start="152.19" dur="5.7">instruments in that lab he is renting-- the  one next to Big Rico&amp;#39;s Pizza?</text><text start="157.89" dur="4.78">No one does a slice like Big Rico. No one.</text><text start="163.52" dur="2.94">Just a reminder to all the parents out there. </text><text start="166.46" dur="6.04">Let&amp;#39;s talk about safety when taking your children  out to play in the Scrub Lands and the Sand Wastes.</text><text start="173.2" dur="5.14">You need to give them plenty of water,  make sure there&amp;#39;s a shade tree in the area,</text><text start="178.35" dur="6.71">and keep an eye on the helicopter colors.  Are the unmarked helicopters circling the area black?</text><text start="185.06" dur="6.24">Probably World Government. Not  a good area for play that day. Are they blue?</text><text start="191.3" dur="7.06">That&amp;#39;s the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Police. They&amp;#39;ll  keep a good eye on your kids, and hardly ever take one.</text><text start="198.36" dur="5.32">Are they painted with complex murals  depicting birds of prey diving?</text><text start="203.68" dur="6.4">No one knows what those helicopters are, or what they want. Do not play in the area.</text><text start="210.08" dur="6.7">Return to your home, and lock the doors until a Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Policeman leaves a carnation on your porch</text><text start="216.79" dur="8.25">to indicate that the danger has passed. Cover  your ears to blot out the screams. Also, remember:</text><text start="225.08" dur="7.5">Gatorade is basically soda, so give your kid   plain old water, and maybe some orange slices when they play.</text><text start="239.26" dur="8.14">A commercial airliner flying through local airspace disappeared today, only to reappear in the Night Vale Elementary gymnasium during</text><text start="247.4" dur="7">basketball practice, disrupting practice quite  badly. The jet roared through the small gym</text><text start="254.4" dur="5.88">for only a fraction of a second, and before  it could strike any players or structure,</text><text start="260.28" dur="9.44">it vanished again, this time apparently for  good. There is no word yet on if or how this</text><text start="269.73" dur="5.62">will affect Night Vale Mountain Lion&amp;#39;s game  schedule, and also, if this could perhaps</text><text start="275.35" dur="7.22">be the work of their bitter rivals the Desert  Bluffs Cacti. Desert Bluffs is always trying</text><text start="282.57" dur="8.16">to show us up through fancier uniforms, better  pregame snacks, and possibly, by transporting</text><text start="290.73" dur="6.44">a commercial jet into our gymnasium, delaying  practice for several minutes at least.</text><text start="297.17" dur="3.9">For shame, Desert Bluffs. For shame.</text><text start="302.62" dur="7.06">That new scientist we now know is named Carlos called a town meeting.</text><text start="309.68" dur="5.12">He has a square jaw and teeth like a military cemetery. </text><text start="314.8" dur="9.02">His hair is perfect, and we all hate and despair and  love that perfect hair in equal measure.</text><text start="324.6" dur="5.46">Old Woman Josie brought corn muffins, which were  decent, but lacked salt.</text><text start="330.06" dur="7.08">She said the angels had taken her salt for a godly mission, and  she hadn&amp;#39;t yet gotten around to buying more.</text><text start="337.14" dur="8.1">Carlos told us that we are, by far, the most  scientifically interesting community in the US,</text><text start="345.24" dur="5.98">and he had come to study just what is  going around here. He grinned, and everything</text><text start="351.22" dur="6.4">about him was perfect, and I fell in love  instantly. </text><text start="362.54" dur="5.68">Government agents from a vague, yet menacing, agency were in the back watching.</text><text start="368.22" dur="4.96">I fear for Carlos. I fear for Night Vale.</text><text start="373.18" dur="7.58">I fear for anyone caught between what they  know and what they don&amp;#39;t yet know that they don&amp;#39;t know.</text><text start="392.34" dur="2.579">We received a press release this morning.</text><text start="394.919" dur="8.4">The Night Vale Business Association is proud  to announce the opening of the brand new Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront Recreation Area.</text><text start="403.32" dur="9.52">I have been to these facilities myself recently on their invitation, and I can tell you that  it is absolutely top of the line and beautiful.</text><text start="412.84" dur="7.92">Sturdy docking areas made from eco-friendly  post-consumer material, a boardwalk for pedestrians,</text><text start="420.76" dur="7.62">and plenty of stands ready for local food  vendors and merchants to turn into a bustling public marketplace.</text><text start="428.38" dur="6.48">Now, there is some concern  about the fact that, given we are in the middle</text><text start="434.86" dur="7.48">of a desert, there is no actual water at the  waterfront-- and that is a definite drawback,</text><text start="442.34" dur="7.08">I agree. For instance, the boardwalk is currently  overlooking sagebrush and rocks.</text><text start="449.42" dur="6.52">The Business Association did not provide an specific remedies  for this problem, but they assured me that</text><text start="455.949" dur="5.54">the new harbor would be a big boost to Night  Vale nonetheless.</text><text start="461.489" dur="7.011">Maybe wait until a flash flood and head down there for the full waterfront experience.</text><text start="470.26" dur="5.62">The local chapter of the NRA is selling bumper  stickers as part of their fundraising week.</text><text start="475.88" dur="5.46">They sent the station one to get some publicity,  and we&amp;#39;re here to serve the community so I&amp;#39;m</text><text start="481.34" dur="7.06">happy to let you all know about it. The stickers  are made from good, sturdy vinyl, and they read,</text><text start="488.4" dur="8.56">&amp;#39;Guns Don&amp;#39;t Kill People; It&amp;#39;s Impossible  To Be Killed By A Gun; We Are All Invincible To Bullets And It&amp;#39;s A Miracle.&amp;#39;</text><text start="496.96" dur="4.94">Stand outside of your front door and shout, &amp;quot;NRA,&amp;quot; to order one.</text><text start="509.88" dur="2.999">Carlos and his team of scientists warn that</text><text start="512.879" dur="5.64">one of the houses in the new development of  Desert Creek, out back of the old elementary school,</text><text start="518.52" dur="8.16">doesn&amp;#39;t actually exist. It seems like  it exists, explained Carlos and his perfect hair,</text><text start="526.68" dur="5.36">like it&amp;#39;s just right there when you  look at it. And it&amp;#39;s between two identical</text><text start="532.05" dur="5.779">houses, so it would make more sense for it  to be there then not. But, he says, they have</text><text start="537.829" dur="6.23">done experiments, and the house is definitely  not there. At news time, the scientists are</text><text start="544.059" dur="7.46">standing in a group in front of the nonexistent  house, daring each other to go knock on the door.</text><text start="551.52" dur="4.2">A great howling was heard from the Night Vale Post Office yesterday.</text><text start="555.72" dur="4.5">Postal workers claim  no knowledge, although passersby described</text><text start="560.23" dur="6.58">the sound as being a little like a human soul  being destroyed through black magic.</text><text start="566.81" dur="5.61">The Indian Tracker-- now, I don&amp;#39;t know if you&amp;#39;ve seen  this guy around; he&amp;#39;s the one who appears</text><text start="572.42" dur="6.209">to be of maybe Slavic origin, yet wears an  Indian headdress out of some racist cartoon</text><text start="578.629" dur="5.52">and claims to be able to be able to read tracks  on asphalt-- he appeared on the scene, and</text><text start="584.149" dur="5.19">swore that he would discover the truth. No  one responded because it&amp;#39;s really hard to</text><text start="589.339" dur="3.64">take him seriously in that headdress of his.</text><text start="597.18" dur="4.9">Lights, seen in the sky above the Arby&amp;#39;s.</text><text start="602.089" dur="11">Not the glowing sign of Arby&amp;#39;s; something  higher and beyond that. We know the difference.</text><text start="613.089" dur="10.32">We&amp;#39;ve caught onto their game. We understand  the lights-above-Arby&amp;#39;s game. Invaders from another world.</text><text start="625.7" dur="10.08">Ladies and gentlemen, the future  is here, and it&amp;#39;s about a hundred feet above the Arby&amp;#39;s.</text><text start="642.98" dur="3.279">Carlos and his scientists at the monitoring</text><text start="646.259" dur="7.92">station near Route 800 say their seismic monitors  have been indicating wild seismic shifts,</text><text start="654.18" dur="6.659">meaning to say that the ground should be going  up all over the place. I don&amp;#39;t know about</text><text start="660.839" dur="5.92">you folks, but the ground has been as still  as the crust of a tiny globe rocketing through</text><text start="666.759" dur="5.74">an endless void could be. Carlos says that  they&amp;#39;ve double-checked the monitors and they</text><text start="672.499" dur="7.56">are in perfect working order. To put it plainly,  there appears to be catastrophic earthquakes</text><text start="680.059" dur="4.9">happening right here in Night Vale that absolutely  no one can feel. </text><text start="686.06" dur="6.3">Well, submit an insurance claim anyway, see what you can get, right?</text><text start="693.74" dur="4.18">Traffic time, listeners. Now, police are issuing</text><text start="697.929" dur="6.72">warnings about ghost cars out on the highways,  those cars only visible in the distance, reaching</text><text start="704.649" dur="7.831">unimaginable speeds, leaving destinations  unknown for destinations more unknown.</text><text start="712.48" dur="4.92">They would like to remind you that you should not  set your speed by these aberrations, and doing</text><text start="717.42" dur="6.53">so will not be considered following the flow  of traffic. However, they do say that it&amp;#39;s</text><text start="723.989" dur="6.59">probably safe to match speed with the mysterious  lights in the sky, as whatever entities or</text><text start="730.579" dur="7">organization is responsible appear to be cautious  and reasonable drivers.</text><text start="737.86" dur="3.24">And now, the weather.</text><text start="741.1" dur="171.3">(These and More Than These, Joseph Fink)</text><text start="912.4" dur="2.1">Welcome back, listeners.</text><text start="916.44" dur="8.62">The sun didn&amp;#39;t set at the correct time today. Carlos and his team of scientists report.  They are quite certain about it. They checked</text><text start="925.06" dur="7.3">multiple clocks, and the sun definitely set  ten minutes later than it was supposed to.</text><text start="932.369" dur="6.12">I asked them if they had any explanations,  but they did not offer anything concrete.</text><text start="938.489" dur="6.45">Mostly they sat in a circle around a desk  clock, staring at it, murmuring and cooing.</text><text start="944.939" dur="7">Still, we must be grateful to have the sun  at all. It&amp;#39;s easy to forget in this hot, hot,</text><text start="951.94" dur="6.92">hot desert climate, but things would actually  be slightly harder for us without the sun.</text><text start="958.86" dur="5.479">The next time the sun rises, whatever time  that turns out to be, take a moment to feel</text><text start="964.339" dur="8.7">grateful for all the warmth, and light, and  even, yes, extreme heat that our desert community is gifted with.</text><text start="974.82" dur="8.76">The city council would like to remind you about the Tiered Heavens, and the Hierarchy  of Angels. The reminder is that you should</text><text start="983.619" dur="6.91">not know anything about this. The structure  of heaven and the angelic organizational chart</text><text start="990.529" dur="7">are privileged information known only to the  city council members on a need-to-know basis.</text><text start="997.56" dur="5.86">Please, do not speak to or acknowledge any  angels that you might come across while shopping</text><text start="1003.429" dur="7.47">at the Ralph&amp;#39;s or at the Desert Flower Bowling  Alley and Arcade Fun Complex. They only tell</text><text start="1010.899" dur="7.86">lies, and do not exist. Report all angel sightings  to the city council for treatment.</text><text start="1020.22" dur="4.56">And now for a brief public service announcement.</text><text start="1024.78" dur="8">Alligators. Can they kill your children? Yes.</text><text start="1032.78" dur="6.82">Along those lines, to get personal for a moment,  I think the best way to die would be swallowed</text><text start="1039.61" dur="9.76">by a giant snake. Going feet first and whole  into a slimy maw would give your life perfect symmetry.</text><text start="1055.2" dur="5.12">Speaking of the Desert Flower Bowling Alley and Arcade Fun Complex,</text><text start="1060.32" dur="4.32">its owner, Teddy Williams,  reports that he has found the entrance to</text><text start="1064.649" dur="7.68">a vast underground city in the pin retrieval  area of lane five. He said he has not yet</text><text start="1072.33" dur="7.439">ventured into it, merely peered down at its  strange spires and broad avenues. He also</text><text start="1079.769" dur="8.471">reports voices of a distant crowd in the depths  of that subterranean metropolis. Apparently,</text><text start="1088.24" dur="5.26">the entrance was discovered when a bowling  ball accidentally rolled into it, clattering</text><text start="1093.5" dur="7.94">down to the city below with sounds that echoed  for miles across the impossibly huge cavern--</text><text start="1101.44" dur="8.62">so, you know, whatever population that city  has, they know about us now, and we might</text><text start="1110.07" dur="3.14">be hearing from them very soon.  </text><text start="1116.3" dur="3.42">Carlos, perfect and beautiful, came into our</text><text start="1119.72" dur="6.439">studios during the break earlier, but declined  to stay for an interview. He had some sort</text><text start="1126.159" dur="6.23">of blinking box in his hand covered with wires  and tubes. Said he was testing the place for</text><text start="1132.389" dur="6.191">materials. I don&amp;#39;t know what materials he  meant, but that box sure whistled and beeped</text><text start="1138.58" dur="6.709">a lot. When he put it close to the microphone  it sounded like, well, like a bunch of baby</text><text start="1145.289" dur="7.78">birds had just woken up, really went crazy.  Carlos looked nervous. I&amp;#39;ve never seen that</text><text start="1153.07" dur="7.3">kind of look on someone with that strong of  a jaw. He left in a hurry. Told us to evacuate</text><text start="1160.37" dur="8.16">the building. But then, who would be hear  to talk sweetly to all of you out there?</text><text start="1168.53" dur="8.3">Settling in to be another clear night and pretty evening  here in Night Vale. I hope all of you out</text><text start="1176.83" dur="9.06">there have someone to sleep through it with,  or, at least, good memories of when you did.</text><text start="1186.94" dur="4.98">Good night, listeners. Good night.</text><text start="1198.1" dur="4.12">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books.</text><text start="1202.22" dur="6.18">It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey  Cranor, and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice</text><text start="1208.44" dur="5.94">of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin.  Original music by Disparition. All of it can</text><text start="1214.38" dur="7.539">be downloaded for free at disparition.info.  This episode&amp;#39;s weather was &amp;quot;These and More</text><text start="1221.919" dur="5.98">Than These,&amp;quot; also by Joseph.  Check out commonplacebooks.com for more information</text><text start="1227.899" dur="6.12">on this show, as well as our books on the  unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and</text><text start="1234.019" dur="6.25">what it means to be a grownup.  Today&amp;#39;s proverb: Look to the north. Keep looking.</text><text start="1240.269" dur="2.2">There&amp;#39;s nothing coming from the south.</text></transcript>