<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="8.809">Today&amp;#39;s air quality is mauve and speckled.
Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="32.44" dur="8.6">Representatives from the greater medical insurance community announced
this week that major insurance providers would</text><text start="41.04" dur="9.06">no longer cover government-disseminated illnesses.
These ailments were created to control undesirable</text><text start="50.1" dur="11.1">populations and include: AIDS, most cancers,
irritable bowel syndrome, telekinesis, tingling,</text><text start="61.2" dur="7.479">and any kind of food allergy. Doctors advise
that the best way to avoid acquiring any of</text><text start="68.679" dur="7.64">these conditions is to limit questionable
public activities. Try not to be in a lower</text><text start="76.319" dur="8.96">economic class, and give regularly to an approved
religious organization. Take these precautions</text><text start="85.289" dur="5.76">and you should live a healthy, or at least
medically-insured, life.</text><text start="94.04" dur="10">In other health news, the Night Vale Council for Commerce reminds
you to regularly consume wheat and wheat by-products.</text><text start="104.04" dur="6.36">By doing so, you are directly supporting the
local Night Vale farmer, as well as the local</text><text start="110.409" dur="7.16">Night Vale commodities conglomerates. Looking
for a snack? Try wheat, or a wheat by-product.</text><text start="118.26" dur="7.38">Dinner? Wheat and/or its by-product. Trying
to patch a leaky roof? We have just the thing</text><text start="125.649" dur="9.411">for you, and we also have its by-products.
Wheat and wheat by-products. By Americans,</text><text start="135.06" dur="5.08">for Americans, in Americans, watching Americans.</text><text start="151.3" dur="5.02">New information on the Apache Tracker, who you might remember as that</text><text start="156.32" dur="3.999">white guy who wears
the cartoonishly inaccurate and offensive</text><text start="160.319" dur="6.881">Indian headdress, and who disappeared some
weeks ago after investigating the strange</text><text start="167.2" dur="8.94">occurrences at the Night Vale Post Office.
Well, word is in that he has reappeared, except</text><text start="176.15" dur="7.5">it now seems he is actually Native American.
Witnesses say his features are still recognizable,</text><text start="183.65" dur="6.74">but during the disappearance he has transformed
into that which he always absurdly claimed</text><text start="190.39" dur="8.26">to be. More explanation, of course, is needed--
but the Apache Tracker is also now only able</text><text start="198.65" dur="5.369">to speak Russian, and I did not bother to
get his statement translated.</text><text start="204.019" dur="6.82">Apparently, he has been taking to leaning on the hood
of an old Honda Accord in the parking lot</text><text start="210.84" dur="7.96">of the Desert Flower Bowling Alley and Arcade
Fun Complex, shaking his head slowly and checking</text><text start="218.81" dur="8.989">his watch. Does his complete racial transformation
make his previous actions less offensive,</text><text start="227.799" dur="6.1">listeners? Write us a letter telling us what
you think, and then put it away in a drawer</text><text start="233.9" dur="6.919">for ten years. Reading it again, you&amp;#39;ll get
a little pang of nostalgia for the person</text><text start="240.819" dur="3.64">you used to be, once upon a time.</text><text start="247.44" dur="4.16">The City
Council today issued a strong warning against</text><text start="251.6" dur="7.919">the manufacture and sale of discount bloodstones.
They say that these bloodstones of inferior</text><text start="259.519" dur="7.12">design and construction have the potential
to cause major accidents in even common day-to-day</text><text start="266.639" dur="8.44">chanting rituals. These accidents have included,
in just the past few months: locust swarms,</text><text start="275.08" dur="7.16">pus tornadoes, and the creation and subsequent
obliteration of a mirror version of Night</text><text start="282.25" dur="8.08">Vale, forcing all of us to watch our identical
counterparts perish-- and thus confront the</text><text start="290.33" dur="8.16">inevitability of our own futures. Anyone caught
selling these bloodstones will be put into</text><text start="298.49" dur="8.16">the Dark Box, pending erasure from recorded
history. The lesser charge of buying or possessing</text><text start="306.65" dur="7.5">them will be met with mere summary execution.
Critics charge that the City Council is lying</text><text start="314.15" dur="5.9">about all of this, due to the fact that the
Council owns the only certified bloodstone</text><text start="320.05" dur="9.06">factory in town. But, the Council has vehemently
denied this charge by gibbering, howling,</text><text start="329.11" dur="2.5">and knocking over microphones.</text><text start="341.98" dur="4.9">Oh, dear. I
apologize, listeners.</text><text start="346.88" dur="6.58">We at Night Vale Community Radio are experiencing the following technical
problems:</text><text start="354.12" dur="10.88">the need for air, eye movement, and gooey stuff inside. Please, stand by.</text><text start="369.7" dur="3.86">Thank you. These problems have been corrected.</text><text start="374.8" dur="7.06">An update on our previous message about wheat
and wheat by-products. You should not eat</text><text start="381.86" dur="8.46">wheat or wheat by-products, say several frantic
scientists, waving clipboards in our studio.</text><text start="390.32" dur="6.62">As it turns out all wheat and wheat by-products,
for unknown reasons, have turned into venomous</text><text start="396.94" dur="7.48">snakes, which are crawling all over our small
city, causing even more chaos than is normal.</text><text start="404.42" dur="5.98">These snakes have been described as terrifying,
loathsome, and &amp;quot;probably from the bowels of</text><text start="410.4" dur="8.92">hell itself!&amp;quot;-- also, green and three feet
long. If you have any wheat or wheat by-products</text><text start="419.32" dur="8">in your home, you are almost certainly already
dead. Sorry about that.</text><text start="428.96" dur="9.88">Property taxes are going up again, Night Vale. Several citizens
are justifiably upset over this latest increase,</text><text start="438.84" dur="7.84">but municipal services do, after all, cost
money. Schools, public transportation, parks</text><text start="446.68" dur="7.86">and recreation facilities, and of course,
the multi-billion dollar pulsar development facility. </text><text start="454.54" dur="5.6">Speaking of which, scientists say
that they are on the verge of developing the</text><text start="460.15" dur="9.019">first ever human-made neutron star. Usually
the aftermath of a supernova, this pulsar</text><text start="469.169" dur="6.571">would be roughly four miles in diameter, but
with a nearly incomprehensible density that</text><text start="475.74" dur="7.1">makes it about half the mass of our own sun.
And to think, this rapidly rotating sphere</text><text start="482.84" dur="5.78">of radioactive matter will be right here under
the sands of Night Vale, producing enough</text><text start="488.62" dur="6.9">energy to power the earth for billions of
years. The City of Night Vale plans to use</text><text start="495.52" dur="7.22">the pulsar to light the high school football
stadium, which still uses whale oil lamps.</text><text start="502.74" dur="8.2">John Peters-- you know, the farmer-- is particularly
upset... not only about the pulsar development,</text><text start="510.94" dur="7.58">but also about the higher taxes. As owner
of more than 150 acres, John will certainly</text><text start="518.52" dur="6.98">have to pay a large share. And given that
John is a peach farmer in a desert, he hasn&amp;#39;t</text><text start="525.51" dur="7.41">actually raised a successful crop ever. His
only income is his half a million dollar annual</text><text start="532.92" dur="6.68">subsidy for imaginary corn, which has been
one of Night Vale&amp;#39;s greatest exports. People</text><text start="539.6" dur="9.76">come from all over-- even Desert Bluffs, unfortunately--
to buy his imaginary corn. I like to butter</text><text start="549.37" dur="6.19">up a piece of bread and then rub the imaginary
corn along it, and then sprinkle it with a</text><text start="555.56" dur="7.8">little bit of salt and cayenne. Boy, is that
a delicious and low-carcinogen summer treat!</text><text start="564.7" dur="6.66">But even our town heroes like John Peters--
you know, the farmer-- have to pay their fair</text><text start="571.37" dur="10.23">share. No citizen is above paying taxes. Well,
except Marcus Vanston, but that&amp;#39;s understandable</text><text start="581.6" dur="6.75">because he&amp;#39;s so wealthy. When you&amp;#39;re worth
as much as Marcus Vanston, you have proved</text><text start="588.35" dur="5.92">your value to society through hard work and
determination, and are no longer required</text><text start="594.27" dur="6.7">to show anyone any further proof that you
care about anything or anybody else, because</text><text start="600.97" dur="8.38">you obviously do. Look at all your money!
According to some, Marcus is worth over five</text><text start="609.35" dur="8.52">billion dollars, and that&amp;#39;s five billion reasons
Marcus is our town&amp;#39;s greatest citizen.</text><text start="618.9" dur="7.44">Further updates on wheat and wheat by-products: The
good news is that they are no longer poisonous</text><text start="626.35" dur="7.22">serpents. The bad news is that they have transformed
into a particularly evil and destructive form</text><text start="633.57" dur="7.87">of spirit. Please, be aware that wheat and
wheat by-products are now malevolent and violent</text><text start="641.44" dur="6.76">supernatural forces, capable of physically
moving objects up to 200 pounds and entering</text><text start="648.21" dur="7.18">human souls of up to Soul Strength Four. The
frantic scientists, who are now hopping up</text><text start="655.39" dur="6.5">and down just outside my recording booth,
indicating various charts and figures, recommend</text><text start="661.89" dur="6.59">creating a simple lean-to out of animal bones
and mud, such as you might have made and played</text><text start="668.48" dur="8.16">in as a child, and hiding there until the
spiritual forces of wheat and wheat by-products have passed. </text><text start="680.24" dur="6.28">A reminder to all Night Vale
citizens that the annual Sorrow Songs Sing-Along</text><text start="686.53" dur="6.04">is this Thursday. There will be a potluck
lunch, and the softball team will be selling</text><text start="692.57" dur="6.55">refreshments to fund things that each of them
individually want to buy for themselves. Anyone</text><text start="699.12" dur="6.05">who has their own Sorrow Song they&amp;#39;d like
to add to our communal vocal malaise should</text><text start="705.17" dur="9.39">submit it to City Hall by Tuesday, at the
latest. Remember that low moans and minor-key</text><text start="714.56" dur="7.48">chants do not count. The composer of the best
Sorrow Song, as indicated by our audience</text><text start="722.04" dur="10.86">participatory Weep-O-Meter, will be ritualistically
drowned in a pool of our own townspeople&amp;#39;s tears. Good luck!</text><text start="736.54" dur="6.46">Listeners, the City Council,
for national security reasons, have replaced</text><text start="743" dur="6.93">the following report with the sound of a burbling
brook, followed by the sound of a running blender.</text><text start="752.02" dur="10.92">Friends, listeners, there&amp;#39;s a...
[Sound of a burbling brook]</text><text start="762.94" dur="11.22">[Sound of a running blender]</text><text start="774.16" dur="8.1">...what it does. City Comptroller
Waynetta Barnett received a $1.5 billion check</text><text start="782.26" dur="5.98">from the Federal Government this week. The
check was to support rebuilding efforts from</text><text start="788.24" dur="6.96">this past week&amp;#39;s massive earthquake, reaching
9.7 on the Richter scale, the epicenter of</text><text start="795.2" dur="7.1">which was directly below Night Vale. Of course,
we experienced absolutely no damage to the</text><text start="802.3" dur="7">town, and nobody reported feeling any effects
at all from this enormous seismological event.</text><text start="810.2" dur="6.02">Comptroller Barnett says that she suspects
that FEMA just saw the meter reading, declared</text><text start="816.23" dur="5.6">this a disaster area, and sent a check. She
doesn&amp;#39;t think they have any interest in visiting</text><text start="821.83" dur="6.92">Night Vale, so we can probably just spend
the money however we want. Barnett added that</text><text start="828.75" dur="6.18">those new Mini Cooper sedans are really cute,
and wanted us all to look at their website.</text><text start="835.92" dur="10.04">We asked Carlos about our inability to experience
tectonic shifts. Carlos, lovely Carlos, had</text><text start="845.96" dur="7.2">previously recorded other massive tremor activity
underneath our city. His response was a few</text><text start="853.17" dur="9.9">seconds of stammering followed by a sigh and
slow head shake. His eyes were distant-- distracted,</text><text start="863.07" dur="6.57">yet beautiful. I asked him where he got his
shirt. It fit him so well. He said he would</text><text start="869.64" dur="4.46">look at his notes and computer models and
see if he could figure out what was going</text><text start="874.11" dur="4.14">on. I don&amp;#39;t know if he listens to me sometimes.</text><text start="879.68" dur="7.2">Ladies and gentlemen, I take you from an unreal disaster to an un-unreal one.</text><text start="887.8" dur="3.76">It is my sad
duty now to announce that the City Council</text><text start="891.56" dur="7.18">is officially putting Night Vale under an
emergency state, due to the ongoing and life-threatening</text><text start="898.74" dur="6.87">wheat and wheat by-products situation. The
Council states that anyone who has come into</text><text start="905.61" dur="6.96">contact with wheat and wheat by-products,
and has by some happy miracle survived, should</text><text start="912.57" dur="7.42">consider themselves infected and proceed to
the usual quarantine area, just behind the</text><text start="919.99" dur="7.59">playground in Mission Grove Park-- there to
spend the rest of their days in quiet contemplation</text><text start="927.58" dur="7.3">and weaving. Everyone else should head immediately
to the Wheat and Wheat By-Products Shelter</text><text start="934.88" dur="8.02">that has been sitting unused for decades under
the public library. When asked why a Wheat</text><text start="942.91" dur="8.3">and Wheat By-Products Shelter already existed,
the City Council answered, simply, &amp;quot;Prophecy.&amp;quot;</text><text start="952.1" dur="7.62">May you all be safe. May you all be well.
May you be strong and flexible with ruddy</text><text start="959.72" dur="7">cheeks and legs like tree trunks. And now,
the weather.</text><text start="967.14" dur="110.74"> [&amp;quot;Cigarette Burns Forever&amp;quot; by Adam Green]</text><text start="1077.88" dur="7.44">News from Old Woman Josie, out
near the Car Lot. She reports that the Angels</text><text start="1085.32" dur="7.1">have gathered in a circle in her living room,
blocking her view of the television. They</text><text start="1092.42" dur="7.72">are shoulder-to-shoulder, facing each other,
radiant with holy light. &amp;quot;The Bowling Alley,&amp;quot;</text><text start="1100.14" dur="7.019">they are chanting. &amp;quot;The Bowling Alley.&amp;quot; She
says that a repeat of The West Wing she had</text><text start="1107.159" dur="6.6">really hoped to watch is on, and she is quite
annoyed by her usually considerate angelic</text><text start="1113.759" dur="7">house guests. More on this story, maybe...
if there ever is more.</text><text start="1123" dur="9.659">And finally, some good news. All wheat and wheat by-products have
mysteriously vanished from Night Vale, and</text><text start="1132.659" dur="8.5">the City Council promises that they will be
gone forever. This scourge, this siege upon</text><text start="1141.16" dur="9.3">us, this salvo of food-based warfare is finally
over. Nevermore will be we threatened in our</text><text start="1150.47" dur="9.319">homes by this enemy or its by-products. We
also will never eat bread again, and that&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1159.789" dur="7.87">a pretty big bummer. But this is the balance
that must be made between what we desire and</text><text start="1167.659" dur="9.62">what we fear, between pain and pleasure, between
wheat, dear listeners, and its by-products.</text><text start="1178.46" dur="6.48">Many of you are huddled now and forever in
the quarantine behind the playground in Mission</text><text start="1184.95" dur="7.55">Grove Park. For this community-minded sacrifice,
we thank you. I know you were forced there</text><text start="1192.5" dur="7.74">by martial law, but still, you should be commended
for your brave action. Terminal quarantine</text><text start="1200.24" dur="8.36">might seem scary now, but I understand they
have a well-stocked supply of canned lentils</text><text start="1208.6" dur="7.919">and the Silver Screen Edition of Trivial Pursuit.
And of course, you have the radio. I hope</text><text start="1216.519" dur="7.2">you will let my dulcet voice and our humble
community station into your ears and hearts</text><text start="1223.73" dur="10.1">until your final wheat-loving breath. Dear
listeners, stay tuned next for a live broadcast</text><text start="1233.83" dur="9.68">of a man, locked in a recording booth, silently
staring at the microphone with intense suspicion.</text><text start="1243.94" dur="9.98">And as always, since always, and for always,
goodnight, Night Vale. Goodnight. </text><text start="1260.08" dur="4.92">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace
Books. It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey</text><text start="1265.009" dur="5.64">Cranor, and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice
of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1270.649" dur="6.1">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1276.749" dur="6.961">weather was &amp;quot;Cigarette Burns Forever&amp;quot; by Adam
Green. Find out more at adamgreen.info. Want</text><text start="1283.71" dur="3.839">to have your music featured in the weather
section? Want to contribute your talents to</text><text start="1287.549" dur="5.141">the show? Just want to say hi? Email us at
nightvale@commonplacebooks.com, or follow</text><text start="1292.69" dur="5.489">us on Twitter at @NightValeRadio. Check out
commonplacebooks.com for more information</text><text start="1298.179" dur="5.72">on this show, as well as our books on the
unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1303.9" dur="4.88">Today&amp;#39;s proverb:
Today is the last day of your life up to this point.</text></transcript>