<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="5.209">Hi. If you have found yourself enjoying Welcome
to Night Vale, or if your captors are winning</text><text start="5.209" dur="5.14">you over by playing it day and night in your
homemade cell, or if you&amp;#39;ve grown used to</text><text start="10.349" dur="4.66">hearing it faintly in the background as you
dream of walking on a strange and sandy beach</text><text start="15.009" dur="4.681">next to a vast and alien ocean, then we would
appreciate it if you would write a review</text><text start="19.69" dur="4.25">of it on iTunes. It would help us out a lot.
For your own safety, please do not mention</text><text start="23.94" dur="4.84">Hooded Figures, hawks, or the color blue in
any of your reviews. Thank you.</text><text start="29.2" dur="9.84">The policeman in that intersection is not directing traffic.
He&amp;#39;s coding an urgent message to all of us.</text><text start="39.06" dur="3.28">Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="66.48" dur="5.24">First, the news. Old
Town Night Vale residents are complaining</text><text start="71.729" dur="6.45">about extremely noisy sunsets. Several agitated
citizens are pushing for the City Council</text><text start="78.179" dur="6.26">to do something about the solar shrieking
every evening for the past few weeks. One</text><text start="84.439" dur="6.97">homeowner described the sound as &amp;quot;the parched
cries of sad buzzards, or perhaps even the</text><text start="91.409" dur="8">unholy voice of Old Scratch himself.&amp;quot; The
City Council, speaking in unison at a televised</text><text start="99.409" dur="5.31">press conference, said that the noise is just
the windmill farms that litter the unfortunate</text><text start="104.719" dur="7">wastelands of Desert Bluffs, and that the
noises do not fall under Night Vale jurisdiction.</text><text start="111.72" dur="5.999">Walton Kincaid, president of the community
group, Soundproof Old Town, said that the</text><text start="117.719" dur="5.28">windmills can&amp;#39;t possibly be the source of
the noise, as they are non-existent and also</text><text start="122.999" dur="7.26">don&amp;#39;t work, because of Desert Bluffs&amp;#39; staggering
incompetence. The City Council called a second</text><text start="130.259" dur="7.34">press conference, wherein they all wordlessly
stared down Kincaid for fourteen uninterrupted</text><text start="137.599" dur="7.8">minutes. Their dark eyes tore holes straight
through the community spokesman (metaphorically</text><text start="145.409" dur="6.601">speaking), until his soul was compacted into
what looked like a partially chewed black-eyed</text><text start="152.01" dur="7.52">pea (literally). To date, only Old Town residents
have reported hearing these inconceivable</text><text start="159.53" dur="6.599">noises every evening as the sun crosses the
indifferent horizon. And the noises seem to</text><text start="166.129" dur="5.651">be taking their toll; there have been two
heart attacks, twelve cases of significant</text><text start="171.78" dur="7.9">muscular atrophy, and at least two dozen claims
of folks growing third eyes, including Kincaid</text><text start="179.68" dur="6.41">himself, who had an arachnid-like eight eyes
when he spoke before City Council yesterday</text><text start="186.09" dur="7.34">morning. No other neighborhood can hear the
sounds. I spoke to Simone Rigadeau in the</text><text start="193.43" dur="5.46">Earth Sciences building at Night Vale Community
College about this scientifically fascinating</text><text start="198.89" dur="8.659">story, and she called it a simple case of
celestial just desserts. Full disclosure,</text><text start="207.549" dur="5.881">listeners: Rigadeau does not work in Earth
Sciences. She is a transient living in the</text><text start="213.43" dur="7.179">recycling closet of the Earth Sciences building,
and she collects cans as pets. There is another</text><text start="220.609" dur="7.92">hearing scheduled at 4am tomorrow, on the
highest ledge overlooking Skeleton Gorge,</text><text start="228.529" dur="6.391">which can only be accessed by government helicopters.
All previous endeavors to scale the cliff-side</text><text start="234.92" dur="8.219">by rock-climbing enthusiasts have failed in
extravagantly gory fashion. The Council issued</text><text start="243.139" dur="7">a statement wishing Kincaid luck in attending
this mandatory meeting.</text><text start="253.38" dur="7.78">Breaking news: we&amp;#39;ve received confirmation from the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret
Police that fugitive Hiram McDaniels was finally</text><text start="261.17" dur="6.33">apprehended. McDaniels has been on the lam
since August. He was wanted on several counts</text><text start="267.5" dur="6.75">of insurance fraud, falsifying identification
papers, evading arrest, and assaulting a police</text><text start="274.25" dur="6.81">vehicle with fire. McDaniels was spotted near
his Earl Road apartment early Saturday morning</text><text start="281.06" dur="5.53">by several alert neighbors. The neighbors
said they were able to identify McDaniels</text><text start="286.59" dur="7.5">because he matched police sketches of an 18
foot tall five-headed dragon that had been</text><text start="294.09" dur="7.13">posted across Night Vale. Fingerprints later
confirmed that McDaniels was definitely a</text><text start="301.22" dur="6.82">dragon. Secret Police are still unsure of
McDaniels&amp;#39; motives for returning home. And,</text><text start="308.04" dur="7">well, listeners, our station intern Stacy
just handed me a photo of Hiram McDaniels.</text><text start="315.04" dur="8.14">He&amp;#39;s a very dynamic-looking dragon. The raw
power. The intensity in those five faces,</text><text start="323.19" dur="7.99">those many sets of piercing blue and red and
black and green and yellow eyes. I can certainly</text><text start="331.18" dur="6.12">see how he charmed his way out of an arrest.
He must never get tickets. What a guy!</text><text start="338.22" dur="7.72">An unsigned press release I found under my pillow
this morning announces the following:</text><text start="347.02" dur="7.1">&amp;quot;There is a free party this Friday at the Abandoned
Missile Silo outside of town. The purpose</text><text start="354.13" dur="7.89">of this party is to celebrate! There will
be no sign, or music, but the party is inside</text><text start="362.02" dur="9.1">the silo. This party takes place at 3am and
will be over at 3:05. It will be dark, both</text><text start="371.13" dur="7.62">inside and outside the silo. Grope blindly
towards happiness. Keep your mouth open and</text><text start="378.75" dur="6.8">your teeth together to indicate you are at
a party. You will hear noises, and later,</text><text start="385.55" dur="8.58">you will not. This party will feature special
guest Bon Jovi, although he does not yet know it. See you there!&amp;quot; </text><text start="397.58" dur="5.12">An interesting note on
Hiram McDaniels: intern Stacy tells me that</text><text start="402.71" dur="7.19">she&amp;#39;s been Googling the roguish dragon. Did
you know that he has a blog? He&amp;#39;s a very smart</text><text start="409.9" dur="6.72">fellow, some really groundbreaking ideas.
Here&amp;#39;s one post from last week: &amp;quot;If I were</text><text start="416.62" dur="5.75">mayor of Night Vale, I would give incentives
for small business development, and focus</text><text start="422.37" dur="7.61">on youth physical fitness programs. Human
youth are the human future, after all.&amp;quot; Well,</text><text start="429.98" dur="8.96">it seems a certain multi-headed fugitive wants
 to become mayor of Night Vale. You have my vote, Hiram!</text><text start="441.74" dur="5.16">Thursday night, the City Council
is voting on a new measure that would prohibit</text><text start="446.9" dur="6.59">breathing as an involuntary muscular action.
Historically, the human body has been able</text><text start="453.49" dur="6.34">to control breathing without the brain needing
to consciously activate the diaphragm. Under</text><text start="459.83" dur="5.11">the new rule, all residents of Night Vale
would be required to make the physical choice</text><text start="464.94" dur="6.65">of whether or not, and when, to breathe. The
City Council said that we have too long taken</text><text start="471.59" dur="6.44">the receipt of oxygen for granted, and that
the sense of entitlement must cease. If the</text><text start="478.03" dur="5.78">vote passes, residents will have until March
1st of next year to learn to control these</text><text start="483.81" dur="7.27">involuntary muscle groups during lucid sleep.
Detractors say that it is our constitutional</text><text start="491.08" dur="7.08">right to breathe how we want, and that it
is not the government&amp;#39;s job to legislate breathing.</text><text start="498.16" dur="5.98">The Council responded by waving a brick in
the air at reporters and shouting &amp;quot;We learned</text><text start="504.14" dur="7.06">to beat our own hearts! We taught ourselves
to wet our own corneas! We have pulled ourselves</text><text start="511.2" dur="8.6">up from nothing! It is the American dream.&amp;quot;
Then, they took a deep breath all together,</text><text start="519.8" dur="5.1">lowered the brick, broke it into pieces, and
devoured it.</text><text start="526.12" dur="3.38">And now a word from our sponsor.</text><text start="529.5" dur="7.64">We all want to live forever, right? Wrong.
Think about watching your family die as you</text><text start="537.14" dur="8.43">selfishly carry on, your children aging and
passing, your grandchildren, and so on. Think</text><text start="545.58" dur="7.14">of all the friends you&amp;#39;ll make, but eventually
lose. You don&amp;#39;t want that! No! You know the</text><text start="552.72" dur="4.66">earth is eventually going to be swallowed
by the sun, right? And one day, you would</text><text start="557.39" dur="6.98">be present for this greatest of all apocalypses.
As fascinating as this would be, scientifically</text><text start="564.37" dur="7.11">speaking, this excitement would fade as the
pain of thousand-degree flames engulfed your</text><text start="571.48" dur="8.32">tender body, and your aged mind would be so
alone in this interminable torture. Does this</text><text start="579.8" dur="9.9">sound like something you want? We didn&amp;#39;t think
so. Immortality is stupid. Think before you wish.</text><text start="589.7" dur="2.84">This message brought to you by Direct
TV.</text><text start="595.62" dur="9.02">Dear listeners, right after we reported on Hiram McDaniels&amp;#39; interest in becoming Night
Vale mayor, the dirty campaign tactics came</text><text start="604.64" dur="8.16">into play stirring up bad feelings, and slinging
the old municipal mud. Incumbent Mayor Pamela</text><text start="612.81" dur="5.69">Winchell issued a statement citing township
bylaws that prohibit prisoners from running</text><text start="618.5" dur="7.68">for public office. Now, isn&amp;#39;t it just like
a career politician, such as Mayor Winchell,</text><text start="626.18" dur="6.26">to make such unethical, ad hominem attacks
on a great reptilian beast, simply because</text><text start="632.45" dur="6.78">he is in jail? It sounds to me like the mayor
is feeling McDaniels breathing down her neck!</text><text start="639.23" dur="4.46">Breathing dragon fire, that is. Give ‘em
hell, Hiram!</text><text start="644.88" dur="9.24">The following is a test of the Emergency Dream Broadcast System. In the event
of an actual emergency, you would just now</text><text start="654.12" dur="5.29">be experiencing a dream in which you were
in the neighborhood where you grew up, only</text><text start="659.41" dur="8.26">all the houses are now black, featureless
cylinders. Just row after row of these blank</text><text start="667.67" dur="6.7">dark cylinders, stretching out around you.
You are home... but you are also somewhere</text><text start="674.37" dur="5.78">from whence you will never find home again.
There is someone waiting for you at the end</text><text start="680.15" dur="7.66">of the longest street. You know that, although
you do not know who. You try to run down the</text><text start="687.81" dur="7.61">street and it grows longer and longer. You
pass by one cylinder in particular and know</text><text start="695.42" dur="6.44">that it&amp;#39;s your house. You stop running. You
approach the blank face of the cylinder, its</text><text start="702.62" dur="7">surface seeming to devour light and sound.
You reach out and you are inches from touching</text><text start="709.62" dur="6.34">it. Just then you hear a ding. You look up
to see words in the sky.</text><text start="715.96" dur="5.14">POSSIBLE FLASH FLOODS, they say. ALERT VALID UNTIL 3PM.</text><text start="722.52" dur="5.54">Once again,
this has been a test of the Emergency Dream Broadcast System. </text><text start="730.74" dur="5.38">The Night Vale Mall is having
to deal with angry calls from parents, after</text><text start="736.12" dur="6.969">the Santa they hired for Christmas photos
was once again a no-show. Mall public relations</text><text start="743.089" dur="7.311">officials said that the missing Santa is actually
a performance art piece, meant to show people</text><text start="750.4" dur="7.54">how our capitalist idols are truly nonexistent,
ghosts of materialistic ideas that we have</text><text start="757.94" dur="7.82">embraced as replacements for true spiritual
meaning. A long line of upset parents and</text><text start="765.77" dur="7.22">crying children stretched from Santa&amp;#39;s empty
chair to just past the Hollister. The mall</text><text start="772.99" dur="6.44">PR officials added that they have a really
cool idea for Valentine&amp;#39;s Day. They&amp;#39;re thinking,</text><text start="779.43" dur="8.78">like, moving pictures of actual beating hearts
projected onto a large teddy bear? Which has</text><text start="788.21" dur="7.39">been stretched open like a vivisected frog
from seventh grade life science? Officials</text><text start="795.6" dur="7.48">added, &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s going to be monstrous and beautiful.
You don&amp;#39;t even know what art really is. You</text><text start="803.089" dur="7.54">don&amp;#39;t even know yourself.&amp;quot; They concluded
by chanting and pumping their arms in unison,</text><text start="810.63" dur="8.93">like a lower, Paleolithic version of the YMCA dance. And now... the weather. </text><text start="819.56" dur="247.36">[&amp;quot;The Brightness&amp;quot; by Anais Mitchell]</text><text start="1066.92" dur="7.38">During the break, I  received a message from Mayor Winchell&amp;#39;s office
responding to our previous reports. According</text><text start="1074.309" dur="6.49">to the mayor, mayoral elections aren&amp;#39;t for
another three years, and Hiram McDaniels is</text><text start="1080.799" dur="5.84">ineligible to run not only because of his
jail stay, but also because he is neither</text><text start="1086.639" dur="7.94">a Night Vale resident, nor a human being.
There is, she says, no precedent for a five-headed</text><text start="1094.58" dur="6.8">dragon as elected official. Mayor Winchell
also pointed out that writing the throwaway</text><text start="1101.389" dur="8.551">phrase &amp;quot;If I were mayor of Night Vale&amp;quot; on
a blog is not an official declaration of candidacy.</text><text start="1109.94" dur="8.14">&amp;quot;There is paperwork!&amp;quot; Mayor Winchell shouted
into my voicemail. &amp;quot;You can&amp;#39;t just... argh!&amp;quot;</text><text start="1118.08" dur="6.479">she continued, trailing off slightly at the
end. What followed was about ninety-five seconds</text><text start="1124.559" dur="6.7">of loud stomping, and what sounded like wood
chopping in the distance, before the message</text><text start="1131.259" dur="9.92">finally ended. Allow me a retort, dear listeners,
with this brief editorial: With all due respect,</text><text start="1141.179" dur="7.6">Madame Mayor, have we not had enough dragon-bashing?
Our great country once held to some terrible</text><text start="1148.789" dur="8.26">old customs, but we grew up. We learned. We
abolished slavery. Women won the right to</text><text start="1157.049" dur="5.84">vote. Ghosts can now marry (but of course,
not have children I mean, that would be a</text><text start="1162.889" dur="6.41">real slippery slope). And our own little burg
is on the verge of becoming the first city</text><text start="1169.299" dur="7.42">in this great nation to legalize time travel.
So let&amp;#39;s loosen our collars! Let&amp;#39;s march into</text><text start="1176.72" dur="8">the reptilian future, not cling to the narrow
past. Just because a dragon is a dragon, and</text><text start="1184.72" dur="7.86">has five heads, doesn&amp;#39;t mean he can&amp;#39;t lead
our community. Sure, critics will say, &amp;quot;Oh!</text><text start="1192.58" dur="5.51">But Cecil! What if his five heads don&amp;#39;t agree
on something? What if one&amp;#39;s like,&amp;#39;Yeah, let&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1198.09" dur="4.73">build this school!&amp;#39; But another&amp;#39;s like, &amp;#39;No
more schools!&amp;#39; And the others are drunk or</text><text start="1202.82" dur="7.84">sleepy or something? How can we agree to elect
five heads that can&amp;#39;t agree with themselves?&amp;quot;</text><text start="1210.66" dur="7.88">To this, I say shame on you for your negative
stereotypes of multi-headed beings. Free your</text><text start="1218.549" dur="8.551">mind! The rest, as our official town song
says, will follow. The song also says, &amp;quot;Lap</text><text start="1227.1" dur="5.72">deeply of the scarlet mud, after the blood
rains of the apocalypse,&amp;quot; but I don&amp;#39;t think</text><text start="1232.82" dur="7.959">that quite applies here. So with this, I am
proud to offer my endorsement of Hiram McDaniels</text><text start="1240.779" dur="6.9">for Mayor of Night Vale. Sure, the election
isn&amp;#39;t for three years, but it&amp;#39;s never too</text><text start="1247.69" dur="7.429">early to affect change. And in that time,
we will rally. We will petition to get what</text><text start="1255.119" dur="7.94">we want. And soon, a great leader will rise.
Lead us to that future, Hiram!</text><text start="1265.54" dur="11.12">Ah, but that is later. Now, it is dark. It is quiet. Just
you and me, dear listener.</text><text start="1276.66" dur="7.999">Just my voice, traveling from this microphone, traveling
silent and immediate across sleepy homes and</text><text start="1284.659" dur="7.92">lost souls to your ears. You curl under a
blanket, protecting your body from the world</text><text start="1292.59" dur="8.079">excepting a few clever spiders and you are
listening, hearing me. Sleep heavily and know</text><text start="1300.669" dur="7.051">that I am here with you now. The past is gone,
and cannot harm you anymore. And while the</text><text start="1307.72" dur="8.08">future is fast coming for you, it always flinches
first, and settles in as the gentle present.</text><text start="1315.809" dur="11.33">This now, this us, we can cope with that.
We can do this together, you and I. Drowsily,</text><text start="1327.139" dur="7.98">but comfortably. Stay tuned now for our two-hour
special, Car Alarms and Their Variations,</text><text start="1335.119" dur="7.24">brought to you commercial-free by Canada Dry.
Goodnight, Night Vale. Goodnight.</text><text start="1356.56" dur="5.719">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace
Books. It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey</text><text start="1362.279" dur="6.28">Cranor, and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice
of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1368.559" dur="6.32">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1374.879" dur="6.11">weather was &amp;quot;The Brightness&amp;quot; by Anais Mitchell.
Find out more at anaismitchell.com. Want to</text><text start="1380.989" dur="3.831">have your music featured in the weather section?
Want to contribute your talents to the show?</text><text start="1384.82" dur="7.36">Just want to say hi? Email us at nightvale@commonplacebooks.com,
or follow us on Twitter at @NightValeRadio.</text><text start="1392.19" dur="5.089">Check out commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1397.279" dur="4.2">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1401.479" dur="3.02">Today&amp;#39;s proverb: Does the carpet match the drapes?</text><text start="1404.5" dur="4.3">No, it doesn&amp;#39;t.
You&amp;#39;re the worst interior decorator. Please leave my home.</text></transcript>