<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="6.859">&amp;quot;This is a story about you,&amp;quot; said the man
on the radio. And you were pleased, because</text><text start="6.859" dur="7.34">you always wanted to hear about yourself on
the radio. Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="35.06" dur="7.36">This is a story about you. You live in a trailer,
out near the Car Lot, next to Old Woman Josie&amp;#39;s</text><text start="42.429" dur="6.11">house. Occasionally, she&amp;#39;ll wave at you on
her way out to get the mail or more snacks</text><text start="48.539" dur="6.241">for the Angels. Occasionally, you&amp;#39;ll wave
back. You&amp;#39;re not a terrible neighbor, as far</text><text start="54.78" dur="6.219">as it goes. At night, you can see the red
light blinking on and off on top of the radio</text><text start="60.999" dur="8.52">tower. A tiny flurry of human activity against
the impeccable backdrop of stars and void.</text><text start="69.52" dur="4.72">You&amp;#39;ll sit out on the steps of your trailer,
with your back to the brightness of the Car</text><text start="74.25" dur="8.79">Lot, watching the radio tower for hours. But
only sometimes. Mostly, you do other things.</text><text start="83.04" dur="7.68">This story is about you. You didn&amp;#39;t always
live in Night Vale. You lived somewhere else,</text><text start="90.72" dur="6.18">where there were more trees, more water. You
wrote direct mail campaigns for companies,</text><text start="96.9" dur="6.81">selling their products. &amp;quot;Dear resident,&amp;quot; you
wrote often. &amp;quot;Finally, some good news in this</text><text start="103.71" dur="6.27">dreary world! At last, a reason not to kill
yourself!&amp;quot; Then you would delete that and</text><text start="109.98" dur="6.64">write something else, and it would be sent
out, and it would not be read by anyone. You</text><text start="116.62" dur="6.96">had a friend, and then a girlfriend, and then
a fiancee-- the same person. She cooked dinner</text><text start="123.58" dur="4.82">sometimes, but sometimes you cooked. You often touched.</text><text start="139.16" dur="6.08">One day you were walking from the glass box of your office to your old Ford
Probe,</text><text start="145.24" dur="5.62">and a vision came to you. You saw above you a planet, </text><text start="150.86" dur="9.279">of awesome size, lit by no sun.
An invisible titan, all thick black forests</text><text start="160.139" dur="12.58">and jagged mountains and deep turbulent oceans.
It was so far away. So desolate. And so impossibly,</text><text start="172.73" dur="9.629">terrifyingly dark. And that day, you did not
go home. You drove instead. You drove a long</text><text start="182.359" dur="9.2">time, and eventually you ended up in Night
Vale, and you stopped driving. You have been</text><text start="191.569" dur="8.01">haunted ever since by how easy it was to walk
away from your life, and how few the repercussions</text><text start="199.579" dur="6.961">were. You never heard from your fiancee or
your job again. They never looked for you,</text><text start="206.54" dur="7.82">which doesn&amp;#39;t seem likely, or maybe it&amp;#39;s that
in Night Vale, you cannot be found. The complete</text><text start="214.37" dur="4.94">freedom. The lack of consequence. It terrifies you. </text><text start="225.76" dur="3.64">You 
have a new job now. Every day except Sunday</text><text start="229.4" dur="7.3">you drive out into the Sand Wastes, and there
you find two trucks. You move wooden crates</text><text start="236.709" dur="6.64">from one truck to another while a man in a
suit silently watches. It is a different man</text><text start="243.349" dur="8.831">each time. Sometimes the crates tick. Mostly,
they do not. When you are done, the man in</text><text start="252.18" dur="7.239">the suit hands you an amount of cash, also
different each time, and you go home. It is</text><text start="259.419" dur="10.12">the best job you&amp;#39;ve ever had. Except, today...
it was different. You moved the crates. The</text><text start="269.55" dur="7.579">man in the suit, a stranger, watched. But
then, as had never happened before, the man</text><text start="277.129" dur="7.311">in the suit received a phone call. He walked
off at some distance to take it. &amp;quot;Yes, sir!&amp;quot;</text><text start="284.44" dur="9.74">he said, and &amp;quot;No, sir!&amp;quot; Also he made hawk
shrieking sounds. It wasn&amp;#39;t terribly interesting.</text><text start="294.18" dur="7.4">You moved crates. But then, an impulse...
an awful impulse came over you, and for no</text><text start="301.58" dur="5.799">other reason than that you are trapped by
the freedom to do anything in this life, you</text><text start="307.379" dur="6.91">took one of the crates, and put it in your
trunk. By the time the man came back from</text><text start="314.289" dur="5.5">his phone call, you were done with your job.
He gave you the money (it was nearly five</text><text start="319.789" dur="8.1">hundred dollars today, the second highest
it had ever been), and you drove home with the crate in your trunk.</text><text start="333.68" dur="4.32">When you got home,
you took the crate into your trailer and left</text><text start="338" dur="7.66">it in the kitchen. The crate did not make
a ticking sound. It made no sound at all.</text><text start="345.669" dur="7.06">Nothing made a sound except you, breathing
in and breathing out. You cooked dinner (you</text><text start="352.729" dur="5.511">always cooked dinner), the red light on the
tower blinked on and off in your peripheral</text><text start="358.24" dur="6.94">vision, a message that was there and then
wasn&amp;#39;t, and that you could never quite read.</text><text start="365.18" dur="6.729">You wondered how long it would take them to
miss the crate. You did not wonder who &amp;#39;they&amp;#39;</text><text start="371.909" dur="6.47">were. Some mysteries aren&amp;#39;t questions to be
answered, but just the kind of opaque fact--</text><text start="378.379" dur="3.74">a thing which exists to be not known. </text><text start="383.64" dur="6.48">Which brings us to now. To this story. This story about you.</text><text start="390.12" dur="5.98">You are listening to the radio.
The announcer is talking about you.</text><text start="397.14" dur="7.519">And then you hear something else, a guttural howl out of the desert distance, and you know that</text><text start="404.659" dur="9.5">the crate&amp;#39;s absence has been discovered. The
crate-- well, it sits, That&amp;#39;s all. On the</text><text start="414.159" dur="9.38">kitchen floor. That&amp;#39;s all. It&amp;#39;s warm, warmer
than the air around it. It smells sharp and</text><text start="423.55" dur="7.329">earthy, like freshly ground cinnamon. And
when you put your ear against the rough warm</text><text start="430.879" dur="8.3">wood, you hear a soft humming-- an indistinct
melody. It does not appear to be difficult</text><text start="439.18" dur="10.979">to open. All you would need to do is remove
a few nails. You do not open it. You decide,</text><text start="450.16" dur="6.84">instead, to go to the Moonlight All-Night
Diner, and have a slice of pie.</text><text start="457.94" dur="12.18">The wind is hot, like always, and smells like honey and
mud. Night is your favorite time. Daylight</text><text start="470.129" dur="5.59">brings only a chain of visual sensations,
none of which cohere into meaning for you</text><text start="475.719" dur="8.44">anymore. Life has become out of focus, free
of consequence. As you drive you turn off</text><text start="484.159" dur="8.44">the headlights, for a moment. In that moment,
you feel again, above you, not even far away</text><text start="492.61" dur="9.95">now, that planet of awesome size, lit by no
sun. An invisible titan, all thick black forests</text><text start="502.56" dur="7.46">and jagged mountains and deep, turbulent oceans.
You see nothing but the faint moonlight on</text><text start="510.02" dur="7.96">your dashboard, but you know the planet is
out there-- yawning in the unseen spaces.</text><text start="519.36" dur="7.88">The moment passes. You turn your headlights
back on, and all you see is a road. Just asphalt.</text><text start="527.24" dur="8.96">Just that. And you pass a man waving semaphore
flags indicating that the speed limit for this stretch is 45.</text><text start="537.54" dur="7">The Moonlight All-Night
is radiant green; a slab of mint light in</text><text start="544.54" dur="6.09">the warm darkness. You squint when you see
it, like it hurts your eyes, but it does not</text><text start="550.63" dur="8.81">hurt your eyes. You park near the front door.
A man rolls by on the ground, his eyes bleary</text><text start="559.44" dur="8.58">and sightless, whispering the word &amp;quot;mudwomb&amp;quot;
over and over. But you don&amp;#39;t have the money</text><text start="568.02" dur="6.691">to tip him, so you go inside. You order a
slice of strawberry pie, and the waitress</text><text start="574.72" dur="6.559">indicates through words and movements that
it will be brought to you presently. The radio</text><text start="581.279" dur="9.22">speaks soothingly to you from static-y speakers
set into a foam tile ceiling. It is telling</text><text start="590.51" dur="5.08">a story about you. Your story, at last.</text><text start="602.38" dur="4.32">A
man slides into the booth across from you.</text><text start="606.709" dur="7.37">You recognize him vaguely, although he looks
considerably different now. It is that man</text><text start="614.079" dur="6.931">who appeared to be of Slavic origin, but who
dressed in an absurd caricature of an Indian</text><text start="621.01" dur="8.68">chief and called himself the Apache Tracker.
Except now, it&amp;#39;s difficult for you to miss,</text><text start="629.69" dur="7.66">he has actually transformed into a Native
American. You wonder if the pie will get there</text><text start="637.35" dur="8.71">soon. The Apache Tracker smells of potting
soil and sweat. He leans across the table</text><text start="646.06" dur="3.12">and touches your hand lightly.</text><text start="653.16" dur="3.46">You do not
pull the hand away, because you know that</text><text start="656.63" dur="3.26">there will be no consequence for any of this.</text><text start="660.94" dur="4.88">&amp;quot;Вы в опасности,&amp;quot; [Translation: You are in danger.] he says, &amp;quot;Они идут.&amp;quot;
[Translation: They&amp;#39;re coming.]</text><text start="666.7" dur="9.8">You nod. He taps the table. Then, bringing his thick eyebrows
together and pursing his lips, he leans down</text><text start="676.5" dur="10.16">and taps the ground. You nod again. &amp;quot;I think
my pie is here now,&amp;quot; you say unnecessarily,</text><text start="686.66" dur="6.789">as the pie is quite visibly placed in front of you. You did not order invisible pie. You</text><text start="693.449" dur="11.3">hate invisible pie. He looks at the pie for
a long time, and then lets his breath hiss out slowly through his nose.</text><text start="706.06" dur="4.78"> &amp;quot;Они придут
снизу. Пироги не помогут.&amp;quot; [Translation: They will come from below. Pies
will not help.]</text><text start="712.14" dur="4.54">He leaves. What an asshole that guy is!</text><text start="722.68" dur="8.5">You finish the pie and ask for
the check. &amp;quot;Check please,&amp;quot; you say, whispering</text><text start="731.19" dur="5.649">it into your drinking glass as is custom,
and then lifting the tray of sugar packets</text><text start="736.839" dur="7.1">to find it, filled out and ready to be paid.
You drop a few dollars onto the check, place</text><text start="743.949" dur="7.39">it back under the sugars, wait for the sound
of swallowing, and leave the diner. The waitress</text><text start="751.339" dur="8.8">nods as you leave, but not at you. She nods
slowly and rhythmically to music only she</text><text start="760.139" dur="7.42">can hear, her eyes riding the curved line
of neon lights above the menu.</text><text start="768.8" dur="7.7">As you start the car, the man on the radio says something
about the weather. </text><text start="776.98" dur="132.94">[&amp;quot;You Don&amp;#39;t Know&amp;quot; by Mount Moon]</text><text start="909.92" dur="5.48">The crate is in your kitchen, where
you left it, and you get down on your knees</text><text start="915.41" dur="9.02">to embrace it more fully. It has grown warmer--
even hot. It still is not ticking.</text><text start="925.48" dur="7.7"> It had taken you no time to get back home. Now that
you think about it, were there any other cars</text><text start="933.18" dur="8.3">on the road? Where did all the cars go? The
man with the semaphore flags explaining the</text><text start="941.48" dur="8.54">speed limit-- he wasn&amp;#39;t there either. Your
heart pounds. Without allowing another stray</text><text start="950.029" dur="5.971">thought to wander through your mind and delay
you, you grab the crate and throw it in your</text><text start="956" dur="6.36">trunk. You turn the ignition, and your car
radio comes alive with a pop-- just as the</text><text start="962.36" dur="8.78">announcer says that your car radio comes alive
with a pop. Where to now? You don&amp;#39;t know,</text><text start="971.14" dur="7.679">but you go there anyway. A pair of headlights,
a pair of eyes, and two shaky hands, speeding</text><text start="978.819" dur="6.871">through the silent town. Behind you, you see
helicopter searchlights sweeping down onto</text><text start="985.69" dur="7.329">your trailer. There are sirens. A purplish
cloud hangs over the town, glittering occasionally</text><text start="993.019" dur="7.12">as it rotates. The whole works. You drive
past the Moonlight All-Night-- still aglow</text><text start="1000.149" dur="6.12">and full of people slowly eating what sounds
good only late at night, and Teddy Williams&amp;#39;</text><text start="1006.269" dur="6.951">Desert Flower Bowling Alley and Arcade Fun
Complex-- which has taken to not only locking</text><text start="1013.22" dur="7.84">but barricading its doors at closing time.
You pass by City Hall which, as always, is</text><text start="1021.06" dur="7.48">completely shrouded after dark in black velvet.
Moving farther out, following the pull of</text><text start="1028.549" dur="5.86">the distant, uncertain moon, you pass by the
Car Lot (where the salesmen have been put</text><text start="1034.409" dur="6.28">away for the night), and Old Woman Josie&amp;#39;s
house (where the only sign that the unassuming</text><text start="1040.689" dur="5.98">little home could be a place of residence
for Angels is the bright halo of heavenly</text><text start="1046.669" dur="7.451">light surrounding it, and the sign out front
that says Angels&amp;#39; Residence). And the town</text><text start="1054.12" dur="7.56">is behind you, and you are out in the Scrub
Lands, and the Sand Wastes. By the road you</text><text start="1061.69" dur="6.29">see a man, holding a cactus in one hand and
a pair of scissors in the other. He shakes</text><text start="1067.98" dur="3.66">both at you as you pass, and howls.</text><text start="1073.4" dur="6.72">And then,
you are alone. Just you, and the desert.</text><text start="1081.1" dur="7.3">You stop the car and get out. Pebbles crunch in
the sand in response to your movement.</text><text start="1088.9" dur="6.88">The radio murmurs behind the closed doors of the
car. The headlights illuminate only a few</text><text start="1095.78" dur="6.64">stray plants, and the wide dumb eyes of some
nocturnal animal.</text><text start="1103.4" dur="6.76">Looking back, you see the bulge of light that is your Night Vale.</text><text start="1111.1" dur="4.04"> The
Purple Cloud, now floating over the heart</text><text start="1115.15" dur="7">of the city, reaches its tendrils in and out
of buildings.</text><text start="1122.66" dur="3.98">You hear screams, and gunfire.</text><text start="1127.5" dur="8.039">You open the trunk and lay one hand on the
crate. It pulses with some kind of life. Still</text><text start="1135.539" dur="8.98">no ticking though. You look back. Several
buildings are on fire. Crowds of people are</text><text start="1144.52" dur="8.26">floating in the air, held aloft by beams of
light, and struggling feebly against power</text><text start="1152.789" dur="7">they cannot begin to understand. The ground
shifts, like it was startled.</text><text start="1161" dur="3.58">It&amp;#39;s so quiet, when it finally comes. </text><text start="1165.34" dur="8.08">You see the black car
long before it arrives. It comes to a halt nearby and two men step out. </text><text start="1174.14" dur="3.86">You don&amp;#39;t run.
Neither do they. </text><text start="1179.36" dur="3.56">&amp;quot;How did you find me?&amp;quot; you ask.</text><text start="1183.34" dur="5.719">&amp;quot;Everything you do is being broadcast
on the radio for some reason. That made it</text><text start="1189.059" dur="4.98">pretty easy,&amp;quot; says one of the men, the one
that isn&amp;#39;t tall. </text><text start="1194.7" dur="3.36">&amp;quot;Yeah,&amp;quot; you say. &amp;quot;I see that now.&amp;quot;</text><text start="1199.3" dur="6.56">&amp;quot;You have the item?&amp;quot; the man who is
not tall asks. You say nothing. The man who</text><text start="1205.86" dur="8.34">is not tall signals the man who is not short,
and he walks past you, looks into your trunk, and nods.</text><text start="1214.8" dur="6.54">&amp;quot;Even easier,&amp;quot; says the man who
is not tall. There is an unexpected click.</text><text start="1222.4" dur="7.4">One of the rear doors of the black car has
opened, and your fiancee has stepped out.</text><text start="1230.35" dur="7.47">Her eyes are wet, like it was the night you
left. She does not appear to have aged, but</text><text start="1237.82" dur="3.82">then, you can&amp;#39;t actually remember how long
it has been.</text><text start="1242.76" dur="4.34">Could it have been last week? Or was it ten years ago?</text><text start="1248.62" dur="8.86">&amp;quot;Why?&amp;quot; she says.
&amp;quot;Why? Why?&amp;quot; You don&amp;#39;t know what to say.</text><text start="1266.3" dur="10.48">The man who is not short steps up to you, puts
a knife against your throat. Nobody says anything.</text><text start="1276.789" dur="6.58">Your fiancee shakes her head. Her eyes are
empty. Broken. Gushing.</text><text start="1284.06" dur="8.68">The radio is saying all of this as it happens. You hear it dimly
through the car door. You can&amp;#39;t stop smiling.</text><text start="1293.78" dur="8.24">All at once, the consequences. All at once
you are no longer free. It&amp;#39;s all coming back</text><text start="1302.029" dur="9.76">around. All at once. Life-- bleary, washed-out--
snaps back into focus. The red light on the</text><text start="1311.789" dur="7.08">tower still blinks in the distance and every
message in this world has a meaning. It all</text><text start="1318.87" dur="4.54">makes sense and you are finally being punished.</text><text start="1324.12" dur="4.3">You can&amp;#39;t think of a time you have ever been happier.</text><text start="1330.36" dur="5.58">Your fiancee abruptly gets back into
the car. Neither of the men seem to notice</text><text start="1335.95" dur="5.12">her. One opens the crate with a couple quick
taps,</text><text start="1341.82" dur="6.36">and pulls out of it an intricate miniature house.</text><text start="1349.26" dur="7.38">The hours that must have been spent
building it! Every detail is accounted for!</text><text start="1356.64" dur="7.02">Inside the house you think you see for a moment,
lights and movement.</text><text start="1364.6" dur="5.42">&amp;quot;Undamaged,&amp;quot; says the man who is not tall. You beam at him.</text><text start="1370.02" dur="4.08">The
knife presses harder against your throat, but it doesn&amp;#39;t hurt. </text><text start="1375.88" dur="4.899">Your eyes wander up and
you see above you the dark planet of awesome</text><text start="1380.779" dur="7.74">size perched in its sunless void, an invisible
titan all thick black forests and jagged mountains</text><text start="1388.529" dur="3.74">and deep, turbulent oceans. A monster. </text><text start="1392.66" dur="7.36">Spinning.
Soundless. Forgotten. It&amp;#39;s so close now.</text><text start="1401.24" dur="8.1">You see it just above you. Maybe even if you tried
very hard, you could touch it.</text><text start="1410.76" dur="1.22"> You reach up...</text><text start="1428.66" dur="8.06">This has been your story. The radio moves
on to other things-- news, traffic, political</text><text start="1436.73" dur="9.86">opinions, and corrections to political opinions.
But there was time, one day, one single day,</text><text start="1446.59" dur="9.79">in which it was only one story. A story about
you. And you were pleased, because you always</text><text start="1456.38" dur="9.56">wanted to hear about yourself on the radio.
Goodnight, Night Vale. Goodnight.</text><text start="1477.26" dur="5.38">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace
Books. It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey</text><text start="1482.64" dur="5.529">Cranor, and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice
of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1488.169" dur="6.341">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. Russian translation</text><text start="1494.51" dur="3.96">by Daniel Mirsky. Спасибо [Translation:
Thank you], Daniel. This episode&amp;#39;s weather</text><text start="1498.47" dur="6.179">was &amp;quot;You Don&amp;#39;t Know&amp;quot; by Mount Moon. Find out
more at mountmoon.bandcamp.com. Want to have</text><text start="1504.649" dur="3.821">your music featured in the weather section?
Want to contribute your talents to the show?</text><text start="1508.47" dur="6.78">Just want to say hi? Email us at nightvale@commonplacebooks.com,
or follow us on Twitter at @NightValeRadio.</text><text start="1515.25" dur="5.32">Check out commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1520.57" dur="4.22">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1524.79" dur="6.31"> Today&amp;#39;s proverb: I&amp;#39;d never join a pen15 club that would allow
a person like me to become a member.</text></transcript>