<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0.7" dur="4.489">Before we take you live to the lonely little
burg of Night Vale, we have an important announcement:</text><text start="5.189" dur="4.28">Welcome to Night Vale t-shirts are now available.
Go about your daily life bearing our name</text><text start="9.469" dur="5.151">upon your body. Share secret signs and messages
with passers-by in the know. Welcome to Night</text><text start="14.62" dur="5.78">Vale t-shirts. Get them today at commonplacebooks.com.
All right, that&amp;#39;s it from me. Take it, Cecil.</text><text start="20.4" dur="8.94">Look to the obelisk. We don&amp;#39;t know where it
came from, but it&amp;#39;s attracting a lot of cats.</text><text start="30.64" dur="7">Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="58" dur="6.08">Happy New Year, Night Vale!  Last night&amp;#39;s fireworks extravaganza at</text><text start="64.08" dur="8.58">the Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront Recreation
Area was beautiful! This is despite the fact</text><text start="72.67" dur="7.659">that the Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront
Recreation Area never really existed, and</text><text start="80.329" dur="6.93">was in no way a multi-million dollar failure
of municipal planning. And just because the</text><text start="87.259" dur="6.27">only things remaining on the premises are
several large piles of rubble and a red sign</text><text start="93.529" dur="6.88">reading &amp;quot;NOTHING IS HERE. NOTHING WAS EVER
HERE&amp;quot; does not mean that they failed to correctly</text><text start="100.409" dur="9.78">use tax dollars to build a harbor, a waterfront,
or a recreation area. Anyway, the fireworks</text><text start="110.189" dur="7">over the city-made sign were lovely. Happy
2013!</text><text start="118.06" dur="7.54">Ladies and gentlemen, surely you have noticed... there&amp;#39;s a Man in a Tan Jacket.</text><text start="127.08" dur="9.499">Countless residents have seen him, but no one can seem to remember exactly what he looks
like; just that he has a tan jacket and a</text><text start="136.58" dur="8.78">deerskin suitcase, and he has been spotted
all over town. But no one can quite recall</text><text start="145.37" dur="9.17">specifically where they saw him, or what time
of day it was. Just that they saw him. Frances</text><text start="154.54" dur="5.83">Donaldson-- the tall woman with the green
eyes who manages the antiques mall-- thinks</text><text start="160.37" dur="7">maybe the Man in the Tan Jacket is simply
a shared dream. But I know I saw him, Night</text><text start="167.469" dur="9.16">Vale. I know what I saw. This man couldn&amp;#39;t
possibly be a dream. He was so vivid. His</text><text start="176.629" dur="12.02">eyes were... well, his nose and his chin...
oh, I can just see! I just can&amp;#39;t remember!</text><text start="188.649" dur="10.15">The man was clear as day! He had a tan jacket,
and a deerskin suitcase. He can&amp;#39;t be a dream,</text><text start="198.799" dur="8.88">can he? Please, call in, listeners, and let
us know if you can remember anything else.</text><text start="209.8" dur="8.22">This Monday through Friday is the annual Night
Vale Career Fair at the Downtown Convention</text><text start="218.03" dur="8.26">Center. There will be dozens of booths, representing
phony local businesses that will take your</text><text start="226.29" dur="7.099">resumes and photos (via hidden surveillance
cameras) and conduct sample interviews designed</text><text start="233.389" dur="5.54">to badger you into implicating yourself in
nefarious activities.</text><text start="239.9" dur="9.24">First-generation Night Vale residents-- particularly those whose
parents were originally born in Maine, Massachusetts,</text><text start="249.15" dur="6.44">Canada, Micronesia, and Suriname-- are strongly
encouraged to attend.</text><text start="256.24" dur="9.46">This year&amp;#39;s keynote speaker is an audio tape of droning moans
leaden with subliminal tips about achieving</text><text start="265.7" dur="6.81">personal prosperity and how to come clean
about the terrible things you have done, you</text><text start="272.51" dur="8.9">cretin. Last year&amp;#39;s fair featured several
very high-profile arrests, and exciting door</text><text start="281.41" dur="10.4">prizes. Tickets are $25-- or $15 if you still
have working retinas to scan.</text><text start="293.12" dur="8.84">Over the weekend, Teddy Williams-- owner of the Desert Flower
Bowling Alley and Arcade Fun Complex-- sent</text><text start="301.97" dur="8">us some security camera footage of what he
believes to be the first-ever glimpse of citizens</text><text start="309.97" dur="8.92">of the Underground City deep below Lane Five.
Early Saturday morning, Fun Complex cameras</text><text start="318.89" dur="7.17">picked up blurry motion near the soda machine.
The footage is quite fuzzy and difficult to</text><text start="326.06" dur="6.67">discern. Perhaps it is merely rats or raccoons,
digging through an uncovered supply of junk</text><text start="332.73" dur="7.4">food. But it is, of course, much more likely
that a lost nation of people, living in the</text><text start="340.13" dur="7.09">bowels of a small-town bowling alley, are
finally revealing themselves, taking our food</text><text start="347.22" dur="7.86">supplies, and preparing for war. Teddy told
us that he believes this city to be thousands</text><text start="355.08" dur="7.22">strong and ready to move into Night Vale.
Ready to take arms against the &amp;quot;Upper World&amp;quot;</text><text start="362.3" dur="6.88">(as they probably call us). Ready to conquer
this heaven and become the righteous owners</text><text start="369.18" dur="8.02">of our sun-soaked precious land... we assume.
It takes very little extrapolation to believe</text><text start="377.21" dur="7.41">that they worship a god named Huntokhar, who
demands sacrifice to keep their Underground</text><text start="384.62" dur="7.16">City thriving in the absence of nourishing
sunlight. And a fair assumption is they are</text><text start="391.78" dur="8.18">ruled by a Child King, recently coronated,
who is too weak to rein back the generals</text><text start="399.96" dur="3.58">intent on marching upon us in war.</text><text start="405.04" dur="3.96"> Ladies
and gentlemen, if you care for your community,</text><text start="409" dur="9.04">your town, your Night Vale like I do, you
will arm yourselves. You will rally your neighbors</text><text start="418.04" dur="6.27">to militia. You will point fingers at those
who do not wish to fight and have them rounded</text><text start="424.31" dur="10.08">up into pens. This is no time for the weak.
We are at a presumptive war with a projected</text><text start="434.39" dur="9.14">enemy whom we cannot yet see, or even be certain
of, but who are probably bloodthirsty giants.</text><text start="444.48" dur="7.36">If you would like to learn more about starting
a militia, simply learn to be a true American.</text><text start="451.84" dur="9.9">That&amp;#39;s how you&amp;#39;ll know. And remember, Night
Vale is at war. Your careless talk costs lives.</text><text start="461.75" dur="7">They know we are here, and it seems somebody
talked.</text><text start="468.75" dur="8.05">Who was it, Night Vale? Was it Steve Carlsberg? Did Steve Carlsberg talk? </text><text start="476.8" dur="3.44">Maybe
a group of good citizens should go have a</text><text start="480.25" dur="8.61">&amp;quot;chat&amp;quot; with Steve and find out what he&amp;#39;s been
saying, and to whom. Stay by your radios,</text><text start="488.86" dur="5.1">listeners. We will report further as events
warrant. </text><text start="496.92" dur="4.78">More now on the Man in the Tan Jacket.</text><text start="503.02" dur="8.1">Old Woman Josie called to tell us that her
Angel friends are saying that the deerskin</text><text start="511.12" dur="9.18">suitcase is full of flies. The Angels would
not tell her more, explaining that knowing</text><text start="520.31" dur="8.3">more would jeopardize her Eternal Soul, as
well as their own statuses as Angels. They</text><text start="528.61" dur="7.14">did not want to mess with that! Old Woman
Josie added that she thinks the Man in the</text><text start="535.75" dur="7.62">Tan Jacket is just a salesman of some sort.
A fly salesman, she bets, wandering from town</text><text start="543.37" dur="10.13">to town with polished shoes and a suitcase
full of flies. &amp;quot;Oh, I just can&amp;#39;t stand those</text><text start="553.5" dur="8.3">fly salesmen,&amp;quot; she said. &amp;quot;Ringing my doorbell
at 3am, wanting to show me samples and asking</text><text start="561.81" dur="2.5">for glasses of orange milk!&amp;quot;</text><text start="566.72" dur="4.28">The Night Vale
Daily Journal has announced that, despite</text><text start="571.01" dur="7.82">cost-cutting measures and mandatory subscription
laws, it is facing a huge budget shortfall this year.</text><text start="580.16" dur="6.62"> &amp;quot;We cannot pay back our printers,
or our delivery crews,&amp;quot; said editor Leanne</text><text start="586.78" dur="7.96">Hart, in a prepared statement whispered through
my mail slot late last night. &amp;quot;And we have</text><text start="594.75" dur="7">already had to banish much of our staff into
the Sand Wastes of the desert.&amp;quot;</text><text start="602.68" dur="7.72">She went on to explain that this &amp;quot;budget shortfall&amp;quot; has
nothing to do with the reported lavish birthday</text><text start="610.41" dur="8.01">party she threw for herself in Night Vale
Stadium, featuring a lazy river made entirely</text><text start="618.42" dur="7.78">of champagne and a birthday cake topped with
very thin slices of moon rock.</text><text start="627.28" dur="8.78">In an addendum she tapped in Morse code on my bathroom window,
she said that the Journal is considering all</text><text start="636.07" dur="8.1">new sources of income-- including creating
additional advertising space and mugging Night</text><text start="644.17" dur="6.88">Vale citizens, and that I shouldn&amp;#39;t mention
the whole birthday party thing after all,</text><text start="651.05" dur="7.12">because she was never even born, so how could
she have had a birthday party?</text><text start="659.5" dur="8.94">She spent the rest of the night tapping out the phrase &amp;quot;birthdays
are a fake idea,&amp;quot; which actually was a pretty</text><text start="668.45" dur="3.54">relaxing sound to fall asleep to.</text><text start="673.22" dur="4.98"> Hey, kids
and parents! Time once again for our Children&amp;#39;s</text><text start="678.2" dur="10.56">Fun Fact Science Corner! Today we are exploring
common birds and their meanings. An eagle</text><text start="688.76" dur="7.36">indicates that an important phone call is
impending. A sparrow says that you should</text><text start="696.12" dur="9.74">beware the sea, and sell any stocks invested
in food-based companies. A pigeon means that</text><text start="705.86" dur="5.94">your mother has died-- or that all is well.
It&amp;#39;s a bit uncertain.</text><text start="713.48" dur="7.7">A hummingbird tells us that the physical constants of the universe
are slowly degrading and may someday shift,</text><text start="721.19" dur="4.81">invalidating the laws of physics and instantly
wiping out the universe as we know it while</text><text start="726" dur="7.52">simultaneously creating an entirely new universe
in a single transcendent moment of genocide</text><text start="733.529" dur="9.84">and genesis. As for hawks, well... no one
knows what hawks mean, or if they are real.</text><text start="744.02" dur="6.22">Have you ever even seen a hawk? Of course
not. No one has.</text><text start="751.68" dur="4.26">This has been our Children&amp;#39;s Fun Fact Science Corner.</text><text start="759.62" dur="3.3">And now a word from
our sponsors.</text><text start="763.9" dur="5.72">Today&amp;#39;s program has been sponsored by the physical act of gulping.</text><text start="770.24" dur="4.06">For thousands
of years, gulping has been there for human</text><text start="774.31" dur="6.62">beings when they needed an expressive gesture
of the throat. Whether you want to indicate</text><text start="780.93" dur="7.909">nervousness about an upcoming test or appointment,
fear of the Faceless Old Woman who lives secretly</text><text start="788.839" dur="8.52">in your home, or just want to ingest milk
faster than with regular swallowing, gulping</text><text start="797.37" dur="10.11">is the way to go. Forget sweating! Never mind
shivering! Sneezing? Ugh! When you think physical</text><text start="807.48" dur="8.42">actions, think gulping! Gulp now and receive
a complimentary prize package, which will</text><text start="815.91" dur="10.4">be conveniently buried in an unmarked spot
somewhere in the Scrublands. Find it, and it&amp;#39;s yours! Gulp! </text><text start="827.56" dur="6.66">This just in: The Sheriff&amp;#39;s
Secret Police has just issued an important</text><text start="834.23" dur="7.83">request related to our earlier story. They
ask that all Night Vale citizens be on the</text><text start="842.06" dur="10.1">lookout for a Man in a Tan Jacket, carrying
a deerskin suitcase. He is about five or six</text><text start="852.16" dur="8.84">foot something, probably with hair, and normal
human features. He was last seen early this</text><text start="861.01" dur="7.29">morning on the unlit, gravel-paved stretch
of Oak Trail, near Larry Leroy&amp;#39;s house out</text><text start="868.3" dur="7.74">on the edge of town. The Man in the Tan Jacket
was reportedly seen in the moonless black,</text><text start="876.04" dur="7">standing next to a refrigerator engulfed in
flames. He was smoking a cigarette.</text><text start="884.6" dur="8.86">Witnesses claimed he stared at them as they slowly drove
by on the darkened country road, but despite</text><text start="893.46" dur="8">the prolonged eye contact, the witnesses still
could not describe his face to police.</text><text start="903" dur="7.26">Two days prior, the Man in the Tan Jacket was
seen standing in a park. No one can remember</text><text start="910.27" dur="7.96">which park, but they&amp;#39;re fairly certain it
was a park. Or, maybe, it was in the Old Navy</text><text start="918.23" dur="8.43">Outlet Store or near the invisible clock tower...
it wasn&amp;#39;t quite clear. Either way, the man</text><text start="926.66" dur="9.2">was definitely standing with his deerskin
suitcase, and staring up at the sun for hours.</text><text start="935.86" dur="7.22">He followed the bizarre glowing orb, which
is somehow the source of all light and life,</text><text start="943.08" dur="4.83">and — &amp;quot;Oh god, the sun, are you kidding
us with this thing? We don&amp;#39;t even have time</text><text start="947.91" dur="8.21">for that mystery!&amp;quot; the Secret Police then
interjected. Secret Police officials added</text><text start="956.12" dur="9.3">that if you see a Man in a Tan Jacket carrying
a deerskin suitcase, write down what you see</text><text start="965.42" dur="7.88">immediately. The City Council has temporarily
lifted their ban on pens and pencils, so that</text><text start="973.3" dur="7.5">citizens can help law enforcement on this
matter. Once you write down your encounter,</text><text start="980.8" dur="9.46">call 911 immediately, or simply say, &amp;quot;Hey,
police!&amp;quot; out loud. We&amp;#39;re all being monitored</text><text start="990.27" dur="7">almost 24/7, so they&amp;#39;ll probably hear you
just fine.</text><text start="998.62" dur="2.58">Let&amp;#39;s go now to traffic.</text><text start="1002.52" dur="7.26">There  is a car. It&amp;#39;s not in Night Vale, or even
in the desert that cradles our little town.</text><text start="1010.32" dur="8.76">It&amp;#39;s out somewhere beyond that. There are
many cars there, but I&amp;#39;m speaking only about one.</text><text start="1019.9" dur="6.54">Blue, square-ish, with tires and windows
and an engine that works... most of the time.</text><text start="1027.239" dur="7.54">A woman is driving it, and she is also glancing
whenever she can at the child in the passenger seat.</text><text start="1035.3" dur="8.88">He is a child, but he is 15. You understand.
She is glancing at him, but she is not saying</text><text start="1044.189" dur="4.74">anything. And he is not saying anything either.</text><text start="1050.06" dur="4.04">She wants to cry, or, she wants to push</text><text start="1054.1" dur="7.34">him out of the car... ... or, she wants to
go back in time and insist on using a condom...</text><text start="1062.18" dur="6.38">... only she would never do that. She wouldn&amp;#39;t
change any of this, really. Not for all the</text><text start="1068.57" dur="7.429">money-- piles of money, some of it defunct
money from defunct and absent governments--</text><text start="1075.999" dur="8.82">she wouldn&amp;#39;t give any of this back. So she
drives her car. Blue. Square-ish.</text><text start="1084.819" dur="5.92">With tires, and windows, and an engine that works... most
of the time.</text><text start="1091.7" dur="6.6">And she glances at the 15 year-old child. And neither of them speaks.</text><text start="1098.76" dur="6.7"> This has
been traffic. And now, the weather.</text><text start="1106.92" dur="99.7">[&amp;quot;Movement 1: Invocation of the Duke&amp;quot; by daKAH Hip Hop Orchestra]</text><text start="1206.62" dur="10.08">Ladies and gentlemen: During the break, I received a call from someone claiming
to be an Angel.</text><text start="1216.7" dur="10.1">Now, I don&amp;#39;t know if this was a prank or not, as no one has ever actually
proven that they&amp;#39;ve talked to an Angel. Even</text><text start="1226.8" dur="9.42">Old Woman Josie&amp;#39;s word is just that, her word.
But listeners, I think this had to have been</text><text start="1236.23" dur="10.429">an Angel, because my face became hot, and
the voice filled every part of my body, and</text><text start="1246.659" dur="6.83">tears were flowing down my face the instant
I touched the phone receiver, and the whole</text><text start="1253.489" dur="5.88">room was lit up in-- well, how can I describe
this?--</text><text start="1260.32" dur="6.46">a bright black beam illuminating every atomic detail!</text><text start="1267.72" dur="7.019">And the Angel-- if that is
indeed who called-- the Angel said that the</text><text start="1274.739" dur="8.94">Man in the Tan Jacket with the deerskin suitcase
was from a place underneath the earth.</text><text start="1284.86" dur="11.4">Underneath our knowledge. A vast world, right below our
feet. I asked for more, but the Angel-- if</text><text start="1296.269" dur="7">that is indeed who called-- whispered only,
&amp;quot;A flower in the desert.&amp;quot;</text><text start="1304.74" dur="6.42">And it filled me with ecstasy and dread.</text><text start="1312.48" dur="6.86">Then the call ended,
and the black ray of truth was gone, and I</text><text start="1319.35" dur="9.26">was breathless and alone. And dear listeners,
the silence...</text><text start="1329.72" dur="7.9">Well, it was unlike any silence you have ever not heard.</text><text start="1339.4" dur="6.66">So our mystery man
remains un-found. And I&amp;#39;m still not sure why</text><text start="1346.07" dur="10.22">an Angel would have to use a telephone. But,
for now, we can only know what we know.</text><text start="1356.8" dur="4.22">And that is that we don&amp;#39;t know. </text><text start="1362.44" dur="5.819">Thank you again
for listening, listeners. I look forward to</text><text start="1368.26" dur="8.08">another fine year. A new year, well-spent
with all of you out there.</text><text start="1377.26" dur="6.32">Stay tuned next for two commercial-free hours of E♯. </text><text start="1385.02" dur="7.379">Goodnight, Night Vale. Be alert, and write down everything</text><text start="1392.399" dur="5.82">you cannot comprehend. Until next time.</text><text start="1403.14" dur="6.76">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books. It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey
Cranor, and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice</text><text start="1409.96" dur="6.02">of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music
by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded</text><text start="1415.98" dur="5.769">for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s
weather was &amp;quot;Invocation of the Duke&amp;quot; by daKAH</text><text start="1421.749" dur="7.18">Hip Hop Orchestra. Find out more at myspace.com/dakah.
Want to have your music featured in the weather</text><text start="1428.929" dur="6.38">section? Want to contribute your talents to
the show? Just want to say hi? Email us at</text><text start="1435.309" dur="3.92">nightvale@commonplacebooks.com, or follow
us on Twitter at @NightValeRadio. Check out</text><text start="1439.229" dur="4.481">commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1443.71" dur="4.42">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1448.13" dur="5.22">Today&amp;#39;s proverb: Biologically speaking, we are all people,
made up of smaller people.</text></transcript>