<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0.04" dur="3.66">The desert seems vast, even endless, </text><text start="4.22" dur="6.48">and yet scientists tell us that somewhere, even now, there is snow.</text><text start="11.46" dur="3.06">Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="38.2" dur="8.98">The Night Vale Tourism Board&amp;#39;s Visitable Night Vale campaign has kicked off with posters encouraging folks to take their family on</text><text start="47.19" dur="6.799">a scenery-filled jaunt through the trails of Radon Canyon. Their slogan? &amp;quot;The view is</text><text start="53.989" dur="6.221">literally breathtaking.&amp;quot; Posters will be placed at police stations and frozen yogurt shops</text><text start="60.21" dur="7">in nearby towns, along with promotional giveaways of plastic sheeting and re-breathers.</text><text start="67.38" dur="4.18">And now, the news. Have any of our listeners seen the glowing</text><text start="71.57" dur="6.28">cloud that has been moving in from the west? Well, John Peters-- you know, the farmer?--</text><text start="77.85" dur="4.76">he saw it over the western ridge this morning, said he would have thought it was the setting</text><text start="82.61" dur="7">sun if it wasn&amp;#39;t for the time of day. Apparently the cloud glows in a variety of colors,</text><text start="89.61" dur="7.81">perhaps changing from observer to observer, although all report a low whistling when it draws near.</text><text start="100.64" dur="7.3">One death has already been attributed to the glow cloud. But listen, it&amp;#39;s probably nothing.</text><text start="107.94" dur="5.23">If we had to shut down the town for every mysterious event that at least one death could</text><text start="113.17" dur="5.75">be attributed to, we&amp;#39;d never have time to do anything, right? That&amp;#39;s what the Sheriff&amp;#39;s</text><text start="118.92" dur="6.559">Secret Police are saying, and I agree. Although, I would not go so far as to endorse their</text><text start="125.479" dur="7.321">suggestion to run directly at the cloud, shrieking and waving your arms, just to see what it does.</text><text start="137.4" dur="3.26">The Apache Tracker-- and I remind you that</text><text start="140.66" dur="6.67">this is that white guy who wears the huge and cartoonishly inaccurate Indian headdress--</text><text start="147.33" dur="5.28">has announced that he has found some disturbing evidence concerning the recent incident at</text><text start="152.61" dur="5.9">the Night Vale Post Office, which has been sealed by the city council since the great</text><text start="158.51" dur="7">screaming that was heard from it a few weeks ago. He said that using ancient Indian magics</text><text start="166.01" dur="6.38">he slipped through council security into the post office, and observed that all the letters</text><text start="172.39" dur="6.15">and packages had been thrown about as in a whirlwind, that there was the heavy stench</text><text start="178.54" dur="9.66">of scorched flesh, that the words written in blood on the wall said, &amp;quot;More to come, and soon.&amp;quot;</text><text start="189.32" dur="5.94">Can you believe this guy said he used Indian magics? What an asshole.</text><text start="203.8" dur="7.58">Here&amp;#39;s something odd. There is a cat hovering in the men&amp;#39;s bathroom at the radio station here.</text><text start="211.38" dur="6.18">He seems perfectly happy and healthy, but it&amp;#39;s floating about four feet off the</text><text start="217.56" dur="7.34">ground next to the sink. Doesn&amp;#39;t seem to be able to move from its current hover spot.</text><text start="225.2" dur="5.68">If you pet him, he purrs, and he&amp;#39;ll rub on your body like a normal cat if you get close</text><text start="230.88" dur="5.41">enough. Fortunately, because he&amp;#39;s right by the sink, it was pretty easy to leave some</text><text start="236.29" dur="6.51">water and food where he could get it, and it&amp;#39;s nice to have a station pet. Wish it wasn&amp;#39;t</text><text start="242.8" dur="6.77">trapped in a hovering prison in the men&amp;#39;s bathroom, but listen: no pet is perfect. It</text><text start="249.57" dur="4.3">becomes perfect when you learn to accept it for what it is.</text><text start="258.52" dur="3.6">And now, a message from our sponsors.</text><text start="262.72" dur="4.28">I took a walk on the cool sand dunes, brittle</text><text start="267" dur="7.5">grass overgrown, and above me in the night sky above me I saw.</text><text start="275.34" dur="9.7">Bitter taste of unripe peaches and a smell I could not place nor could I escape. I remembered other times that</text><text start="285.04" dur="8.88">I could not escape. I remembered other smells. The moon slunk like a wounded animal. The</text><text start="293.93" dur="8.56">world spun like it had lost control. Concentrate only on breathing, and let go of ideas you</text><text start="302.49" dur="9.97">had about nutrition and alarm clocks. I took a walk on the cool sand dunes, brittle grass</text><text start="312.46" dur="7.9">overgrown, and above me in the night sky above me I saw.</text><text start="321.42" dur="7">This message was brought to you by Coca Cola. The city council, in cooperation with government</text><text start="328.43" dur="6.78">agents from a vague, yet menacing, agency, is asking all citizens to stop by the Night</text><text start="335.21" dur="6.419">Vale Elementary School gymnasium tonight at seven for a brief questionnaire about mysterious</text><text start="341.629" dur="7">sights that definitely no one saw, and strange thoughts that in no way occurred to anyone,</text><text start="348.92" dur="7.04">because all of us are normal, and to be otherwise would make us outcasts from our own community.</text><text start="355.96" dur="6.04">Remember: if you see something, say nothing, and drink to forget.</text><text start="363.8" dur="5.619">The Boy Scouts of Night Vale have announced some slight changes to their hierarchy, which</text><text start="369.419" dur="9.78">will now be the following: Cub Scout, Boy Scout, Eagle Scout, Blood Pact Scout, Weird</text><text start="379.21" dur="10.949">Scout, Dreadnought Scout, Dark Scout, Fear Scout, and finally, Eternal Scout. As always,</text><text start="390.159" dur="6.07">signup is automatic and random, so please keep an eye out for the scarlet envelope that</text><text start="396.229" dur="4.52">will let you know your son has been chosen for the process.</text><text start="403.64" dur="6.42">This is probably nothing listeners, but John Peters-- you know, the farmer-- he reports</text><text start="410.069" dur="6.71">that the Glow Cloud is directly over Old Town Night Vale, and appears to be raining small</text><text start="416.779" dur="9.46">creatures upon the earth. Armadillos, lizards, a few crows-- that kind of thing. Fortunately,</text><text start="426.249" dur="5.241">the animals appear to be dead already, so the Night Vale Animal Control Department has</text><text start="431.49" dur="5.47">said that it should be a snap to clean those up. They just have to be tossed on the Eternal</text><text start="436.96" dur="6.849">Animal Pyre in Mission Grove Park, so, if that&amp;#39;s the worst the Glow Cloud has for us,</text><text start="443.809" dur="7.871">I say go ahead and do your daily errands. Just bring along a good strong umbrella capable</text><text start="451.68" dur="7.42">of handling falling animals up to, say, ten pounds. More on the Glow Cloud as it continues</text><text start="459.11" dur="7.609">to crawl across our sky. And hey, here&amp;#39;s a tip: take your kids out, and use the Cloud&amp;#39;s</text><text start="466.719" dur="6.931">constantly mutating hue to teach him or her the names of colors. It&amp;#39;s fun, and it shows</text><text start="473.65" dur="3.7">them the real-life applications of learning.</text><text start="480.65" dur="10.849">Alert: the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Police are searching for a fugitive named Hiram McDaniels, who escaped custody last night following a 9pm arrest.</text><text start="491.499" dur="7.06">McDaniels is described as a five-headed dragon, approximately 18 feet tall, with mostly</text><text start="498.569" dur="7">green eyes and weighing about 3600 pounds. He is suspected of insurance fraud.</text><text start="506.1" dur="5.58">McDaniels was pulled over for speeding last night, and the Secret Police became suspicious when he</text><text start="511.68" dur="7.04">allegedly gave the officers a fake driver&amp;#39;s license for a five foot eight man named Frank Chen.</text><text start="518.72" dur="4.98">After discerning that Frank Chen was actually a five-headed dragon from somewhere</text><text start="523.7" dur="6.52">other than our little world, the Secret Police searched McDaniels&amp;#39; vehicle. Representatives</text><text start="530.22" dur="5.52">from local civil rights organizations have protested that officers had no legal grounds</text><text start="535.74" dur="6.69">to search the vehicle, but they ceded the point when reminded by Secret Police officials</text><text start="542.43" dur="5.64">that our backwards court system will uphold any old authoritarian rule made up on the</text><text start="548.07" dur="7.27">fly by unsupervised gun-carrying thugs of a shadow government. The Secret Police say</text><text start="555.34" dur="5.44">McDaniels escaped police custody by breathing fire from his purple head, and he was last</text><text start="560.78" dur="6.62">seen flying and shrieking over Red Mesa. Secret Police are asking for tips leading to the</text><text start="567.4" dur="7">arrest of Hiram McDaniels. They remind you that, if seen, he should not be approached,</text><text start="574.4" dur="7.48">as he is literally a five headed dragon. Contact the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Police if you have any</text><text start="581.88" dur="6.14">information. Ask for Officer Ben. Helpful tipsters will earn one stamp on their</text><text start="588.02" dur="7.54">Alert Citizen card. Collect five stamps, and you get stop sign immunity for one year.</text><text start="600.28" dur="8.34">And now, a look at the community calendar. Saturday, the public library will be unknowable.</text><text start="608.62" dur="6.28">Citizens will forget the existence of the library from 6am Saturday morning until 11pm</text><text start="614.91" dur="6.37">that night. The library will be under a sort of renovation. It is not important what kind</text><text start="621.28" dur="6.07">of renovation. Sunday is Dot Day! Remember, red dots on what</text><text start="627.35" dur="7">you love, blue dots on what you don&amp;#39;t. Mixing those up can cause permanent consequences.</text><text start="635.32" dur="6.26">Monday, Louie Blascoe is offering bluegrass lessons in the back of Louie&amp;#39;s Music Shop.</text><text start="642.34" dur="5.82">Of course, the shop burned down years ago, and Louie skipped town immediately after with</text><text start="648.16" dur="5.67">his insurance money, but he&amp;#39;s sent word that you should bring your instrument to the crumbled</text><text start="653.83" dur="5.96">ashy shell of where his shop once was, and pretend that he is there in the darkness teaching</text><text start="659.79" dur="6.28">you. The price is $50 per lesson, payable in advance.</text><text start="666.07" dur="8.29">Tuesday afternoon, join the Night Vale PTA for a bake sale to support Citizens for a Blood Space War.</text><text start="674.36" dur="4.58">Proceeds will go to support neutron bomb development and deployment to</text><text start="678.95" dur="6.6">our outer solar system allies. Wednesday has been cancelled due to a scheduling</text><text start="685.55" dur="6.92">error. And on Thursday is a free concert. And...that&amp;#39;s all it says here.</text><text start="698.24" dur="3.52">New call in from John Peters-- you know, the farmer?</text><text start="701.76" dur="5.5">Seems the Glow Cloud has doubled in size, enveloping all of Night Vale in its</text><text start="707.27" dur="5.63">weird light and humming song. Little League administration has announced that they will</text><text start="712.9" dur="5.51">be going ahead with the game, although there will be an awning built over the field die</text><text start="718.41" dur="6.41">to the increasing size of the animal corpses being dropped. I&amp;#39;ve had multiple reports that</text><text start="724.82" dur="6.62">a lion, like the kind you would see on the sunbaked plains of Africa, or a pee-stained</text><text start="731.44" dur="7">enclosure at a local zoo, fell on top of the White Sand Ice Cream Shop. The Shop is offering</text><text start="738.62" dur="5.74">a free dipped cone to anyone who can figure out how to get the thing off.</text><text start="744.36" dur="6.09">The Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Police have apparently taken to shouting questions at the Glow Cloud,</text><text start="750.45" dur="7.46">trying to ascertain what exactly it wants. So far, the Glow Cloud has not answered.</text><text start="758.7" dur="9.14">The Glow Cloud does not need to converse with us. It does not feel as we tiny humans feel.</text><text start="767.84" dur="9.16">It has no need for thoughts or feelings of love. The Glow Cloud simply is.</text><text start="777" dur="7.84">All hail the mighty Glow Cloud. All hail.</text><text start="784.96" dur="6.2">And now, slaves of the Cloud, the weather.</text><text start="791.16" dur="171.46">(The Bus is Late, Satellite High)</text><text start="962.62" dur="3.54">Sorry, listeners. Not sure what happened in</text><text start="966.16" dur="6.42">that earlier section of the broadcast. As in, I actually don&amp;#39;t remember what happened.</text><text start="973.12" dur="7.28">Tried to play back the tapes, but they&amp;#39;re all blank, and smell faintly of vanilla.</text><text start="980.42" dur="6.59">The Glow Cloud, meanwhile, has moved on. It is now just a glowing spot in the distance,</text><text start="987.01" dur="7.55">humming east to destinations unknown. We may never fully understand, or, understand at</text><text start="994.56" dur="5.54">all what it was and why it dumped a lot of dead animals on our community.  </text><text start="1000.94" dur="8.84">But, and I&amp;#39;m going to get a little personal here, that&amp;#39;s the essence of life, isn&amp;#39;t it? Sometimes you</text><text start="1009.78" dur="6.19">go through things that seem huge at the time, like a mysterious glowing cloud devouring</text><text start="1015.97" dur="6.88">your entire community. While they&amp;#39;re happening they feel like the only thing that matters,</text><text start="1022.85" dur="5.029">and you can hardly imagine that there&amp;#39;s a world out there that might have anything else</text><text start="1027.879" dur="8.54">going on. And then the Glow Cloud moves on. And you move on. And the event is behind you.</text><text start="1036.419" dur="10.04">And you may find that, as time passes, you remember it less and less-- or absolutely</text><text start="1046.459" dur="6.511">not at all, in my case. And you are left with nothing but a powerful wonder at the fleeting</text><text start="1052.97" dur="8.92">nature of even the most important things in life, and the faint, but pretty, smell of vanilla.</text><text start="1066.18" dur="4.62">Dear listeners, here is a list of things.</text><text start="1072.1" dur="11.86">Emotions you don&amp;#39;t understand upon viewing a sunset. Lost pets, found. Lost pets, unfound.</text><text start="1084.72" dur="13.4">A secret lost pet city on the moon. Trees that see. Restaurants that hear. A void that thinks.</text><text start="1098.12" dur="8.4">A face half seen just before falling asleep. Trembling hands reaching for desperately</text><text start="1106.529" dur="11.18">needed items. Sandwiches. Silence when there should be noise. Noise when there should be silence.</text><text start="1118.34" dur="8.339">Nothing when you want something. Something when you thought there was nothing.</text><text start="1126.679" dur="8.82">Clear plastic binder sheets. Scented dryer sheets. Rain coming down in sheets.</text><text start="1136.66" dur="7.94">Night. Rest. Sleep. End.</text><text start="1146.12" dur="4.8">Goodnight, listeners. Goodnight.</text><text start="1153.7" dur="4.78">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books. It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey Cranor,</text><text start="1158.48" dur="3.88">and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin.</text><text start="1162.37" dur="5.519">Original music by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded for free at disparition.info.</text><text start="1167.889" dur="7">This episode&amp;#39;s weather was &amp;quot;The Bus is Late&amp;quot; by Satellite High. Find out more at satellite-high.com.</text><text start="1174.889" dur="4.67">Check out commonplacebooks.com for more information on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1179.559" dur="4">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1183.56" dur="7.96">Today&amp;#39;s proverb: Men are from Mars, women are from Venus, Earth is a hallucination, podcasts are dreams.</text></transcript>