<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="6.49">The Arctic is lit by the midnight sun. The
surface of the moon is lit by the face of</text><text start="6.49" dur="7">the Earth. Our little town is lit too, by
lights just above that we cannot explain.</text><text start="14.1" dur="2.64">Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="40.24" dur="8.92">The Night Vale Daily
Journal has announced that they will be cutting back their publication schedule to Monday through Thursday only, due to the economic</text><text start="49.17" dur="6.35">downturn and a massive decline in the literate
population. The Thursday Daily Journal will</text><text start="55.52" dur="6.35">now be called the Weekend Edition, and on
Sundays, newspaper kiosks usually filled with</text><text start="61.87" dur="7.499">important newsprint will be filled with 2%
milk. When asked why milk, the Journal&amp;#39;s publishing</text><text start="69.369" dur="7.4">editor Leann Hart said, &amp;quot;It is important that
we maintain an unbiased approach to news reporting.&amp;quot;</text><text start="81.749" dur="6.37">The Night Vale Business Association is proud
to announce the new Night Vale Stadium, next</text><text start="88.119" dur="6.411">to The Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront Recreation
Area. The stadium will be able to seat 50,000,</text><text start="94.53" dur="6.53">but will be closed all nights of the year
except for November 10th, for the annual parade</text><text start="101.06" dur="6.449">of the mysterious hooded figures, in which
all of our favorite ominous hooded figures--</text><text start="107.509" dur="5.511">the one that lurks under the slide in the
Night Vale Elementary playground, the ones</text><text start="113.02" dur="6.769">that meet regularly in the dog park, and the
one that will occasionally openly steal babies,</text><text start="119.789" dur="6.72">and for reasons no one can understand, we
all stand by and let him do it-- all of them</text><text start="126.509" dur="8.12">will be parading proudly through Night Vale
Stadium. I tell you, with these new facilities,</text><text start="134.63" dur="7.54">it promises to be quite a spectacle. And then,
it promises to be a vast, dark, and echo-y</text><text start="142.17" dur="5.86">space for the other meaningless 364 days of
the year.</text><text start="153.2" dur="9.34">Here at the radio station it&amp;#39;s contract  negotiation season with the station management
again! That&amp;#39;s always an interesting time.</text><text start="162.55" dur="7.13">Now, obviously, I&amp;#39;m not allowed to go into
details, but negotiation is tricky when you&amp;#39;re</text><text start="169.68" dur="6.66">never allowed to glimpse what you&amp;#39;re negotiating
with. Station management stays inside their</text><text start="176.34" dur="6.52">office at all times, only communicating with
us through sealed envelopes that are spat</text><text start="182.86" dur="7.28">out from under the door like a sunflower shell
through teeth. Then, in order to respond,</text><text start="190.14" dur="6.19">you just kind of shout at the closed door
and hope that management hears. Sometimes</text><text start="196.33" dur="6.78">you can see movements through the frosted
glass, large shaped shifting around, strange</text><text start="203.11" dur="7.14">tendrils whipping through the air. Architecturally
speaking, the apparent size of management&amp;#39;s</text><text start="210.25" dur="5.96">office does not physically make sense given
the size of the building, but it&amp;#39;s hard to</text><text start="216.21" dur="9.5">say really, as no one has ever seen the actual
office. Only its translucence. Look, I&amp;#39;ve</text><text start="225.71" dur="6.12">probably said too much. I can see down the
hall that an envelope just came flying out.</text><text start="231.83" dur="9.239">I pray it&amp;#39;s not another HR retraining session
in the Dark Box. Uhhhhhg. But what can I say.</text><text start="241.069" dur="9.451">I&amp;#39;m a reporter at heart! I can&amp;#39;t not report.
Oh! My. Let&amp;#39;s go to the</text><text start="250.52" dur="9.82">seven-day outlook. Your daily shades of the
sky forecast. Monday: turquoise. Tuesday:</text><text start="260.34" dur="12.94">taupe. Wednesday: robin&amp;#39;s egg. Thursday: turquoise-taupe.
Friday: coal dust. Saturday: coal dust with</text><text start="273.29" dur="7">chances of indigo in the late afternoon. Sunday:
void.</text><text start="283.92" dur="6.92">The city council has asked me to remind everyone about the new drive to clean up litter.</text><text start="290.84" dur="3.32">Night Vale is our home. And who wants to leave</text><text start="294.17" dur="6.83">trash all over their home? Put it in the garbage
can, listeners. And if you see any trash around,</text><text start="301" dur="8.06">pick it up, and throw it away! Do your part.
Unless the trash is marked with a small red</text><text start="309.06" dur="5.91">flag. The council has asked me to remind you
that any litter marked with a red flag is</text><text start="314.97" dur="10.53">not to be picked up or approached. Remember
the slogan: No flag? Goes in the bag. Red flag? Run.</text><text start="327.28" dur="8.32">Listeners, we are currently fielding
numerous reports that books have stopped working.</text><text start="335.61" dur="6.22">It seems that all over Night Vale, books have
simply ceased functioning. The scientists</text><text start="341.83" dur="4.41">are studying one of the broken books to see
if they can understand just what is going</text><text start="346.24" dur="8.98">on here. The exact problem is currently unclear,
but some of the words being used include &amp;#39;sparks,&amp;#39;</text><text start="355.23" dur="8.409">&amp;#39;meat smell,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;biting,&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;lethal gas.&amp;#39;
For your own safety, please do not attempt</text><text start="363.639" dur="6.471">to open a book until we have more information
on the nature and cause of these problems.</text><text start="370.11" dur="4.279">The city council has released only a brief
statement, indicating that their stance on</text><text start="374.389" dur="5.971">books has not changed, and that, as always,
they believe that books are dangerous and</text><text start="380.36" dur="4.54">inadvisable, and should not be kept in private
homes.</text><text start="386.64" dur="2.82">Another warning for Night Vale residents.</text><text start="389.46" dur="6.88">Sources say that the Used and Discount Sporting
Goods Store on Flint Drive is a front for</text><text start="396.35" dur="5.98">the World Government. This is based on extensive
study of the location, and also because it</text><text start="402.33" dur="6.83">has a black helicopter pad on which black
helicopters regularly depart and land; fairly</text><text start="409.16" dur="7.7">unusual for a used and discount sporting goods
store. We sent our intern, Chad, to try buying</text><text start="416.86" dur="6.95">a tennis racket, and have not heard back from
him for several weeks. This brings me to a</text><text start="423.81" dur="7.359">related point. To the parents of Chad the
Intern: we regret to inform you that your</text><text start="431.169" dur="6.6">son was lost in the line of community radio
duty, and that he will be missed, and never</text><text start="437.77" dur="6.78">forgotten. May you all feel blessed to have
the family that you have, and if you&amp;#39;re looking</text><text start="444.55" dur="6.95">for sporting goods, check out Play Ball right
over by our own community radio station! Play</text><text start="451.5" dur="7">Ball is only a front for the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret
Police, and so can be completely trusted.</text><text start="464.77" dur="6.63">Larry Leroy, out on the edge of town, reported
that a creeping fear came into Night Vale</text><text start="471.4" dur="8.06">today. He felt it first as a mild apprehension,
then, a growing worry, and finally, a mortal</text><text start="479.47" dur="5.62">panic. It passed from him to the employees
at the car lot, who crouched behind their</text><text start="485.09" dur="7.59">cars and cast fearful eyes at the empty sky.
It did not affect Old Woman Josie, presumably</text><text start="492.68" dur="5.76">because of her angelic protection, but it
went from there to the rest of the town until</text><text start="498.44" dur="7.38">we all were shivering in anticipation for
a terrible thing we could not yet see. I myself</text><text start="505.83" dur="7.3">was frozen, sure that any movement would lead
to death, that any word would be my last.</text><text start="513.13" dur="5.61">Of course, that also could have been the contracts
negotiations with station management, and</text><text start="518.74" dur="8">the hideous envelope I just received. Also,
I&amp;#39;m battling Lyme disease. Meanwhile, the</text><text start="526.75" dur="6.08">creeping fear passed, first leaving Larry
Leroy out on the edge of town, and then the</text><text start="532.83" dur="6.11">car lot, where they went back to offering
gently used cars at affordable prices, and</text><text start="538.94" dur="5.05">finally, the rest of us, who could go back
to living with the knowledge that at any given</text><text start="543.99" dur="6.55">moment we will either live or die, and it&amp;#39;s
no use guessing which. It is not currently</text><text start="550.54" dur="8.4">known where the creeping fear will go next--
hopefully, to Desert Bluffs. It would serve them right.</text><text start="561.44" dur="5.12">Two hawkeyed listeners sent in
reports that Carlos, our curious scientific</text><text start="566.57" dur="6.85">visitor, was seen getting his beautiful, beautiful
hair cut. He was having his gorgeous hair</text><text start="573.42" dur="9.66">shorn! Cut! Cut short! So very short from
his perfectly shaped brilliant head. Listeners,</text><text start="583.08" dur="6.13">I am not one to gossip even if it is a local
celebrity, but please explain to me why Carlos</text><text start="589.21" dur="7">would strip away-- decimate!-- any part of
his thick black hair-- not to ignore the dignified,</text><text start="596.21" dur="7.17">if premature, touch of grey in the temples.
What treacherous barber should agree to such</text><text start="603.38" dur="8.32">depravity? Who takes mere money, or even soulless
joy, in depriving our small community of such</text><text start="611.7" dur="7.86">a simple, but important, act as luridly admiring
Carlos&amp;#39; stunning coif?</text><text start="619.56" dur="9.78">Reports from two intrepid sources are that it was Telly the Barber.
Telly, who likes sports, and has posters of</text><text start="629.35" dur="9.16">combs. Telly the Barber seems to be the one
who betrayed our community. Telly the Barber.</text><text start="638.51" dur="6.63">It is Telly the Barber at the corner of southwest
5th Street and Old Musk Road with the red</text><text start="645.14" dur="6.66">and white spinning pole and the sign that
says, &amp;quot;Telly&amp;#39;s.&amp;quot; Telly is about five foot</text><text start="651.8" dur="9.22">nine with a small mustache and a thick potbelly.
He talks with an accent, and sneers. Telly</text><text start="661.02" dur="9.06">the Barber cut Carlos&amp;#39; beautiful hair. According
to reports. Telly.</text><text start="674.58" dur="5">Now, while I gather myself, let&amp;#39;s have a look at traffic.</text><text start="679.58" dur="10.46">Oh. Wow! Well,
that looks pretty good. Yup. Yeeeess. Okay,</text><text start="690.04" dur="9.22">not too bad there either I see. Oh! That gentleman
needs to slow it down! It is not a race my</text><text start="699.27" dur="8.93">friend! Not a literal one, anyway. That has
been traffic. And now for an editorial.</text><text start="708.2" dur="6.52">I don&amp;#39;t ask favors much, dear listeners, that
you know, but I&amp;#39;m asking all of you right</text><text start="714.73" dur="6.46">now to conduct a letter writing campaign to
station management, which was not pleased</text><text start="721.19" dur="6.28">with my discussion of their physical attributes
and behavior, and is now threatening to shut</text><text start="727.47" dur="10.59">down my show-- or possibly, my life. For good.
Their wording was...kind of ambiguous. Obviously</text><text start="738.06" dur="5.18">we will not be able to deliver the letters
directly to the management per se, as no one</text><text start="743.24" dur="6.029">has ever opened their door, but we can shout
the content of the letters outside their office</text><text start="749.269" dur="5.981">and, we presume, given an anatomy that includes
ears, they will be able to hear what you have</text><text start="755.25" dur="7.31">to say. So if you like this show, and you
want to hear more of it, then we need to hear</text><text start="762.56" dur="7.98">from you. Make your voice heard to whatever
it is that lies in wait behind that darkened</text><text start="770.54" dur="12.86">office door. Oh! Um, I&amp;#39;m sorry dear listeners--
we&amp;#39;ll be back after this word from our sponsors.</text><text start="783.4" dur="5.78">This segment has been brought to us by Big
Rico&amp;#39;s Pizza. Listeners, we are proud to have</text><text start="789.18" dur="5.63">Big Rico&amp;#39;s as a sponsor of our show. You will
not find a better pizza joint in all of Night</text><text start="794.81" dur="6.49">Vale than Big Rico&amp;#39;s. Just the other night,
I stopped by Big Rico&amp;#39;s. I was in the mood</text><text start="801.3" dur="5.539">for a delicious pizza slice, and since Big
Rico&amp;#39;s is the only pizza place in Night Vale</text><text start="806.839" dur="5.12">that has not burned to the ground in an unsolved
arson case, and did I mention, is also the</text><text start="811.959" dur="6.9">best pizza in town, I ordered a single Rico&amp;#39;s
slice with two authentic toppings. And boy,</text><text start="818.86" dur="7.34">was I satisfied. The flavor was scrumptious.
The taste was also scrumptious. And it was</text><text start="826.2" dur="6.36">warm, the pizza slice! I have been told that
even the hooded figures eat there; the wait</text><text start="832.56" dur="5.83">staff look like they avert their hollow gazes
quite a bit. Even the city council offers</text><text start="838.39" dur="6.259">its ringing endorsement of Big Rico&amp;#39;s. All
Night Vale citizens are mandated to eat at</text><text start="844.649" dur="8.31">Big Rico&amp;#39;s once a week. It is a misdemeanor
not to. Big Rico&amp;#39;s Pizza. No one does a slice</text><text start="852.959" dur="3.46">like Big Rico, folks! No one.</text><text start="858.5" dur="7.84">And now, sweet, sweet listeners... The weather.</text><text start="866.34" dur="215.9">(Bill and Annie, Chuck Brodsky)</text><text start="1082.24" dur="6.99">Hello, radio audience.
I come to you live from under my desk, where</text><text start="1089.23" dur="6.86">I have dragged my microphone, and am currently
hiding in the fetal position. Did you write</text><text start="1096.09" dur="8.06">letters? Maybe you should not do this anymore.
Station management has opened its door for</text><text start="1104.15" dur="7.43">the first time in my memory, and is now roaming
the building. I don&amp;#39;t know exactly what management</text><text start="1111.58" dur="4.37">looks like, as that is when I took cover under
my desk, and I can only hope that they are</text><text start="1115.95" dur="7.28">not listening to what&amp;#39;s going out right now
or else I may have sealed my fate. I can hear</text><text start="1123.23" dur="8.35">only a kind of clicking footstep, and a faint
hissing sound like releasing steam. An intern</text><text start="1131.58" dur="5.94">went to see what management wanted and has
not returned. If you are related to Jerry</text><text start="1137.52" dur="5.649">Hartman, afternoon board operator at Night
Vale Community Radio, I am sorry to inform</text><text start="1143.169" dur="6.751">you that he is probably dead or at least corporally
absorbed into management permanently.</text><text start="1149.92" dur="5.82">Jerry and Chad the interns will both be missed,
but we will surely see them in the Thanksgiving</text><text start="1155.75" dur="5.96">Day Dead Citizens Impersonation Contest, which
this year will be in the employee lounge under</text><text start="1161.71" dur="9.11">the Night Vale Mall from 11am to 9:45pm. There
will be a cash bar and two Twister boards.</text><text start="1172.56" dur="5.72">I am going to see if I can make a break for
the door. If you don&amp;#39;t hear from me again,</text><text start="1178.28" dur="7.14">it has truly been a pleasure. Good night,
Night Vale. And goodbye!</text><text start="1190.06" dur="4.84">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books.
It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey Cranor,</text><text start="1194.929" dur="5.211">and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice of
Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1200.14" dur="5.33">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1205.47" dur="5.99">weather was &amp;quot;Bill &amp;amp; Annie&amp;quot; by Chuck Brodsky.
Find out more at chuckbrodsky.com. Check out</text><text start="1211.46" dur="4.709">commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1216.169" dur="5.98">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup. Today&amp;#39;s proverb:</text><text start="1222.149" dur="4.56">There&amp;#39;s a special place in Hell. It&amp;#39;s really
hip. Very exclusive.</text></transcript>