<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="7.149">Close your eyes. Let my words wash over you.
You are safe now. </text><text start="7.96" dur="2.26">Welcome to Night Vale. </text><text start="34.92" dur="6.02">Local historians are protesting the removal of the
Shape in Grove Park that No One Acknowledges</text><text start="40.95" dur="5.25">or Speaks About. While their protest has been
hampered by the fact that none of them will</text><text start="46.2" dur="5.82">acknowledge or speak about it, they did--
through a system of gestures and grimaces--</text><text start="52.02" dur="6.08">convey the message that, whatever the Shape
is, and whatever its effects on nearby neighborhoods,</text><text start="58.1" dur="8.04">it is a Night Vale landmark and should be
protected. The Shape itself offered no comment--</text><text start="66.14" dur="6.48">only a low moaning and gelatinous quiver.
The City Council would not provide any reason</text><text start="72.62" dur="6.5">for the removal, but did say that any work
in Grove Park was making way for a new swing</text><text start="79.12" dur="8.82">set, picnic area, and bloodstone circle, which we all can agree are good contributions to the community.</text><text start="91.28" dur="4.24">The Night Vale Green Market
Co-Op announced today that, after fifteen</text><text start="95.53" dur="6.6">years, they will begin selling fruits and
vegetables. Green Market Board President Tristan</text><text start="102.13" dur="7.25">Cortez said that recent customer surveys indicated
that shoppers have grown tired of empty pickup</text><text start="109.38" dur="5.82">trucks and vacant tents lining the City Hall
parking lot every Sunday morning in the summer</text><text start="115.2" dur="7.56">and fall. Cortez said that research indicates
that consumers are more likely to buy products</text><text start="122.76" dur="6.109">if they are available and for sale, and that
Green Market and Grocery shoppers tend to</text><text start="128.869" dur="6.831">purchase food items. Cortez said that the
decision to sell food at the Green Market</text><text start="135.7" dur="6.53">was a controversial one, as many board members
and Co-Op shareholders feel fruit and vegetable</text><text start="142.23" dur="7.149">sales will interfere with their ongoing secretive
domestic espionage operations. When reached</text><text start="149.379" dur="6.33">for comment, our source within the Secret
Police only breathed heavily into the phone</text><text start="155.709" dur="5.4">while tapping an as-yet uncracked code into the receiver.</text><text start="166.1" dur="9.12">Michael Sandero, starting quarterback for the Night Vale Scorpions, has reportedly grown a second head.</text><text start="175.22" dur="6.92">It is not currently known whether this is a result of the previously reported lightning strike, or just another</text><text start="182.15" dur="7.169">odd coincidence in the kid&amp;#39;s odd life. People
in the know say that the new head is better</text><text start="189.319" dur="6.021">looking and smarter than the first one, and
even Michael&amp;#39;s mother has issued a statement</text><text start="195.34" dur="5.489">indicating that she likes it much better than
her son and that she will be changing the</text><text start="200.829" dur="7">rankings on the public &amp;quot;Which of My Children
I Like Best&amp;quot; board outside her house.</text><text start="207.829" dur="6.16">Sander could not be reached for comment. Probably. We didn&amp;#39;t try.</text><text start="217.7" dur="9.259">Friends, listeners; there&amp;#39;s a real tarantula problem here in Night Vale.
Many residents have called in to report that</text><text start="226.959" dur="8.32">illiteracy, unwanted pregnancy, and violent
crime are on the rise in the tarantula communities.</text><text start="235.28" dur="4.72">Animal control is addressing these concerns
through after-school programs called &amp;quot;Teach</text><text start="240.01" dur="6.559">a Spider to Read-- Stop the Madness.&amp;quot; Those
interesting in volunteering should stand in</text><text start="246.569" dur="9.44">their bathtubs and weep until it is all gone.
Nothing left. You can let go now. Let go.</text><text start="256.009" dur="2.78">Shhhhh. Let go.</text><text start="260.46" dur="1.88">And now a message from our sponsor. </text><text start="264.1" dur="11.96">Tired of your home? Sick of comfort? Come to the Hole in the Vacant Lot out back
of the Ralph&amp;#39;s and huddle with Us.</text><text start="276.06" dur="8.2">Who are we? Good question. Come to the Hole in the Vacant Lot out back of the Ralph&amp;#39;s and huddle</text><text start="284.27" dur="8.609">with Us. Why do we want you to come? Why did
we spend money for this airtime? We understand</text><text start="292.879" dur="13.28">you are confused. But: Hole, Vacant Lot, Ralph&amp;#39;s,
huddle, Us. For the low, low price. Act today.</text><text start="306.16" dur="9.38">Or tomorrow. Not Wednesday. Wednesday is no
good for Us. Anyway, we&amp;#39;re almost out of airtime,</text><text start="315.54" dur="8.88">so just come on down to the Hole in the Vacant Lot out back of the Ralph&amp;#39;s and huddle with Us. Or else.</text><text start="328.5" dur="4.879">Back to our regularly scheduled
programming. Ladies and gentlemen, the rumor</text><text start="333.379" dur="7.64">mill is abuzz. We&amp;#39;ve had a celebrity sighting
in our little burgh! Old Woman Josie and one</text><text start="341.03" dur="7.359">of her angel friends reportedly saw Rita Hayworth
getting gas at the Fuel &amp;#39;n Go over by the</text><text start="348.389" dur="6.811">bowling alley. Rita Hayworth, ladies and gentlemen!
Right here in Night Vale. Can you believe it?</text><text start="355.2" dur="5.779">Old Woman Josie said Rita was looking
a bit older, moderately obese, and considerably</text><text start="360.979" dur="7.14">more Hispanic, but the angel assured her it
was indeed Rita. He is an angel after all...</text><text start="368.12" dur="7.92">he would know, right? Wow! Rita Hayworth!
Right here in Night Vale! Just imagine!</text><text start="377.5" dur="7.12">Update on the Shape Formerly in Grove Park that No One Acknowledges or Speaks About:</text><text start="384.62" dur="6.36">it seems the City Council, in their superhuman mercy
and all-seeing glory, have chosen to move the</text><text start="390.99" dur="5.47">Shape directly in front of our own radio station,
where it is continuing to be what can only</text><text start="396.46" dur="6.229">be described as... indescribable. The Shape
was not available for comment as I could find</text><text start="402.689" dur="6.361">no one willing to speak to it... or even meet
my eye when I mentioned it. It has occurred</text><text start="409.05" dur="6.88">to me that I may be the only one able to see
it. Now that I think about it, I have also</text><text start="415.93" dur="4.709">never bothered to actually check whether this
mic is attached to any sort of recording or</text><text start="420.639" dur="8.6">broadcasting device. And it is possible that
I am alone in an empty universe, speaking</text><text start="429.389" dur="7.03">to no one, unaware that the world is held
aloft merely by my delusions and my smooth,</text><text start="436.419" dur="8.8">sonorous voice. More on this story as it develops,
I say, possibly only to myself.</text><text start="451.54" dur="7.16">The Night Vale Community Theater is holding auditions
for its fall show &amp;quot;Once On This Island.&amp;quot; Interested</text><text start="458.729" dur="5.24">thespians should bring a head shot and resume
to the Recreation Center auditorium on Thursday</text><text start="463.969" dur="7.9">night. All auditionees must perform a one-minute
monologue and sing one song. Bring sheet music</text><text start="471.87" dur="6.229">if you would like piano accompaniment. Auditionees
will also be required to do a cold reading,</text><text start="478.099" dur="5.951">and give blood and stool samples along with
mandatory radiation testing following the</text><text start="484.05" dur="7.679">auditions. Do not sing anything from South
Pacific. People of color are urged to audition,</text><text start="491.729" dur="8.071">as Night Vale Community Theater is an equal-opportunity
employer. Also, actors with long-range sniper</text><text start="499.8" dur="6.199">training, FORTRAN computer programming, and
top-notch wilderness survival skills are a</text><text start="505.999" dur="8.04">plus. Final casting will be announced in secret
via dirigible. No one can ever know.</text><text start="516.6" dur="6.6">Update on the Green Market situation from earlier in our broadcast. Everything is exactly the</text><text start="523.21" dur="5.18">same as when we last reported on it. There
is no new information.</text><text start="529.6" dur="4.32">Listeners, do you ever think about the moon?</text><text start="533.92" dur="5.42">I was sitting outside last night looking at the moon and I thought,</text><text start="539.34" dur="7.28">does anyone actually know what that thing
is? Have there been any studies on this? I</text><text start="546.62" dur="7.82">went to ask Carlos, but he hasn&amp;#39;t been seen
much since that treacherous Telly&amp;#39;s vile haircut.</text><text start="554.44" dur="8.12">The moon&amp;#39;s weird though, right? It&amp;#39;s there,
and there, and then suddenly it&amp;#39;s not. And</text><text start="562.57" dur="8.13">it seems to be pretty far up. It is watching
us? If not, what is it watching instead? Is</text><text start="570.7" dur="5.99">there something more interesting than us?
Hey, watch us moon! We may not always be the</text><text start="576.69" dur="8.48">best show in the universe, but we try. This
has been today&amp;#39;s Children&amp;#39;s Fun Fact Science Corner.</text><text start="596.04" dur="4.38">Speaking of which, the Night Vale
School District has announced some changes</text><text start="600.42" dur="7.26">to the elementary school curriculum. They
are as follows: In response to parent feedback,</text><text start="607.68" dur="5.98">history class will focus more heavily on textbook
readings and traditional exams, rather than</text><text start="613.66" dur="7.06">live ammo drills. Geology is adding a new
type of rock on the grounds that it&amp;#39;s been</text><text start="620.72" dur="7.12">a while since anyone has done that. The new
type of rock is &amp;quot;vimbee,&amp;quot; and it is categorized</text><text start="627.84" dur="6.78">by its pale blue color, and the fact that
it is completely edible. Points will be awarded</text><text start="634.62" dur="4.62">to the first student to discover a real-world
example of it.</text><text start="639.24" dur="7.24">Math and English are switching names. Their curriculum will stay exactly
the same.</text><text start="647.6" dur="8.46">Astronomy will now be conducting stargazing sessions only with blindfolds on
every participant, in order to protect them</text><text start="656.06" dur="7">from the existential terror of the void. Also,
Pluto has been declared imaginary.</text><text start="664.74" dur="6.82">All classrooms will be equipped with at least one teacher
physically present for the entire instruction</text><text start="671.57" dur="7">period. Astral projection will no longer be
used in any classroom situation.</text><text start="678.57" dur="7.7">Finally, in addition to the current foreign language offerings of Spanish, French, and Modified</text><text start="686.27" dur="11.94">Sumerian, schools will now be offering Double Spanish, Weird Spanish, Coptic Spanish, Russian, and Unmodified Sumerian. </text><text start="700.9" dur="4">And now a continuation of our previous investigation into whether</text><text start="704.9" dur="5.61">I am literally the only person in the world,
speaking to myself in a fit of madness caused</text><text start="710.51" dur="4.52">by my inability to admit the tragedy of my
own existence.</text><text start="716.3" dur="6.52">Leland, our newest intern, recently brought me a cup of coffee. He is no longer in my field of vision, but I do</text><text start="722.83" dur="5.29">still have the cup of coffee, which is well
made and is given me the needed pick-me-up</text><text start="728.12" dur="7.86">to continue considering this terrifying possibility.
Is it possible that I only imagined Leland,</text><text start="735.98" dur="6.68">and forgot making myself this cup of coffee?
But then, who would have grown this coffee?</text><text start="742.66" dur="7.5">Where was this cup procured from? Oh, Leland&amp;#39;s
back in the room. He&amp;#39;s waving at me-- hello,</text><text start="750.16" dur="7.44">Leland-- and he&amp;#39;s saying... wait, what was
that, Leland? I see. He&amp;#39;s saying that the</text><text start="757.6" dur="6.04">Shape has turned a molten red and is causing
small whirlwinds in front of our radio station</text><text start="763.64" dur="5.69">doors. There is apparently a sound of a great
many voices chanting as though it were an</text><text start="769.33" dur="5.42">army giving out a battle cry before raining
down destruction on our arid little hamlet.</text><text start="775.72" dur="6.84">Oh? He has stopped shouting, and is now writing
furiously on a piece of paper. I have to say,</text><text start="782.56" dur="4.78">Leland&amp;#39;s existence, as well as his finally
speaking about the Shape that No One Else</text><text start="787.35" dur="5.88">Would Speak About, has reassured me greatly
about my lonely and solipsistic vigil here</text><text start="793.23" dur="9.39">at this microphone. He is handing me the note--
thank you, Leland-- lemme see here... ah.</text><text start="802.62" dur="4.71">It says that the City Council believes the
reason for the violent reaction of the Shape</text><text start="807.33" dur="6.54">Formerly in Grove Park that No One Acknowledges
or Speaks About is because I have been acknowledging</text><text start="813.87" dur="7.33">and speaking about it, which has made it angry.
They urge me to stop speaking of it, and never</text><text start="821.2" dur="4.64">do it again, and in exchange they&amp;#39;ll move
it somewhere else so we can get our front</text><text start="825.84" dur="7.76">loading zone back. After brief consideration...
I have decided to accept the Council&amp;#39;s offer,</text><text start="833.6" dur="5.48">because they are trustworthy leaders looking
out for our better future, and also because</text><text start="839.08" dur="7">Leland just got vaporized by a strange red
light emanating from the station entrance.</text><text start="846.8" dur="5.82">To the family of Leland, we thank you for
his service to the cause of community radio,</text><text start="852.62" dur="7.84">and join you in mourning his loss. And, without
further ado, nor ever again mentioning anything</text><text start="860.46" dur="3.54">we shouldn&amp;#39;t, let&amp;#39;s go to the weather.</text><text start="864" dur="222.62">[&amp;quot;Jerusalem&amp;quot; by Dan Bern]</text><text start="1086.62" dur="6">Hello listeners. In breaking news, the sky. The</text><text start="1092.63" dur="10.73">earth. Life. Existence as an unchanging plane
with horizons of birth and death in the faint</text><text start="1103.36" dur="9.2">distance. We have nothing to speak about.
There never was. Words are an unnecessary</text><text start="1112.57" dur="9.96">trouble. Expression is time wasting away.
Any communication is just a yelp in the darkness.</text><text start="1122.53" dur="11.55">Ladies, gentlemen, listeners, you. I am speaking
now but I am saying nothing. I am just making</text><text start="1134.08" dur="7.06">noises and, as it happens, they are organized
in words and you should not draw meaning from this. </text><text start="1143.86" dur="8.26">The service for Leland will be lovely.
We will throw flowers and weep. He will be</text><text start="1152.12" dur="6.29">buried in the break room as is the custom.
His family will come and moon about the coffee</text><text start="1158.41" dur="8.87">as though we have answers. We do not have
answers. I am not certain that we even have questions.</text><text start="1168.36" dur="3.42">I have chosen to not be certain
of anything at all.</text><text start="1173.64" dur="8.98">This is Cecil, generally, speaking to you, metaphorically, for Night
Vale Community Radio. And I would like to</text><text start="1182.63" dur="9.97">say in the most nebulous terms possible, and with no real world implications or insinuations of objective meaning:</text><text start="1192.6" dur="3.42">Goodnight, listeners. Goodnight.</text><text start="1204.24" dur="7.54">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books. It is written by Joseph
Fink and Jeffrey Cranor, and produced by Joseph</text><text start="1211.78" dur="6.4">Fink. The voice of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin.
Original music by Disparition. All of it can</text><text start="1218.18" dur="5.92">be downloaded for free at disparition.info.
This episode&amp;#39;s weather was &amp;quot;Jerusalem&amp;quot; by</text><text start="1224.1" dur="7.14">Dan Bern. Find out more at danbern.com. Check
out commonplacebooks.com for more information</text><text start="1231.25" dur="5.559">on this show, as well as our books on the
unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and</text><text start="1236.809" dur="3.26">what it means to be a grownup. Today&amp;#39;s proverb:</text><text start="1240.069" dur="4.04">A million dollars isn&amp;#39;t cool. You know what&amp;#39;s cool? A basilisk.</text></transcript>