<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="3.52">Rabbits are not what they seem to be.</text><text start="4.18" dur="2.52">Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="30.82" dur="7.66">We&amp;#39;ve had some power outages reported throughout Night Vale in the last
couple of hours. If you&amp;#39;re experiencing one...</text><text start="38.48" dur="5.62">well then you can&amp;#39;t hear me, can you? The
Night Vale Municipal Utility Department said</text><text start="44.11" dur="5.32">that they are still working to determine the
cause of the outages, which are roving back</text><text start="49.43" dur="8.05">and forth across town in a continuous motion,
like a great pacing beast. Those whose neighborhoods</text><text start="57.48" dur="5.78">have been hit by the outages reported the
shriek of hawks overhead, and that when the</text><text start="63.26" dur="5.669">lights came back on, they felt that perhaps
they were different people-- their memories</text><text start="68.929" dur="5.741">and identities were the same as always, but
suddenly felt like costumes that didn&amp;#39;t fit</text><text start="74.67" dur="6.219">exactly. As though it all were actually brand
new to them. As though they had been switched</text><text start="80.889" dur="7.031">out with someone who was exactly like them.
As though all that was familiar would ever</text><text start="87.92" dur="7.239">after be strange. Keep some flashlights with
spare batteries and a childhood photo album</text><text start="95.159" dur="2.8">by you tonight, just in case. </text><text start="99.48" dur="4.999">The revitalization
of the Old Town Drawbridge experienced another</text><text start="104.479" dur="5.941">setback this week, as engineers determined
that the furniture upholstery used to construct</text><text start="110.42" dur="7.36">the bridge towers soaks up water and creates
an unstable foundation. This week&amp;#39;s collapse</text><text start="117.789" dur="5.54">was the third in as many months. Construction
crews have tried building the bridge tower</text><text start="123.329" dur="9.72">base supports from corrugated cardboard, non-dairy
creamer, and ceramic bowls. Nothing has worked.</text><text start="133.049" dur="6.111">Engineers are asking for help in determining
how proper bridge towers are made. If you</text><text start="139.17" dur="5">have any tips, please write them on notebook
paper and mail them to</text><text start="144.17" dur="5.45">Bridge Magic, LLC PO Box 616</text><text start="149.62" dur="6.38">Do not use cursive or long words.
Clearly labeled drawings are preferred.</text><text start="157.54" dur="8.12">Ladies and gentlemen, it&amp;#39;s that time of year again.
Time for our annual pledge drive. Sorry to</text><text start="165.66" dur="7.2">have to do this, but, you know, Night Vale
has a lot of community-supported radio, and</text><text start="172.87" dur="6.37">the thing about community-supported radio...
it&amp;#39;s supported by listeners like you. As well</text><text start="179.24" dur="6.01">as Guatemala and some teamsters, who are,
sometimes, just too generous. Any amount you</text><text start="185.25" dur="7.3">can give will help us continue our community
programming. A dollar, or two, or even plasma.</text><text start="192.55" dur="7.81">Take WZZZ, our local numbers station, broadcasting
from that strange and tall antenna built out</text><text start="200.36" dur="6.78">back of the Abandoned Gas Station on Oxford
Street. Did you know that it broadcasts a</text><text start="207.14" dur="7.54">monotone female voice reading out seemingly
random numbers interspersed with chimes twenty</text><text start="214.68" dur="6.63">four hours a day, seven days a week? As you
can imagine, that kind of work doesn&amp;#39;t bring</text><text start="221.31" dur="7.74">in a lot of money-- unless it does. To be
honest, here at Night Vale Radio we don&amp;#39;t</text><text start="229.05" dur="6.73">know exactly what that station is for, or
what master it is serving. But I do know that</text><text start="235.78" dur="5.17">it is a vital part of this community, and
we should pitch in to help it. We welcome</text><text start="240.95" dur="8.64">your support. Give us a call! We don&amp;#39;t have
a number; just whisper, &amp;quot;Forsaken Algonquinia&amp;quot;</text><text start="249.59" dur="6.71">into your phone receiver, and Angels, or Facebook,
or something, will deliver us an appropriate</text><text start="256.31" dur="2.38">contribution from your bank account.</text><text start="259.88" dur="2.8">More
on the Drawbridge debacle.</text><text start="262.68" dur="8.18">It was turmoil in city headquarters this morning. Following
this latest in a long line of municipal failures,</text><text start="270.87" dur="5.88">the city council has come under fire from
concerned citizens for wasting taxpayer money</text><text start="276.75" dur="6.82">on inefficient services that go over budget
and over schedule. One critic, who wished</text><text start="283.57" dur="6.03">to remain anonymous, said, &amp;quot;We don&amp;#39;t even
have a river or bay in Night Vale. There would</text><text start="289.6" dur="7.1">never be a boat to necessitate a drawbridge!&amp;quot;
He continued to... You know what? Forget it.</text><text start="296.7" dur="5.26">I can tell you right now that that was Steve
Carlsberg who said that, and he is such a</text><text start="301.96" dur="6.5">spoilsport, that Steve! Have you ever noticed
how he never replaces his hubcaps? It&amp;#39;s laziness,</text><text start="308.46" dur="6.06">pure and simple. Laziness. I just can&amp;#39;t let
him ruin our town by denying Night Vale a</text><text start="314.52" dur="3.44">drawbridge when he can&amp;#39;t even care for a tan
Corolla!</text><text start="319.82" dur="7.88">The Night Vale Daily Journal has  announced that, due to spiraling printing
costs, they will be replacing the print edition</text><text start="327.71" dur="8.33">of the paper with a special new Imagination
Edition. Editor Leanne Hart explains, &amp;quot;Instead</text><text start="336.04" dur="5.5">of confining our customers to the outdated
modes of ink on paper, we are allowing them</text><text start="341.54" dur="6.2">to choose the news that interests them by
imagining whatever news they want. This will</text><text start="347.74" dur="6.84">not only save costs, but allow customers to
experience the news as a full color, full</text><text start="354.58" dur="8.4">motion experience taking place in a mental
world that is tailored to their needs.&amp;quot; Subscription</text><text start="362.99" dur="7.52">to this edition will be compulsory and automatic,
and will cost a mere $60 a month.</text><text start="375.8" dur="8.339">This Friday, at Night Vale High&amp;#39;s Memorial Stadium, it&amp;#39;s
the annual softball showdown between the Night</text><text start="384.139" dur="6.131">Vale Fire Department and the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret
Police. Proceeds from the game will go to</text><text start="390.27" dur="6.41">support development of nuclear weaponry for
a strongly religious Indonesian militia that</text><text start="396.68" dur="6.92">is looking to overthrow their heretical government,
as well as to the Make-A-Wish Foundation.</text><text start="403.6" dur="7">So, even if you don&amp;#39;t like softball, come
on out and support a couple of great causes.</text><text start="410.6" dur="7.26">Last year&amp;#39;s game ended in a rout, as the Secret
Police hit three home runs in the eighth and</text><text start="417.87" dur="7.43">ninth innings. The firefighters claimed that
there was some foul play involved (pun intended,</text><text start="425.3" dur="6.35">dear listeners), as their entire bullpen was
assassinated in the middle innings with blow</text><text start="431.65" dur="8.71">darts. Those murders remain unsolved and completely
uninvestigated. Our hearts go out to the families</text><text start="440.36" dur="8.82">of the deceased relief pitchers. Rest in peace.
It should be a fun one! Expect a real revenge-minded</text><text start="449.18" dur="8.98">fire department to take the field on Friday.
Tickets are only $10, or $5 if you bring enriched</text><text start="458.169" dur="7.09">yellowcake uranium. Black helicopters will
be mind-scanning the town on game day, hunting</text><text start="465.259" dur="8.74">down those who do not attend. The first 500
fans receive surgically applied working gills.</text><text start="475.98" dur="8.7">Notice: there is no digital, static-y hum
coming from the Dog Park, Mayor Pamela Winchell</text><text start="484.69" dur="7.46">announced today. The mayor stressed repeatedly
in her 90 second impromptu press conference</text><text start="492.15" dur="7.299">that there is no unbearable, soul-tearing
sound that rips at the sinews of your very</text><text start="499.449" dur="7.82">being coming from the Dog Park. Mayor Winchell
continued with a plea for all Night Vale residents</text><text start="507.27" dur="6.91">to understand that there could not possibly
be a deeply coded message emanating from a</text><text start="514.18" dur="6.96">small, fenced-in patch of municipal grass
and dirt. Citizens are not even supposed to</text><text start="521.14" dur="6.54">be consciously aware of the Dog Park, so they
could not possibly be receiving a menacing</text><text start="527.68" dur="7.2">and unearthly voice instructing listeners
to bring precious metals and toddlers to the</text><text start="534.88" dur="10.26">Dog Park. &amp;quot;Dog Park,&amp;quot; she repeated. &amp;quot;That
could never, ever be real,&amp;quot; the mayor shouted,</text><text start="545.14" dur="6.64">pounding the podium with her bleeding fists.
There were no follow-up questions.</text><text start="554.4" dur="3.98">And now, a word from our sponsors!</text><text start="559.54" dur="14.18">[Moaning sound]</text><text start="574.7" dur="4.34">And now, traffic. There&amp;#39;s a stalled car on</text><text start="579.05" dur="6.93">the northbound on-ramp to the Eastern Expressway
just south of Route 800. Commuters should</text><text start="585.98" dur="7.6">have little delays, as Highway Patrol is fiercely
denying this report. In fact, police representatives</text><text start="593.58" dur="6.85">have just issued a statement claiming that
there are no cars anywhere, and, &amp;quot;What are</text><text start="600.43" dur="6.77">you doing, talking about them, talking silly
lies, you silly people? There are no cars!</text><text start="607.2" dur="7.72">What is this fiction? Oh, please, do you seriously
believe for a second? Wait. Wait! You thought</text><text start="614.92" dur="7.2">that cars were real?&amp;quot; The Highway Patrol continued,
&amp;quot;Oh, that is rich.&amp;quot;</text><text start="623.56" dur="2.32">All other roads seem clear.</text><text start="625.88" dur="4.8">Expect delays, of course, at the drawbridge
construction site, because it is years away</text><text start="630.72" dur="2.56">from being competently finished.</text><text start="634.46" dur="5.16">Here are
this week&amp;#39;s horoscopes. Virgo: Go see a movie</text><text start="639.62" dur="7.22">today. It&amp;#39;s a great escape! Especially from
all this pollution and dangerous UV radiation.</text><text start="647.05" dur="8.68">Say, is that mole new? Libra: Your dreams
will be filled with prophetic visions. Write</text><text start="655.73" dur="7.94">them down. Hopefully, there are some lottery
numbers or sports scores in there. Scorpio:</text><text start="663.67" dur="10.72">Curse you! Curse your family! Curse your children!
And your children&amp;#39;s children! Vile, vile Scorpio.</text><text start="675.84" dur="7.56">Sagittarius: Eat well today! You&amp;#39;ve earned
it. And by it, I mean massive food allergies.</text><text start="683.4" dur="6.14">And by earned, I mean acquired. I should proof
this stuff before I read it out loud. Let&amp;#39;s</text><text start="689.55" dur="10.5">try that again. You&amp;#39;ve acquired massive food
allergies. Yes, much cleaner. Eat well! Capricorn:</text><text start="700.05" dur="6.64">Those were not contact lenses you put in this
morning. Best not think about this again.</text><text start="707.88" dur="8.82">Aquarius: The white ball will be under the
middle shell. Trust the stars. Invest all</text><text start="716.709" dur="3.76">your money in this lucrative street game.</text><text start="721.46" dur="3.42">Pisces: You&amp;#39;ve won a brand new car!</text><text start="726.02" dur="12.06">Aries: You will feel a haunting sadness about times gone by. Today&amp;#39;s smell is wheatgrass and toast.</text><text start="738.08" dur="9.08">Taurus: Today is your annual Crime Day. All
Tauruses are exempt from laws today.</text><text start="748.54" dur="7.66">Gemini: You will meet someone today who will have
no effect on your life, and who you will immediately</text><text start="756.2" dur="4.4">forget. Retain hope for a possible future.</text><text start="762.24" dur="4.86">Cancer: I&amp;#39;ve gotta pay my phone bill, and also get some more milk.</text><text start="768.44" dur="6.12">That wasn&amp;#39;t me talking;
that is what the stars say today. Interpret it as you will.</text><text start="775.64" dur="7.3">Leo: It&amp;#39;s better that I don&amp;#39;t
read this aloud. Better that you not know.</text><text start="784.019" dur="6.5">Tell your family you love them. That has been
this week&amp;#39;s horoscopes.</text><text start="791.74" dur="5">Good news for radio-controlled airplane hobbyists! </text><text start="796.74" dur="6.68">Those unidentifiable black
metallic trees that suddenly appeared by the</text><text start="803.42" dur="8.78">library back in June and caused all airborne
objects above thirty feet to catch fire? Well,</text><text start="812.2" dur="6.64">they&amp;#39;ve finally been cleared away, as a new
strip mall and parking lot are being developed.</text><text start="819.8" dur="6.849">The Night Vale Airport, local birdwatchers,
and that nice epileptic couple who run the</text><text start="826.649" dur="8.69">Emergency Services helicopter are just pleased
as pleased can be about the news. Several</text><text start="835.339" dur="7.44">petitions, however, have cropped up from neighborhood
improvement organizations. Juanita Jefferson,</text><text start="842.78" dur="5.1">head of one such organization, Night Vale
Or Nothing, said,</text><text start="848.62" dur="5.82">&amp;quot;Treees! They are us!&amp;quot;</text><text start="855.74" dur="5.48">Jefferson then paused for several minutes without blinking
and whispered again, </text><text start="861.84" dur="7.24">&amp;quot;Treeeees,&amp;quot; before collapsing into tears and loud moaning.</text><text start="870.3" dur="11.26">Jefferson was then taken by helicopter to Night Vale General Hospital, where she is reportedly in stable
condition. This morning, Jefferson&amp;#39;s lawyer</text><text start="881.56" dur="7.64">issued a statement saying: &amp;quot;My client fully
recognizes the irony of this helicopter trip,</text><text start="889.2" dur="7.2">but she stands by her earlier pronouncement,
&amp;#39;Trees, trees; they are us.&amp;#39;&amp;quot;</text><text start="897.6" dur="10.12">Meanwhile, I hear from trustworthy informants that there
will be a Pinkberry at the new strip mall. Deeelicious!</text><text start="915.82" dur="6.96">This just in on Drawbridgegate:
The City Council said that, in response to</text><text start="922.79" dur="6.22">this week&amp;#39;s collapse, they will increase the
project budget by $20 million over the next</text><text start="929.01" dur="7.42">14 years-- the new timeline for the bridge.
Money for these extra expenses will come from</text><text start="936.43" dur="14.46">school lunch programs, a 65% hotel tax, and
a $276 bridge toll, which will be discounted to $249 with E-Z Pass. </text><text start="952.44" dur="6.26">And now for a station
editorial. Large, expensive projects are not </text><text start="958.7" dur="7.84">uncommon in Night Vale. We are a patient, but resilient, little city. We have big dreams--</text><text start="966.55" dur="6.11">sometimes scary, unforgettable dreams that
repeat on the same date every year and are</text><text start="972.66" dur="7.58">shared by every person in town, but we make
those big dreams come true. Remember the Clock</text><text start="980.25" dur="8.01">Tower? It took eight years and $23 million
to build. And despite its invisibility, and</text><text start="988.26" dur="7.24">constant teleportation, it is a lovely structure
that keeps impeccable time. It&amp;#39;s a classy</text><text start="995.5" dur="7.36">signature for Night Vale&amp;#39;s growing skyline,
unlike that hideous sports arena Desert Bluffs</text><text start="1002.86" dur="8.04">built last spring. Desert Bluffs can&amp;#39;t do
anything right. That&amp;#39;s where Steve Carlsberg belongs!</text><text start="1011.56" dur="5.56"> God, what a jerk. And now, the weather!</text><text start="1017.84" dur="182.84">[&amp;quot;Aye&amp;quot; by Dio]</text><text start="1201.36" dur="9.4">Apparently, the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Police agree with me about old Steve Carlsberg, dear listeners.</text><text start="1210.76" dur="9.8">We just received a report from a reliable witness that two days ago, Steve was whisked
into the back of a windowless van, only to</text><text start="1220.57" dur="7.28">reappear earlier this morning wearing thick
head bandages and eating styrofoam shaped</text><text start="1227.85" dur="8.79">like an ice cream cone. I want to take this
moment to thank all of you out there, for</text><text start="1236.64" dur="7.58">all of the generous donations you may or may
not be aware that you just made. During this</text><text start="1244.22" dur="10.52">show, we have raised just a hair over $45,000,
which includes a $45,000 donation from a certain</text><text start="1254.74" dur="9.08">anonymous world leader. I can&amp;#39;t tell you who...
let&amp;#39;s just say, muchas gracias, El Presidente!</text><text start="1263.82" dur="8.26">Mano dura, cabeza, y corazón. Thank you again
for your involuntary support of community</text><text start="1272.08" dur="6.52">radio. We couldn&amp;#39;t do it without the support
of listeners like you, in conjunction with</text><text start="1278.61" dur="8.12">unethical contributions from nefarious organizations.
And with that, I leave you alone with your</text><text start="1286.73" dur="11.53">thoughts, folks. Stay tuned next for Zydeco:
Note By Note, a special two-hour verbal description</text><text start="1298.26" dur="7.66">of what zydeco music sounds like. Buenos noches,
Night Vale. Goodnight.</text><text start="1312.86" dur="5.88">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books. It is
written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey Cranor,</text><text start="1318.75" dur="6.19">and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice of
Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1324.94" dur="5.65">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1330.59" dur="7.76">weather was &amp;quot;Aye&amp;quot; by Dio. Find out more at
diomusic.nl. Check out commonplacebooks.com</text><text start="1338.35" dur="5.01">for more information on this show, as well
as our books on the unused story ideas of</text><text start="1343.36" dur="6.33">H.P. Lovecraft, and what it means to be a
grownup. Today&amp;#39;s proverb: Lost? Confused?</text><text start="1349.69" dur="3.44">Lacking direction? Need to find a purpose
in your life?</text></transcript>