<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="11.54">It is almost complete. It is almost complete
at last. Welcome to Night Vale. </text><text start="35.3" dur="7.699">Hello, there. As you well know, faithful listeners, it is Night Vale History Week, in which we all learn</text><text start="42.999" dur="6.08">a little bit about what made our bustling
little town what it is. Or, as the official</text><text start="49.079" dur="6.74">motto released by the City Council goes, &amp;quot;Poke
about in the black recesses of the past until</text><text start="55.819" dur="6.76">it devours our fragile present.&amp;quot; In the interest
of civic participation, Night Vale Community</text><text start="63.079" dur="6.92">Radio will be pitching in with short lessons
about some points of interest from our town&amp;#39;s history,</text><text start="70" dur="4.38">starting with 4000 B.C.</text><text start="75.56" dur="6.26">Archaeologists
believe that this is the earliest date of human settlement in Night Vale. </text><text start="82.08" dur="3.84">Little remains
of these ancient inhabitants except a few</text><text start="85.92" dur="6.89">cave paintings of their towns and their hunting
practices, and of the dark shapes that would</text><text start="92.81" dur="9.82">watch them in the distance. Inhuman, shimmering
shapes that never came closer or farther away,</text><text start="102.63" dur="6.47">but whose presence could be felt even with
eyes shut tight, huddled in fur and the company</text><text start="109.1" dur="8.08">of another human&amp;#39;s naked skin. Or so I&amp;#39;m extrapolating
from the evidence. The cave paintings</text><text start="117.18" dur="5.72">mainly resemble smudges now, after their original
discoverer attempted to power-wash them</text><text start="122.9" dur="6.9">off the wall because he, on religious grounds,
did not believe in the past.</text><text start="135.32" dur="2.36">And now the news:</text><text start="138.6" dur="7.68">The Night Vale Tourism Board asks that whoever
is telepathically assaulting the tourists:</text><text start="146.28" dur="8.66">please stop. According to the NVTB executive
director, Madeline LeFleur, there were two</text><text start="154.95" dur="7.679">separate incidents in one week of entire tour
buses suddenly shrieking in unbridled terror</text><text start="162.629" dur="6.61">and trying to blind themselves using rolled-up
&amp;quot;Visitable Night Vale&amp;quot; brochures-- all to</text><text start="169.239" dur="8.3">the utter confusion of the bus drivers. LeFleur
added, &amp;quot;We just had those brochures printed.&amp;quot;</text><text start="177.54" dur="5.92">LeFleur claims that tourism accounts for tens
of thousands of dollars annually for Night</text><text start="183.46" dur="8.34">Vale, and the town prides itself on hospitality.
She said that if good-hearted families travel</text><text start="191.8" dur="7.46">to Night Vale only to find their subconsciouses
besieged with unforgettable revelations, horrors</text><text start="199.26" dur="9.459">buried so deep as to be completely indescribable,
revealing wholly unbearable new truths, then</text><text start="208.719" dur="6.14">we certainly can&amp;#39;t expect these people to
return... let   alone leave good Yelp ratings</text><text start="214.86" dur="8.499">for local businesses. The city is asking residents
for help in determining who, or what, is causing</text><text start="223.359" dur="6.791">these psychological infractions. The tourism
board is offering puppies as a reward</text><text start="230.15" dur="6.85">for information on this case. Or, even if you
don&amp;#39;t have information, the city asks that</text><text start="237" dur="9.38">you come get a puppy or two anyway. Seriously.
Downtown municipal offices are overrun with them.</text><text start="246.38" dur="11.78">In the trees, walls, carpentry... the
exterminators are completely stymied by this infestation. Please help.</text><text start="261.08" dur="5.94"> It has been several
weeks since anyone in Night Vale has seen the Apache Tracker--</text><text start="267.02" dur="4.7">that white guy who wears
the inaccurate and horribly offensive Indian</text><text start="271.72" dur="6.4">headdress everywhere. He has not been seen
since he began investigating the Great Screaming</text><text start="278.129" dur="7.74">heard at the post office, and the words written
in blood inside. Also the entire structure</text><text start="285.87" dur="6.639">of his house has vanished, and the lot where
it stood is now a bucolic meadow that neighborhood</text><text start="292.509" dur="8.611">kids will not ever enter for reasons even
they are unable to explain. I think I speak</text><text start="301.12" dur="5.48">for everyone in the community when I say good
riddance to that local embarrassment.</text><text start="306.6" dur="3.78">He made the whole town look ignorant and racist.</text><text start="311.14" dur="5.98">And
now, let us continue with our Night Vale History Week special feature.</text><text start="317.9" dur="7.4">The year 1745: The first
white men arrive in Night Vale, which was</text><text start="325.3" dur="6.4">not Night Vale then, but was rather just another
part of a large and featureless desert.</text><text start="332.6" dur="6">I think we can all agree, though, that even
as large and featureless as the desert was,</text><text start="338.62" dur="6.41">the part that would eventually become Desert
Bluffs was still probably awful and drab in</text><text start="345.03" dur="8.69">comparison to our part. In any case, the story
goes that a party of explorers came to the</text><text start="353.72" dur="7.199">area that would be Night Vale, looked around,
and immediately left to go find somewhere</text><text start="360.919" dur="7.68">with more water, and maybe some trees. Then
another three parties of explorers did the</text><text start="368.599" dur="9.8">same thing. Then finally, one party of explorers
all looked at each other, shrugged, and plopped</text><text start="378.409" dur="5.82">down their stuff... and thus was a proud city
born.</text><text start="391.28" dur="2.48">And now, traffic.</text><text start="395.04" dur="6.48">Crews from the Department of Public Safety will be repainting highway
lane markers this week.</text><text start="402.52" dur="8.639">The common white dashes and double yellow lane dividers will be replaced
with colorful ceramic mosaics depicting disgruntled</text><text start="411.159" dur="7">South American workers rising en masse against
an abusive capitalist hegemony. The protective</text><text start="419.2" dur="6.2">The protective steel barriers along curves in the road will
be taken down to make room for some really</text><text start="425.4" dur="7.7">lovely and provocative butcher-paper silhouettes
of slavery-era self-mutilation, reflective</text><text start="433.129" dur="7.951">of several centuries of slow genocide and
dehumanization by Western imperialists, designed</text><text start="441.08" dur="11">by contemporary art darling Kara Walker. Also,
Exits 15 to 17 along Route 800 will be closed</text><text start="452.08" dur="8.28">for the next two Saturdays because of the
biennial Lee Marvin Film Retrospective. So</text><text start="460.37" dur="6.289">please watch for working crews this weekend,
lower your speed, and don&amp;#39;t forget to tip</text><text start="466.659" dur="9.12">the DPS shift leaders. 20% of your current
mileage is standard. Lack of tipping is the</text><text start="475.78" dur="3.4">leading cause of sinkholes in the U.S.</text><text start="481" dur="6.1">The year 1824: The first meeting of the Town Elder</text><text start="487.1" dur="9.249">Council, predecessors to the City Council.
Picture them: crimson robes and soft meat</text><text start="496.349" dur="7.48">crowns (as was traditional at the time), setting
the groundwork for the splendor of today&amp;#39;s</text><text start="503.83" dur="8.079">Night Vale. A number of elements of our modern
civic process were invented in that single</text><text start="511.909" dur="8.01">three-hour meeting, including the City Council
membership (since unchanged), the lovably</text><text start="519.919" dur="7">Byzantine tax system (as well as the system
of brutal penalties for mistakes) and the</text><text start="526.93" dur="8.909">official town song, chant, and moan. All records
of this meeting were destroyed, and... according</text><text start="535.839" dur="10.54">to a note being passed to me just now, I am
to report to City Hall for reeducation effective tomorrow morning. Oh, dear.</text><text start="549.96" dur="3.86">The results of
a recent survey of Night Vale residents came</text><text start="553.82" dur="8.42">to light this week. The study found widespread
dissatisfaction with our town&amp;#39;s public library.</text><text start="562.25" dur="7.899">And, when considering the facts, it&amp;#39;s easy
to see why. The public computers for internet</text><text start="570.149" dur="8.38">use are outdated and slow. The lending period
of 14 days is not nearly long enough to read</text><text start="578.529" dur="7.22">lengthier books, given the busy schedules
of all our lives. The fatality rate is also</text><text start="585.75" dur="6.66">well above the national average for public
libraries. The library bloodstone circle does</text><text start="592.41" dur="6.58">not appear to have seen any maintenance or
cleaning in some time. There are reports of</text><text start="598.99" dur="7.07">a faceless spectre moving about the Biography
section, picking off lone browsers one by</text><text start="606.06" dur="9.38">one. And that Biography section, by the way,
is far too small and has been oddly curated--</text><text start="615.449" dur="9.611">containing 33 copies of the official biography
of Helen Hunt, and no other books. From top</text><text start="625.06" dur="6.68">to bottom, the public library is a disgrace
to our fair city and I can only hope that</text><text start="631.74" dur="6">our City Council does something about that
soon, or I may find myself hoping that the</text><text start="637.75" dur="8.26">faceless spectre puts the library to the same
mysterious, violent end as its many victims.</text><text start="647.889" dur="6.621">Night Vale High won the grudge match against
the Desert Bluffs Vultures last night. Two-headed</text><text start="654.51" dur="6.35">quarterback Michael Sandero credits the win
to help from Angels! The Angels have made</text><text start="660.86" dur="7.38">an adamant denial of any involvement whatsoever
in the game. The school district ethics committee</text><text start="668.24" dur="5.84">has announced that they will look into any
possible &amp;quot;Angelic interference&amp;quot;.</text><text start="677.4" dur="7.46">Speaking of which, Night Vale High School is adding
metal detectors, and parents and students</text><text start="684.86" dur="7.9">alike are outraged. Several parents we talked
to said that NVHS students have long been</text><text start="692.76" dur="7.819">recipients of shadow government-issued Uzis
and rifles, as well as tasers and armor-piercing</text><text start="700.579" dur="7.08">munitions. The School Board&amp;#39;s decision to
put up metal detectors, according to parents,</text><text start="707.67" dur="6.919">impinges on the clandestine operation&amp;#39;s rights
as a vast underground conspiracy of giant</text><text start="714.589" dur="8.12">megacorporations and corrupt world leaders
to bear arms via teenage paramilitary proxies.</text><text start="723.36" dur="6.349">The School Board countered that studies indicate
that weapons distract from educators&amp;#39; ability</text><text start="729.709" dur="7.76">to educate, and that students who bring firearms
to classrooms are more likely to use firearms</text><text start="737.48" dur="6.799">than students without firearms. The School
Board says that school shootings can only</text><text start="744.279" dur="7.381">get in the way of a quality education. Well...
at the risk of becoming too much a part of</text><text start="751.66" dur="6.109">this story, dear listeners, might I say that
the Night Vale School District is overstepping</text><text start="757.769" dur="7.471">its bounds by telling us whether or not our
children can be armed by undercover militants?</text><text start="765.24" dur="7.76">Should it be a school&amp;#39;s job to say, &amp;quot;No, child,
you cannot have grenades or assault rifles</text><text start="773" dur="9.12">in the classroom&amp;quot;? I think not! Beginning
November first, all students at NVHS will</text><text start="782.17" dur="8.02">enter the school through metal detectors.
Any firearms or weaponry found will be confiscated</text><text start="790.19" dur="6.1">and held in the counselor&amp;#39;s office until after
school, when the students can pick them up</text><text start="796.29" dur="8.43">again. Seriously, listeners, what&amp;#39;s next?
Removing the line &amp;quot;Praise the beams, praise,</text><text start="804.72" dur="8.789">o ye knowing beams that guide our lives, our
hearts, our souls; praise o highest to ye</text><text start="813.509" dur="4.24">all-powerful beams&amp;quot; from the Pledge of Allegiance?!</text><text start="818.88" dur="7.92">Let&amp;#39;s return to another key moment in Night Vale history. The year 1943:</text><text start="827.8" dur="6.92">As part of the
war effort, Night Vale citizens dedicated themselves to chanting.</text><text start="834.72" dur="5.16">The young, the old,
men and women alike gathered around their</text><text start="839.88" dur="7.139">bloodstones and chanted for the victory of
the United States. While some credit must</text><text start="847.019" dur="5.76">be given to the strategic planning of U.S
Command, and to the brave fighting of American</text><text start="852.779" dur="6.261">soldiers, most reputable scholars believe
that Night Vale&amp;#39;s chanting was the deciding</text><text start="859.04" dur="7.2">factor in America&amp;#39;s eventual victory over
the Axis powers. The City Council erected</text><text start="866.24" dur="7.18">a seven-story monument in Grove Park saying
so in large, neon letters... until a federal</text><text start="873.42" dur="3">lawsuit forced them to take it down.</text><text start="878.84" dur="5.6">And now,
a word from our sponsors. That word is carp.</text><text start="885.52" dur="7.56">This next installment in our exploration of
Night Vale&amp;#39;s storied past takes place in the future.</text><text start="894.3" dur="9.44">The year 2052: The scion of the Dark
Order will descend, realize he mistimed the</text><text start="903.74" dur="9.079">prophecy, and re-ascend. The Seventh Siege
of the Great Night Vale Temple will rage on.</text><text start="912.819" dur="7.661">The plague of buzzing boils will kill thousands,
and annoy thousands more, with its buzzing.</text><text start="920.48" dur="8.44">The City Council will reveal its true form
and eat half of Night Vale&amp;#39;s population. Approval</text><text start="928.92" dur="5.92">ratings for the mayor will hover in the low
40s... which will be surprising, as there</text><text start="934.85" dur="7">will have been no mayor for over thirty years.
And now, the weather!</text><text start="942.5" dur="265.26">[&amp;quot;Despite What You&amp;#39;ve Been Told&amp;quot; by Two Gallants]</text><text start="1207.76" dur="3.56">The Night Vale
Business Association announced today that</text><text start="1211.32" dur="7.16">the Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront Recreation
Area was not actually something that ever</text><text start="1218.5" dur="8.42">existed in reality, but was instead a shared
hallucination of the entire town&amp;#39;s population.</text><text start="1227.82" dur="5.78">As such, they are proud to declare that they
have never suffered any sort of disastrous</text><text start="1233.61" dur="6.36">business failure, and the reportedly massive
amounts of money lost on building waterfront</text><text start="1239.97" dur="6.99">facilities in a desert are fabrications of
our collective consciousness.</text><text start="1246.96" dur="7.24">They recommend consulting your dream interpretation manuals
to determine exactly what this &amp;quot;Night Vale</text><text start="1254.21" dur="6.94">Harbor&amp;quot; vision could mean. They also said
that if you happen to stumble on the Waterfront</text><text start="1261.15" dur="6.12">buildings out in the desert exactly where
you remembered them, and they seem completely</text><text start="1267.27" dur="7.4">real, standing as vacant and useless as the
day they were built, that&amp;#39;s because you are</text><text start="1274.7" dur="7.93">still hallucinating and should seek medical
treatment immediately. Or have a member of</text><text start="1282.63" dur="8.32">the City Council howl at you if you are of
the Olden Faith, and do not believe in modern medicine.</text><text start="1292.12" dur="5.76">For our final story in this week&amp;#39;s
featured look into the history of Night Vale,</text><text start="1297.88" dur="10.24">let&amp;#39;s look at the very recent past. Yesterday:
I had cereal for breakfast, a sandwich for</text><text start="1308.12" dur="7.88">lunch, steak for dinner. Cars were driven,
cars were not driven. The sun gave a great</text><text start="1316.01" dur="7">shout of light and then, after several hours
of thought, quietly retracted the statement.</text><text start="1323.76" dur="6.4">Old Woman Josie dug up a box in a shady corner
of her yard and carried it, cradled in her</text><text start="1330.169" dur="6.721">arms like a baby or a delicate explosive,
to another part of her yard where she buried</text><text start="1336.89" dur="7.99">it again. An unknown person did something
that no one else saw, the nature and extent</text><text start="1344.88" dur="5.75">of which is impossible to determine, and the
result of which will be lost in the chaotic</text><text start="1350.63" dur="9.81">chain of causation and consequence that is
history. But most importantly, all of us--</text><text start="1360.44" dur="8.28">all of us here in Night Vale, in America,
in the world, in the secret orbital bases--</text><text start="1368.72" dur="8.339">all of us got through another day. We passed
the time from one end of twelve to the other</text><text start="1377.06" dur="11.28">without stopping once. Well done, us! Good
job, people who experience time! Time experiencers!</text><text start="1388.35" dur="12.74">Good job! And, from this moment in history,
the one that&amp;#39;s happening right now... Goodnight.</text><text start="1410.06" dur="4.82">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace
Books. It is written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey</text><text start="1414.88" dur="5.71">Cranor, and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice
of Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1420.59" dur="5.73">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1426.32" dur="5.9">weather was &amp;quot;Despite What You&amp;#39;ve Been Told&amp;quot;
by The Two Gallants. Find out more at twogallants.com.</text><text start="1432.22" dur="3.82">Want to have your music featured in the weather
section? Want to contribute your talents to</text><text start="1436.049" dur="6.901">the show? Just want to say hi? Email us at
nightvale@commonplacebooks.com. Check out</text><text start="1442.95" dur="3.87">commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1446.82" dur="4.46">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1451.28" dur="4.84">Today&amp;#39;s proverb: It must be 3:23PM somewhere. Maybe space?</text></transcript>