<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="11.96">Silence is golden. Words are vibrations. Thoughts
are magic. Welcome to Night Vale. </text><text start="36.24" dur="7.319">Next Saturday is the big lottery drawing, listeners, right
out in front of City Hall. And your community</text><text start="43.559" dur="7.1">radio station has put together a few helpful
tips for winning. The lottery is, of course,</text><text start="50.67" dur="5.75">mandatory, but how can you get the best odds
for drawing a blank white paper, and not one</text><text start="56.42" dur="5.09">of the purple pieces that means you&amp;#39;ll be
ceremonially disemboweled and eaten by the</text><text start="61.51" dur="6.36">wolves at the Night Vale Petting Zoo and Makeshift
Carnival? I know to some of you young people,</text><text start="67.87" dur="6.46">this lottery seems like a barbarous, outdated
tradition. But if not for a municipally-planned</text><text start="74.33" dur="6.92">citizen sacrifice each quarter, how else would
we find satisfactory meats to feed those sad,</text><text start="81.25" dur="11.2">scrawny animals? So here now are the &amp;quot;Three
I&amp;#39;s&amp;quot; of playing the lottery: &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; one: Identify.</text><text start="92.45" dur="10.98">Learn to sense colors. Purple has a grittier
emotional aura than white. &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; two: Ignite.</text><text start="103.43" dur="6.53">Set fire to your home. While it&amp;#39;s not true
that wolves refuse to eat arsonists, it&amp;#39;s</text><text start="109.96" dur="8.88">a scientific fact that they&amp;#39;re unable to detect
the presence of one. &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; three: Imitate. If</text><text start="118.84" dur="6.12">you happen to draw a purple piece, impersonate
someone who drew a white piece. You might</text><text start="124.96" dur="6.18">be mistaken for a person who is color blind.
This, of course, will lead to months of painful</text><text start="131.14" dur="6.329">color re-education at City Hall. But, in most
cultures, that&amp;#39;s better than being eaten by</text><text start="137.469" dur="6.88">wolves. Also, make sure to visit the Food
Truck Festival, which will be downtown as</text><text start="144.349" dur="10.44">part of the lottery festivities. Popular truck
treats include Korean barbecue, vegetarian chili, and veal ice cream. </text><text start="157.22" dur="6.56">Carlos, this station&amp;#39;s
favorite scientist (no offense to Dr. Dubinski)</text><text start="163.79" dur="6.24">in the Night Vale Community College chemistry
department) dropped by our broadcast location</text><text start="170.03" dur="6.87">earlier this morning for a little chat. Sadly,
dinner or weekend plans were not among the</text><text start="176.9" dur="7.059">topics. However, Carlos did request that we
ask listeners for anyone who saw a series</text><text start="183.959" dur="7.44">of bright, colorful flickers coming from Radon
Canyon this past weekend. These flickers would</text><text start="191.4" dur="6.839">also have also been accompanied by unintelligible
noises-- possibly some form of coded communication</text><text start="198.239" dur="7.08">or signal-jamming technique. Carlos suggested
that there could be some very sinister forces</text><text start="205.319" dur="6.23">at work here. He declined to be interviewed
live, claiming only that he was scared for</text><text start="211.549" dur="7.851">us. Scared for all of us in our strange town.
Then he drove away quickly in his economical</text><text start="219.4" dur="6.83">but attractively sporty hybrid coupe. If anyone
out there knows anything about these otherworldly</text><text start="226.23" dur="4.62">lights and sounds, please contact us immediately.</text><text start="232.12" dur="8.6">Night Vale school superintendent Nick Ford, announced today that the Glow Cloud has joined
the School Board.</text><text start="241.7" dur="8.44">The Glow Cloud passed over the entirety of Night Vale several weeks ago--
dropping small and large animal carcasses,</text><text start="250.14" dur="7">controlling our thoughts and tertiary muscle
groups, and erasing every last recording device.</text><text start="257.14" dur="6.48">We&amp;#39;re still unsure the Glow Cloud even existed,
as no one remembers it, nor has any digital</text><text start="263.629" dur="7.46">record of it. If not for a few intrepid citizens
who used old-fashioned pens and pencils to</text><text start="271.09" dur="6.85">record the event in their diaries, we would
have no remaining knowledge of that day. I,</text><text start="277.94" dur="6.11">of course, can only thank those journal writers
anonymously here on the air, as the Night</text><text start="284.05" dur="7.04">Vale City Council long ago banned writing
utensils-- along with margarita glasses and</text><text start="291.09" dur="8.04">bar code scanners-- and I don&amp;#39;t want to get
my fellow reporters in any trouble with the Sheriff&amp;#39;s Secret Police.</text><text start="300.66" dur="6.099">According to Superintendent
Ford, the Glow Cloud&amp;#39;s visit on that nearly-forgotten</text><text start="306.759" dur="8.82">day was simply an effort to find a nice neighborhood
with good schools to raise a child. Now what</text><text start="315.58" dur="7.46">kind of progeny a powerful, formless cloud
formed of noxious nightmares and spiritual</text><text start="323.04" dur="8.24">destruction might produce, I dare not even
speculate. But I do know one thing: that little</text><text start="331.28" dur="7.08">cloud is going to get one heck of an education
in the Night Vale School District. And isn&amp;#39;t</text><text start="338.36" dur="6.36">it heartening to hear that that little puff
of despair&amp;#39;s father, or mother, will serve</text><text start="344.72" dur="6.5">on the School Board? I mean, no matter how
good the school, a student can only get out</text><text start="351.22" dur="6.189">as much as the parents put in. We should all
take such an impactful role in our children&amp;#39;s</text><text start="357.409" dur="8.54">scholastic lives. Especially you, Steve Carlsberg.
You don&amp;#39;t do anything except bring unacceptably</text><text start="365.949" dur="8.19">dry scones to PTA meetings and take grammatically
disastrous minutes on your shifts as meeting</text><text start="374.139" dur="9.5">secretary. Get it together, Steve! Superintendent
Ford offered the following statement of support</text><text start="383.639" dur="11.8">for the newest school board member: &amp;quot;All hail!
Kneel for the Glow Cloud. Sacrifice. Pestilence.</text><text start="395.44" dur="7">Sores. All hail the Glow Cloud!&amp;quot; </text><text start="403.1" dur="6.96">And now,
traffic. This morning, I saw a running man.</text><text start="410.06" dur="8.2">He passed by my home. Panting. Limping. Running
desperate. I tried to stop him, but he would</text><text start="418.27" dur="9.29">not meet my eye. This noon time, I saw a running
man. He was coming down from the mountain,</text><text start="427.56" dur="10.1">holding a bag. His knees were bloody, and
face covered in tears. This evening, I saw</text><text start="437.669" dur="8.331">a running man. He was leaving town, legs pumping
like a terrified heart. I think he was missing</text><text start="446" dur="9.819">a hand. Is it that he wouldn&amp;#39;t meet my eye,
or that he had no eyes? Now I wish I could</text><text start="455.819" dur="9.26">remember. There are many things I wish I could
remember. This has been traffic.</text><text start="479.04" dur="11.16"> New billboards have appeared all over town, bearing the image
of a turkey sandwich and the single word &amp;quot;HARLOT&amp;quot;</text><text start="490.2" dur="7.38">in large, block letters. These billboards
have caused some confusion-- both due to their</text><text start="497.59" dur="7">ambiguous message and to the fact that the
entire structure of the billboards materialized</text><text start="504.83" dur="8.77">overnight in places billboards are not usually
constructed, such as the living rooms of local</text><text start="513.6" dur="10.08">homes, the middle of busy thoroughfares (causing
multiple car accidents), and, in one case,</text><text start="523.69" dur="7.839">directly through a living dog, who does not
appear harmed by the addition to his body,</text><text start="531.529" dur="7.5">and has carried the entire billboard around
town while going about his usual canine business.</text><text start="540.32" dur="7.8">The Department of Health and Human Services
recently claimed responsibility for the billboards,</text><text start="548.12" dur="6.469">saying that they were part of a campaign to
promote nutrition and healthy living among</text><text start="554.589" dur="7.651">children. The original draft of the release
also mentioned something about an offering</text><text start="562.24" dur="8.32">to a long-dead god, but this was altered to
&amp;quot;fun, active lifestyles are important for</text><text start="570.56" dur="4.78">kids of all ages&amp;quot; in a subsequent addendum.</text><text start="576.08" dur="3.9">We&amp;#39;re receiving several phone calls from listeners,</text><text start="579.98" dur="6.44">and from the Parks Department, that those
flickering lights and unintelligible noises</text><text start="586.42" dur="9.44">we reported on earlier were coming from the
Pink Floyd Multimedia Laser Spectacular.</text><text start="596.8" dur="6.98">I contacted Carlos about this, and he said that
the situation is even worse than he imagined.</text><text start="604.6" dur="4.8">He, again, did not mention weekend plans.</text><text start="610.8" dur="4.38">A sports scandal has shook our quiet little town.</text><text start="615.6" dur="6.12">The Night Vale Scorpions have faced
multiple allegations of possible game tampering</text><text start="621.73" dur="6.659">this football season. Representatives for
the Desert Bluffs School District, speaking</text><text start="628.389" dur="7.31">in unpleasant and high-pitched voices indicative
of weakness of will and character, complained</text><text start="635.699" dur="6.39">to the Regional Football and Traffic Code
Authority that Night Vale quarterback Michael</text><text start="642.089" dur="8.24">Sandero&amp;#39;s recently-grown second head counts
as a twelfth man on the field, thus invalidating</text><text start="650.329" dur="10.01">the wins brought on by his also recently-acquired
superhuman agility and strength. The RFTCA</text><text start="660.339" dur="5.381">said that they would look into these allegations
with the utmost seriousness, along with their</text><text start="665.72" dur="7.76">concurrent investigation into whether Night
Vale&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;invisible crosswalk&amp;quot; policy is actually</text><text start="673.49" dur="6.08">a desperate bid to save town funds at the
cost of pedestrian lives.</text><text start="680.76" dur="7.76">Meanwhile, the School Board is due to announce its decision in the
ongoing hearings as to whether appealing to</text><text start="688.529" dur="7.6">Angels for a win constitutes illegal game
tampering. Several Angels agreed to testify</text><text start="696.13" dur="6.019">at the hearings, however their testimonials
were cut short when it became apparent that</text><text start="702.149" dur="6.401">the hearings were actually elaborate traps
set up by the City Council to finally capture</text><text start="708.55" dur="8.219">the Angels, whom the Council does not recognize
as actually existing. Fortunately, the Angels</text><text start="716.769" dur="5.76">easily escaped from their cages in a blaze
of Heavenly light, presumably returning to</text><text start="722.529" dur="6.331">Old Woman Josie&amp;#39;s house, out near the Car
Lot, which has become something of an informal</text><text start="728.86" dur="7.94">shelter for local Angels. When asked about
the controversy over his team&amp;#39;s winning record,</text><text start="736.8" dur="8.1">Coach Nazr al-Mujaheed said, &amp;quot;Our boys are
good boys. They&amp;#39;re good boys at football.</text><text start="744.91" dur="8.239">We win ‘em. With the boys. The football.&amp;quot;
Then he smiled vacantly, waved at no one,</text><text start="753.149" dur="6.32">and wandered off in the direction of the woods.
More on this story as it develops.</text><text start="763.32" dur="9.16">And now, a word from our sponsor. Step into your nearest
Subway restaurant today, and try their new</text><text start="772.48" dur="7.98">6-inch mashed potato sub! Top it with a delicious
assortment of fresh vegetables, like french</text><text start="780.47" dur="7.95">fries and Nutella. They&amp;#39;ll even toast or poach
it for you! There are several Subway locations</text><text start="788.42" dur="7.14">in Night Vale, all easily accessible through
witchcraft and chanting. And between now and</text><text start="795.57" dur="8.069">November 30th, buy nine reverse colonics and
get a free 40-ounce soda or freshly baked</text><text start="803.639" dur="6.34">tobacco cookie. Subway: Devour your own empty
heart.</text><text start="810.92" dur="5.44">Exciting news about the Abandoned Mine Shaft outside of town,</text><text start="816.36" dur="5.36">where people who vote
incorrectly are taken by the secret police:</text><text start="821.72" dur="7.76">HBO On Demand will be made available to prisoners
during their indefinite detention. All your</text><text start="829.48" dur="8.14">favorite shows, such as The Wire, Sex and
the City, and even new hits like Game Of Thrones,</text><text start="837.62" dur="6.52">will be available in every cell. Additionally,
the secret police announced that they will</text><text start="844.14" dur="7.72">be randomly executing one prisoner a day until
all incorrect votes are corrected.</text><text start="858.8" dur="7.909">This just in: We&amp;#39;re receiving word from the City Council
that there was absolutely not a Pink Floyd</text><text start="866.709" dur="6.641">Multimedia Laser Spectacular this weekend
at Radon Canyon... that there never was a</text><text start="873.35" dur="8.68">Pink Floyd Multimedia Laser Spectacular ever
near Night Vale. &amp;quot;Pink Floyd is not even a</text><text start="882.04" dur="7.36">thing,&amp;quot; said the Council in a very stern,
but quiet, statement just received by me,</text><text start="889.41" dur="8.83">here, via phone. The Council... and this is
strange... the entire Council-- not just a</text><text start="898.24" dur="6.64">representative of the Council, the entire
Council-- issued this statement, all speaking</text><text start="904.899" dur="7.4">in unison, just now, over the phone: that
Night Vale citizens are prohibited from discussing</text><text start="912.3" dur="6.2">any lights or sounds coming from Radon Canyon
this past weekend, and that they should just</text><text start="918.5" dur="7.74">stop remembering Pink Floyd shows altogether.
The Council reiterated that there is no way</text><text start="926.24" dur="7.44">that they are huge Floyd fans, privately using
public funds on a laser-powered seance to</text><text start="933.699" dur="7.04">talk &amp;quot;hard-rockin&amp;#39; classic jams&amp;quot; with the
ghost of original front man Syd Barrett, and</text><text start="940.74" dur="6.079">that Syd &amp;quot;wouldn&amp;#39;t even say anything juicy
anyway, because he is such a gentleman, and</text><text start="946.819" dur="10.54">an artist.&amp;quot; This did not happen at all. So,
listeners, we urge you to look away from Radon</text><text start="957.36" dur="8.24">Canyon. Avert your eyes, ears, and memories
from that which is no longer allowed you.</text><text start="965.6" dur="7.2">Comfort and distract yourselves with dense
food and television programming. As the old</text><text start="972.81" dur="8.469">adage goes: &amp;quot;A life of pain is the pain of
life, and you can never escape it-- only hope</text><text start="981.279" dur="7.391">it hides, unknown, in a drawer like a poisonous
spider and never comes out again, even though</text><text start="988.67" dur="7.479">it probably will, in unexpected and horrific
fashion, scaring you from being able to comfortably</text><text start="996.149" dur="8.6">conduct even the most mundane, quotidian tasks.&amp;quot;
Or, at least, that&amp;#39;s how my grandparents always</text><text start="1004.769" dur="4.371">phrased it. And now, the weather.</text><text start="1009.14" dur="244.22">[&amp;quot;This Too
Shall Pass&amp;quot; by Danny Schmidt]</text><text start="1253.36" dur="8.78">Teddy Williams, over at the Desert Flower Bowling Alley and
Arcade Fun Complex, has an update on the doorway</text><text start="1262.14" dur="6.8">into that vast, underground city he found
in the pin retrieval area of Lane Five.</text><text start="1269.8" dur="7.86">He says that every window of the city is now
glowing both day and night. And he heard the</text><text start="1277.669" dur="7">shouts and footsteps of what sounds like an
army marching upwards toward the world above.</text><text start="1285.66" dur="6.84">He also said that, given that nothing really
matters now, bowling is half-off and each</text><text start="1292.51" dur="8.78">game comes with a free basket of wings. Mmm,
nothing like those Desert Flower wings!</text><text start="1302.34" dur="8.319">Let me leave you with this, dear listeners. We
lead frantic lives. Filled with needs and</text><text start="1310.659" dur="8.62">responsibilities, but completely devoid of
any actual purpose. I say let&amp;#39;s try to enjoy</text><text start="1319.289" dur="10.6">the simple things. Life should be like a basket
of chicken wings: salty, full of fat and vinegar,</text><text start="1329.89" dur="6.4">and surrounded by celery you&amp;#39;ll never actually
eat, even when you&amp;#39;re greedily sopping up</text><text start="1336.299" dur="6.411">the last viscous streaks of buffalo sauce
from the wax paper with your spit-stained</text><text start="1342.71" dur="9.72">index finger. Yes, that is as life should
be, Night Vale. Stay tuned next for a special</text><text start="1352.46" dur="6.329">live broadcast of the Night Vale Symphony
Orchestra performing Eugene O&amp;#39;Neill&amp;#39;s classic</text><text start="1358.789" dur="7.92">play, &amp;quot;The Iceman Cometh&amp;quot;. It is a good night,
listeners. Goodnight.</text><text start="1378.2" dur="5.5">Welcome to Night Vale is a production of Commonplace Books. It is
written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey Cranor,</text><text start="1383.71" dur="5">and produced by Joseph Fink. The voice of
Night Vale is Cecil Baldwin. Original music</text><text start="1388.71" dur="5.93">by Disparition. All of it can be downloaded
for free at disparition.info. This episode&amp;#39;s</text><text start="1394.64" dur="5.94">weather was &amp;quot;This Too Shall Pass&amp;quot; by Danny
Schmidt. Find out more at dannyschmidt.com.</text><text start="1400.58" dur="3.709">Want to have your music featured in the weather
section? Want to contribute your talents to</text><text start="1404.289" dur="6.051">the show? Just want to say hi? Email us at
nightvale@commonplacebooks.com. Check out</text><text start="1410.34" dur="4.05">commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1414.39" dur="5.22">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup. Today&amp;#39;s proverb:</text><text start="1419.61" dur="7">We are living in an immaterial world-- a ghost
world-- and I am an immaterial girl-- a ghost.</text></transcript>