<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="12.98">Weird at last, weird at last! God almighty,
weird at last! Welcome to Night Vale.</text><text start="36.16" dur="6.919">The Sheriff’s Secret Police are asking the public’s
help in catching a dangerous fugitive on the</text><text start="43.079" dur="6.321">loose in the greater Night Vale area. They
say he is armed, and should be approached</text><text start="49.4" dur="6.79">with extreme caution. For everyone’s protection,
they are keeping the name and description</text><text start="56.19" dur="7.56">of the fugitive secret, but indicate that
all strangers should be mistrusted and avoided...</text><text start="63.75" dur="7.84">as well as friends and loved ones, because
how well do you know those people, anyway?</text><text start="71.59" dur="9.44">Are you aware of their location every second
of every day? Who among us does not have secrets?</text><text start="81.069" dur="9.06">The fugitive is wanted dead or alive and vigilante
justice is, as always, highly encouraged.</text><text start="91.14" dur="8.1">Our top story today: A large Pyramid has appeared
in the center of the Beatrix Lowman Memorial</text><text start="99.24" dur="7.72">Meditation Zone, destroying over half of the
Zone’s state-of-the-art meditation equipment</text><text start="106.969" dur="8.11">and paraphernalia. Experts have been contacted
as to what could cause sudden Pyramid existence.</text><text start="115.079" dur="7.35">However, as it turns out, there are no experts
in Pyramid materialization. And the town’s</text><text start="122.429" dur="8.84">other experts offered up merely shrugs, followed
by panicked conjectures, and finally, screams</text><text start="131.29" dur="7">and moans, all of which fell uselessly upon
the City Council’s merciless ears.</text><text start="139.58" dur="6.93">The Pyramid has been described as &amp;quot;a kind of triangle
shape, only three-dimensional.&amp;quot; It has made</text><text start="146.51" dur="7.789">no movement, despite repeated taserings by
the Sheriff’s Secret Police. Many suspect</text><text start="154.299" dur="5.451">that this may be a publicity stunt pulled
by our own local cereal company, Flaky-Os,</text><text start="159.75" dur="6.07">who are launching their new line of nighttime-only
cereals next month.</text><text start="166.52" dur="5.68">An angry mob has formed outside of the cereal factory, just in case.</text><text start="177.58" dur="11.72">Telly. You remember, the deceitful barber with a shriveled soul who, just a few weeks
ago, cut perfect scientist Carlos’ perfect,</text><text start="189.3" dur="8.019">beautiful hair very short-- so very, very
short-- thus depriving our community of our</text><text start="197.319" dur="8.39">only remaining pleasure. Well, Telly was seen
recently wandering the Sand Wastes, howling</text><text start="205.709" dur="6.411">at the sky, and holding up Carlos’ shorn
locks as though begging God to reverse the</text><text start="212.12" dur="8.84">crime he has done. Reports indicate that his
skin was blistering, that his eyes were bleary,</text><text start="220.96" dur="8.56">and that he was recently seen trying to give
a cactus a haircut, whispering and cooing</text><text start="229.52" dur="3.4">into what he seemed to think was its ear.</text><text start="233.92" dur="4.989">Listeners, I am not one to stand aside harshly</text><text start="238.909" dur="7.56">and say that a man deserves the punishment
that comes to him, but I also am not sorry</text><text start="246.499" dur="8.39">to see Telly in this state, given his crime.
In any case, if your cactus is in need of</text><text start="254.889" dur="5.82">a haircut, try Telly, out wandering the Sand
Wastes.</text><text start="263.76" dur="10.28">Ladies and gentlemen, I must say that I am not a cat person. But I have really grown
to love Khoshekh, the stray cat that has made</text><text start="274.04" dur="7.07">his home here at the radio station. I discovered
Khoshekh several weeks ago, hovering in a</text><text start="281.11" dur="6.25">fixed location in the men’s bathroom-- and
he’s remained there ever since. The men</text><text start="287.36" dur="4.92">at the station, of course, have taken to keeping
the sink at a light trickle, so he can get</text><text start="292.29" dur="8.24">water, and we even take turns buying Science
Diet Low-Calorie Cat Food. It turns out little</text><text start="300.54" dur="6.19">Khoshekh is getting a bit chubby, since he
can’t actually exercise in his unmovable,</text><text start="306.73" dur="8.18">levitating state. Oh, and thanks to our new
intern, Brad, we’ve finally solved the litter</text><text start="314.91" dur="8.48">problem. Brad is very excellent at both carpentry
and dark magic, so he rigged us up a fine-looking</text><text start="323.41" dur="8.75">litter box that our floating feline friend
can reach. He’s just adorable, that cat!</text><text start="332.16" dur="7.12">As a life-long dog lover, I’ve really turned
the corner. Khoshekh is wonderful! I know</text><text start="339.3" dur="6.04">several others here at the station who feel
the same way. After meeting Khoshekh, Mikaela,</text><text start="345.34" dur="6.29">who works in sales, put her three-year-old
Weimaraner to sleep and then adopted six tabby</text><text start="351.63" dur="7.08">kittens. She’s that much of a convert! Make
sure to take some cute videos, Mikaela. And</text><text start="358.72" dur="5.79">for others of you interested in getting a
new cat, the Night Vale SPCA strongly recommends</text><text start="364.51" dur="6.12">that you have your cat spayed or neutered,
bring them in for their shots and, once the</text><text start="370.65" dur="6.02">cat reaches 18 months, begin using the little
beast to harvest human organs for those &amp;quot;just</text><text start="376.67" dur="7.36">in case&amp;quot; moments. The SPCA has several one-sheets
on preventing heart worms and using pets to</text><text start="384.04" dur="9.1">grow small replacement organs. To get your
copy, go online or simply make up your own informative facts.</text><text start="394.4" dur="7.52">An update on the Pyramid
reported on earlier: Word is in that the Pyramid</text><text start="401.92" dur="9.08">has spoken. It is broadcasting, on low-wave
frequencies, a repeated message. The message</text><text start="411" dur="7.59">is the following: &amp;quot;I will place within some
of you questions. Within others, I will place</text><text start="418.59" dur="6.96">answers. These questions and these answers
will not always align. The questions I provide</text><text start="425.57" dur="7.68">may have no answers, and the answers I provide
may have no questions. I will study the effects</text><text start="433.25" dur="10.28">of these questions, and these answers. Some
of you will hurt others, and others will heal.</text><text start="443.53" dur="5.16">Grow my seeds inside you, and let them flower.&amp;quot;</text><text start="456.2" dur="2.62">The Flaky-Os marketing department must be</text><text start="458.84" dur="7.04">complimented for the best use of viral marketing
in Night Vale since Stan’s Pawn Shop released</text><text start="465.9" dur="7.16">a virulent strain of Ebola back in ‘98.
And, as a communicator by trade, I applaud</text><text start="473.06" dur="6.5">their ingenuity. The Sheriff’s Secret Police
has responded with surface-to-surface missiles</text><text start="479.56" dur="7.76">which, they say, will &amp;quot;silence the dark heart
of the beast.&amp;quot; So far, they have not so much</text><text start="487.34" dur="10.67">as created a smudge on the Pyramid’s broad,
shiny surface. Home handymen, fix-it vixens,</text><text start="498.01" dur="7.74">ladies and gentlemen who love to get their
hands dirty, let’s talk about home repair.</text><text start="505.75" dur="6.55">Certain jobs are fine for the amateur, and
certain others should be left to the professionals.</text><text start="512.31" dur="7.359">Leaky sinks, sticky windows, minor exorcisms,
and bleeding doors-- all these are the kind</text><text start="519.669" dur="5.041">of ‘quick fixes’ that a toolbox and a
quick search on the Internet should allow</text><text start="524.71" dur="9.44">you to take care of. On the other hand, structural
damage, major remodeling, seeping darkness,</text><text start="534.15" dur="8.28">major exorcisms, roof boils, and lawn care--
these are all the kind of work that should</text><text start="542.46" dur="6.72">not be attempted by anyone without years of
expertise and a valid Hammer License from</text><text start="549.18" dur="7.03">the City Council. Finding the right professional
for the job is easy. Just look at the Yellow</text><text start="556.21" dur="9.6">Pages. Or head down to the squatter shacks
by the edge of the Sand Wastes and ask around among the homeless.</text><text start="573.42" dur="5.08"> And now, a public service
announcement from the Night Vale medical community.</text><text start="579.76" dur="6.74">Being in the desert, we get a lot of sun,
and doctors are encouraging Night Vale citizens</text><text start="586.51" dur="6.85">to do regular skin checks. You may think that
freckle or mole is harmless, but you never</text><text start="593.36" dur="7.7">know when it will grow into something much
worse. Surgeons at Night Vale General Hospital</text><text start="601.07" dur="6.96">are noting an uptick in dermatological growths
related to sun exposure. Doctors describe</text><text start="608.06" dur="8.86">these growths as &amp;quot;15-inch spiraled horns.&amp;quot;
The horns mostly protrude from the lower back</text><text start="616.92" dur="8.04">or knees. Unchecked, these horns can develop
a glistening shine, small leather saddles,</text><text start="624.97" dur="8.24">and bright red lips on the very tip. So check
your skin at least once a week in the mirror.</text><text start="633.21" dur="8.63">Dermatologists recommend a three-step process.
1. Search meticulously for 15-inch horns protruding</text><text start="641.84" dur="8.18">from your body. Don’t overlook anything.
2. If you find any suspicious growths, mark</text><text start="650.02" dur="8.89">them with a chalk pentagon. 3. Gently remove
the affected skin area with a sterilized razor</text><text start="658.91" dur="8.44">blade, or similarly clean crafting blade.
If you are not one of the 53% of our community</text><text start="667.36" dur="5.76">that was born without pain-sensing nerves,
you should first consult your primary care</text><text start="673.12" dur="9.66">electrolysist for tips on how to numb yourself
to the nigh-unbearable pain of existence.</text><text start="686" dur="6.54">The Department of Public Safety announced
that all street signs in Night Vale will be</text><text start="692.55" dur="7.72">replaced with Traffic Cops wielding semaphore
flags. Drivers will be required to learn this</text><text start="700.29" dur="7.47">physically expressive maritime alphabet. This
decision is not without its controversy, as</text><text start="707.76" dur="7.6">the existing street signs are entirely in
braille. One critic, Paul Birmingham, says</text><text start="715.37" dur="7.98">removing these signs will deflate the Earth.
As a member of the Air-Filled Earth Society,</text><text start="723.35" dur="9.44">Paul believes that Earth is a precariously-inflated
orb that could pop or sag at any moment. &amp;quot;We’ve</text><text start="732.79" dur="7">gotta stop teaching all this religious propaganda
in our schools and start teaching real science,&amp;quot;</text><text start="739.81" dur="8">Paul shouted from his lean-to behind the library.
I have to admit, listeners, he makes a valid point.</text><text start="752.34" dur="8.58">And now, a word from our sponsor. Today’s
program is brought to you by Audible.com,</text><text start="760.93" dur="6.93">your online source for recorded books. There
are thousands of great titles at Audible.com</text><text start="767.86" dur="6.21">that you can download to your computer, or
portable device, and listen to on the go.</text><text start="774.07" dur="7.2">I use Audible to catch up on best-selling
titles like &amp;quot;The Help&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Van Gogh Notes</text><text start="781.279" dur="7.631">for Technical Communication 11\e.&amp;quot; I’m on
their website right now, and I’m typing</text><text start="788.91" dur="6.08">in a search for &amp;quot;Dog Park,&amp;quot; because I was
thinking about this town’s beautiful new</text><text start="794.99" dur="6.84">fixture, and how I will never, ever take my
dog there. Let’s see what Audible comes</text><text start="801.85" dur="10.71">up with. Huh. It’s a flashing black-and-red
screen that says &amp;quot;THOUGHT CRIME&amp;quot; in all-caps.</text><text start="812.56" dur="7.24">And below that, a little animation of two
digging workers: &amp;quot;Under Construction.&amp;quot; That’s</text><text start="819.8" dur="10">adorable! So check out Audible.com. New Audible
members can get one free audio book just by</text><text start="829.8" dur="6.12">smudging their computer monitors with baby’s
blood and humming the Spanish translation</text><text start="835.92" dur="9.12">of &amp;quot;The Battle Hymn of the Republic.&amp;quot; Audible.com:
&amp;quot;You can’t burn what you can’t even touch.&amp;quot;</text><text start="846.26" dur="9.23">Update on the Pyramid situation. Flaky-Os
Board of Directors are vigorously denying--</text><text start="855.49" dur="5.57">some of them at gunpoint-- that they have
any part in the Pyramid that is stubbornly</text><text start="861.06" dur="7.96">continuing to exist in our town. They are
sneaky ones! I hope the new line of cereal</text><text start="869.02" dur="7.629">turns out to be worth the hype. Meanwhile,
the Pyramid itself has altered its broadcast,</text><text start="876.649" dur="4.84">sending out a second message, which is as follows:</text><text start="883.56" dur="10.7">&amp;quot;Everything you do matters except your life. Death will be the last action you
undertake. I do not live, but I exist. What</text><text start="894.26" dur="6.99">is my purpose? I will not tell you. One day
you will discover your purpose, and then you</text><text start="901.25" dur="4.82">will tell no one. And then you will die.&amp;quot;</text><text start="913.4" dur="8.32">Now, I’m not too good at this ‘viral marketing thing, so I can’t see all the codes and
hidden web addresses that I’m sure are all</text><text start="921.72" dur="6.76">through that message. I’ll leave that to
all the dedicated amateurs out there in the listening world.</text><text start="929.8" dur="4.92">Sheriff’s Secret Police
are now attempting to charge the Pyramid with</text><text start="934.72" dur="6.989">resisting arrest, on the grounds that they
couldn’t figure out how to arrest it. More</text><text start="941.709" dur="5.58">as the story develops. In the meantime, let’s go to the weather.</text><text start="948.28" dur="260.8">[&amp;quot;Last Song&amp;quot; by Jason Webley]</text><text start="1209.08" dur="3.12">Well, listeners, it seems the Pyramid has</text><text start="1212.2" dur="7.62">disappeared-- as mysteriously and suddenly
as it arrived. Too late, I’m afraid, for</text><text start="1219.83" dur="5.9">the Flaky-Os Board of Directors, who have
all been taken to the Abandoned Mine Shaft</text><text start="1225.73" dur="3.88">outside of town for processing by the City
Council.</text><text start="1230.9" dur="5.76">The Sheriff’s Secret Police are declaring victory in their standoff against
the Pyramid... </text><text start="1236.66" dur="4.38">because, they say, it’s about time they won something.</text><text start="1242.42" dur="7.719">Meanwhile, the Pyramid
has left behind a much tinier Pyramid, a mere</text><text start="1250.139" dur="8.2">souvenir of its looming, inscrutable mass.
This tiny Pyramid is broadcasting one final</text><text start="1258.35" dur="6.45">message-- a farewell from the geometric shape
that stole our hearts.</text><text start="1264.8" dur="4.66">So let us wrap up our show today with its words:</text><text start="1271.06" dur="4.54"> &amp;quot;Somewhere there
is a map. And on that map is Earth. </text><text start="1276.36" dur="10.16">And attached to Earth is an arrow that says your name and lists your lifespan. Some of you die standing,</text><text start="1286.52" dur="10.32">others sitting. Many of you die in cars. I
can never die. It is difficult for me to understand</text><text start="1296.85" dur="7.079">the concept that I am attempting to convey.
I cannot show you this vision, but you may</text><text start="1303.929" dur="7">imagine it. Step forward and tell someone
of it, please.&amp;quot;</text><text start="1316.28" dur="8.62">You heard it here, folks. Tell people. Tell people about Flaky-Os&amp;#39; new
line of cereals for nighttime only.</text><text start="1324.9" dur="3.64">Do it in memory of its Board of Directors. </text><text start="1329.48" dur="5.56">Stay tuned now for an hour of dead air with the occasional hiss and crackle.</text><text start="1336.2" dur="8">Speaking of the
nighttime, I truly hope you have a good one, Night Vale. Goodnight.</text><text start="1358.56" dur="3.3">Welcome to Night Vale
is a production of Commonplace Books. It is</text><text start="1361.869" dur="4.731">written by Joseph Fink and Jeffrey Cranor,
and produced by Joseph Fink. The messages</text><text start="1366.6" dur="6.029">from the Pyramid were written by guest contributor
Regis Lacher. The voice of Night Vale is Cecil</text><text start="1372.629" dur="5.74">Baldwin. Original music by Disparition. All
of it can be downloaded for free at disparition.info.</text><text start="1378.369" dur="6.31">This episode’s weather was &amp;quot;Last Song&amp;quot; by
Jason Webley. Find out more at jasonwebley.com.</text><text start="1384.679" dur="4.96">Want to have your music featured in the weather
section? Want to contribute your talents to</text><text start="1389.639" dur="6.181">the show? Just want to say hi? Email us at
nightvale@commonplacebooks.com. Check out</text><text start="1395.82" dur="4.26">commonplacebooks.com for more information
on this show, as well as our books on the</text><text start="1400.08" dur="4.26">unused story ideas of H.P. Lovecraft, and
what it means to be a grownup.</text><text start="1404.34" dur="5.46">Today’s proverb: &amp;quot;Nice bolo tie&amp;quot; is the greatest compliment
a person can ever receive.</text></transcript>